<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./interactivePie.png" type="Visualizer">
	<name>Pie chart (interactive)</name>	
	<shortDescription>
		Displays data in an interactive pie chart with hiliting support.
	</shortDescription>	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
		<p>Displays an interactive pie chart with different viewing 
		options. The interactive pie chart supports hiliting and the changing 
		of the pie and aggregation column on the fly.</p>
		<p>If the pie chart appears in gray no color information is set
		for the selected pie column. Use the 'Color Manager' node in order 
		to set the color appropriate.</p>
		<p>The user can change the following view properties on the fly:
			<ol>
			<li>Pie column</li>
            <li>Aggregation column</li>
            <li>Aggregation method (count, summary, average)</li>
            <li>Pie size</li>
            <li>Show missing value section</li>
            <li>Show pie section outline</li>
            <li>Draw selected section exploded</li>
            <li>Show details for selected sections</li>
            <li>Set value scale to percentage or original</li>
            <li>Pie size</li>
            <li>Explode size</li>
            </ol>
			Each pie column value get its own colored section. 
			Hiliting is supported.
		</p>
		<p><b>Color selected sections:</b>
		If the color selected sections option is selected the pie displays also sub 
        sections for the selected sections. A sub section represents the rows
        color using the color manager. This option is only available if 
        row colors are set.</p>
        <p><b>Please note: This node caches all data in the main memory to 
        provide interactive functions. If you plan to visualize extremely large 
        datasets the non interactive "Pie chart" node may be better suited.</b></p>
        <p><b>The pie chart supports maximum 360 sections!</b></p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Display all rows">
		    If selected the pie chart displays all rows of the incoming data.
	    </option>
	    <option name="No. of rows to display: ">
		    Defines the number of rows to be displayed in the pie chart.
		    This option is disabled if the 'Display all rows' option is selected.
	    </option>
	    <option name="Pie column: ">
	     	The values of this column are represent as colored section in the
	     	pie chart. Can be changed in the view later on.
   	    </option>
   	    <option name="Aggregation method: ">
            The initial aggregation method to use. Can be changed in
            the view later on.
        </option>
        <option name="Aggregation column">
            The column to calculate the aggregation values from. Can be 
            changed in the view later on.
        </option>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<dataIn index="0" name="Data in port">
			The data table to be displayed.
		</dataIn>
	</ports>	
	<views>
		<view index="0" name="Pie Chart">
			Displays the data in an pie chart.
		</view>
	</views>
</knimeNode>