<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./joiner.png" type="Manipulator" deprecated="true">
    <name>Joiner (deprecated)</name>
    <shortDescription>
    	This node is obsolete! Please use the new Joiner node located in 
	    the Data Manipulation -&gt; Column category.
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This node is obsolete! Please use the new Joiner node located in 
	    	the Data Manipulation -&gt; Column category.
	        This node joins two tables (database join-like). The join on the two tables
			is carried out so that the first table (from the first, top input 
			port) provides the left part of the output table and the second table
			(bottom input port) provides the columns for the right part. Thus, the output 
			table has as many rows as both of the input tables (given that both tables
			contain exactly the same row identifier (IDs)) and as many columns as the sum of both 
			column counts. If a row ID only occurs in one of the two tables,
			the remaining part (the column that should have been provided by the 
			other table) is filled with missing cells. <b>NOTE</b>: This node may have 
			high (runtime) complexity if the tables contain different row IDs
			or the rows are sorted differently. (If they have the same keys in the
			same order, this node has linear complexity.) 
		</intro>
        <option name="Duplicate Columns">
	        The dialog allows you to change settings in order to state what should be done if 
			both input tables contain the same column names (column names must 
			inherently be unique). The default setting is "don't execute", i.e. you are not
			able to execute this node (it is red). Your second choice is to filter
			the duplicates, i.e. only the columns from Data Inport #0 are available
			at the outport. As a third option you can append a suffix to duplicate
			column names so that they are also available at the outport.
		</option>
		<option name="Remove rows missing in one table">
			If not all rows in both tables can be matched together, they can be
			either removed completely from the output table (like an INNER JOIN in SQL)
			or the missing columns rom the one table can be replaced by missing cells
			(like an OUTER JOIN in SQL).
		</option>
		</fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Left table">Table contributing to the left part of the output table</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Right table">Table contributing to the right part of the output table</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Joined table">Joined Table</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
