<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 1.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./javascripting.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Java Snippet</name>
    <shortDescription>Calculates a new column based on java code snippets.</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
			This node allows you to execute arbitrary java code to create
			a new column or to replace an existing one. Enter the java code in 
			the text area. To address certain input values of the table 
			use <i>$name_of_col$</i>. For instance, the sum of the first two 
			columns is <i>$col_1$ + $col_2$</i> (replace col_1 and col_2 by the 
			name of the columns). Please also specify the return type with one 
			of the radio buttons. The final value will be the result of your
	        last statement (<b>after</b> last ';'). Note, you can also use static 
	        methods of java utility classes, e.g. to get a column with random
	        values, simply enter Math.random() and check the double return type.
		</intro>
		<option name="Text Area">
		  Enter your java code here (the entire source will be wrapped in a 
		  method), do not add the <b>return</b> keyword though but only the
		  statement that succeeds <b>return</b>. If you use more complex code, 
		  for instance loops, enter a (potentially unnecessary) '<b>;</b>' 
		  right before the return statement. You can add the name of a column 
		  by clicking its name in the left list. Note that numeric 
		  (double-compatible) columns will be handled as generic <i>double</i>,
		  int-compatible columns as <i>int</i> and any other column type as 
		  <i>String</i>.
		</option>
		<option name="Return type">
		  Specify here the resulting type of your code snippet. Unfortunately
		  KNIME cannot determine what will be the correct return type - so you 
		  need to assist here.
		</option>
		<option name="Replace/Append">
		  Specify here if you want the result to be put into a separate or 
		  existing column.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <dataIn name="Any input table" index="0">Input table.</dataIn>
        <dataOut name="Appended table" index="0">Input table with an additional calculated column
	        or one column replaced.
        </dataOut>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
