<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 1.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Learner" icon="./fuzzybf.ico">
	<name>Fuzzy Rule Learner</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
	    Trains a Fuzzy Rule Model on labeled data.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>		
    	Generates a Fuzzy Rule Model (RecBF-DDA) on labeled data using 
    	<a href="http://www.inf.uni-konstanz.de/bioml2/publications/Papers2003/Bert03_mixedFR_ijar.pdf">
    	Mixed Fuzzy Rule Formation</a> as underlying training algorithm based
    	(see <a href="http://www.inf.uni-konstanz.de/bioml2/publications/Papers2004/GaBe04_mixedFRappendix_ijar.pdf">
    	Influence of fuzzy norms and other heuristics on 
    	"Mixed Fuzzy Rule Formation"</a> for an extension.<br />
    	All numeric columns are used as input columns for training. One 
    	(additional) column is used as a classification target.<br />
    	The input port contains the training data, the data output port, which 
    	the trained fuzzy rules as table, and the model output of the Fuzzy Rule
    	Model, which can be used for prediction.<br />
    	The algorithm generates rules based on input data, which can be 
    	described as fuzzy intervals in higher dimensional spaces. These 
    	hyper-rectangles are defined by trapezoid fuzzy membership functions for
    	each dimension.
		</intro>
	<option name="Target Column">
		Select the target to be used as a classification attribute.
	</option>
	<option name="Missing Values">
	    Select method to handle missing values.
	</option>
	<option name="Properties">
	    Check, if a shrink should be performed immediately after a new rule
	    has been introduced. Shrink means the new rule is reduced so that the
	    conflict with all other conflicting rules is avoided.
	</option>
    <option name="Maximum #Epochs">
	    	If checked, set the maximum number of epochs the algorithm has to 
	    	cycle over the entire data set, otherwise train until the rule
	    	model is stable, that is, no commit and/or commit has been executed.
	</option>
	<option name="Fuzzy Norm">
	    Choice of fuzzy norm used to compute the rules' fulfillment across all
	    dimensions and rules. 
	</option>
	<option name="Shrink Function">
	    Shrink procedure which reduces rules to avoid conflict between
	     rules of different classes based on the defined loss value.
	</option>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<dataIn index="0" name="Training Data">
			Data used for training. Should contain numeric data, as well as one
			target attribute for classification.
		</dataIn>
		<dataOut index="0" name="Fuzzy Rule Table">
			Table with generated fuzzy rules, each dimension as fuzzy interval.
		</dataOut>
		<modelOut index="0" name="Fuzzy Rule Model" type="FuzzyRuleModel">
			Generated fuzzy rule model can be used for prediction.
		</modelOut>
	</ports>	
	<views>
		<view index="0" name="Fuzzy Rule Model View">
			Shows a summary of the generated fuzzy rule model.
		</view>
	</views>
	
</knimeNode>