<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Learner" icon="./fuzzybf.png">
	<name>Fuzzy Rule Learner</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
		Learns a Fuzzy Rule Model on labeled numeric data.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>		
    	Learns a Fuzzy Rule Model on labeled numeric data using 
    	<a href="http://www.inf.uni-konstanz.de/bioml2/publications/Papers2003/Bert03_mixedFR_ijar.pdf">
    	Mixed Fuzzy Rule Formation</a> as the underlying training algorithm 
    	(also known as RecBF-DDA algorithm),
    	see <a href="http://www.inf.uni-konstanz.de/bioml2/publications/Papers2004/GaBe04_mixedFRappendix_ijar.pdf">
    	Influence of fuzzy norms and other heuristics on 
    	"Mixed Fuzzy Rule Formation"</a> for an extension of the algorithm.<br />
    	This algorithm generates rules based on numeric data, which are 
    	fuzzy intervals in higher dimensional spaces. These 
    	hyper-rectangles are defined by trapezoid fuzzy membership functions for
    	each dimension.	The selected numeric columns of the input data are used 
    	as input data for training and additional columns are used as 
    	classification target, either one column holding the class information
    	or a number of numeric columns with class degrees between 0 and 1 can
    	be selected. The data output contains the fuzzy rules after execution.
    	Each rule consists of one fuzzy interval for each dimension plus
    	the target classification columns along with a number of rule 
    	measurements. The model output port contains the fuzzy
    	rule model, which can be used for prediction in the Fuzzy Rule Predictor 
    	node.
		</intro>
		<option name="Missing Values">
	    Select one method to handle missing values: "Incorp" may generate fuzzy 
	    rules with missing values, if no replacement value has been 
	    found during the learning process. "Best Guess" computes the optimal
	    replacement value by projecting the fuzzy rule (with missing value(s))
	    onto the missing dimension(s) of all other rules. "Mean", "Min", and "Max"
	    replaces the missing value with each column's statistical property. 
	    "Zero" and "One" perform a constant replacement by inserting either zero
	    or one.
		</option>
		<option name="Advanced">
	    <b>Shrink after commit</b> If selected, a shrink to reduce conflicting 
	    rules is executed immediately after a new rule is committed, i.e. the 
	    new rule is reduced so that conflicts with all other rules of different
	    classes are avoided.<br />
	    <b>Use class with max coverage</b> If selected, only the class with
	    maximum coverage degree of the target columns is used during training,
	    otherwise all class columns are considered for coverage. 
		</option>
	    <option name="Maximum no. Epochs">
    	If selected, the option defines the maximum number of epochs 
    	the algorithm has to process the entire data set, otherwise it repeats 
    	this process until this rule model is stable, i.e. no new rule has been 
    	committed and/or no shrink is executed.
        <option name="Target Columns">
        Select the target(s) to be used for classification. If more
        than one column (only numeric) is selected, the columns must contain 
        class membership values between 0 and 1 for each class given by the 
        column name.
        </option>
		<option name="Fuzzy">
		<b>Fuzzy Norm</b> Select a fuzzy norm to compute the rules' activation 
		across all dimensions and rules. Fuzzy norms are important, because they
		combine the membership values of each fuzzy interval for one rule and 
		compute a final output across all rules. Different choices of fuzzy 
		norms are available: Min/Max Norm, Product Norm, Lukasiewicz Norm, and 
		Yager[2.0] Norm.<br />
		<b>Shrink Function</b> Select a shrink method to reduce rules in order
		to avoid conflicts between rules of different classes. There are three
		shrink methods available to normalize the loss in volume: 
		VolumnBorderBased shrink applies the volume loss in terms of the support
		or core region borders; VolumnAnchorBased shrink uses the anchor value 
		border; and VolumnRuleBased shrink uses the entire rule volume.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<dataIn index="0" name="Training Data">
			Numeric data as well as class information used for training.
		</dataIn>
		<dataOut index="0" name="Fuzzy Rules">
			Rules with fuzzy intervals in each dimension, classification columns,
			and additional rule measures.
		</dataOut>
		<modelOut index="0" name="Fuzzy Rule Model">
			Fuzzy Rule Model can be used for prediction.
		</modelOut>
	</ports>	
	<views>
		<view index="0" name="Learner Statistics">
			Displays a summary of the learning process.
		</view>
	</views>
	
</knimeNode>