<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.10" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10"
	type="Manipulator" icon="../outlier.png">
	<name>Numeric Outliers</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Detects and handles outliers for all numerical columns.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>
				This node detects and treats the outliers for each of the selected columns
				individually by means of
				<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Outlier#Tukey's_fences">interquartile range (IQR)</a>.
			</p>
			<p>
				To detect the outliers for a given column, the first and
				third
				quartile (Q<sub>1</sub>, Q<sub>3</sub>) is computed.
				An observation is flagged an outlier if it lies
				outside the range
				R = [Q<sub>1</sub> - k(IQR), Q<sub>3</sub> + k(IQR)] with
				IQR = Q<sub>3</sub> - Q<sub>1</sub>	and k &gt;= 0.
				Setting k = 1.5 the smallest value in R corresponds,
				typically, to the lower end of a boxplot's whisker and largest value
				to its upper end.
				<br />
				Providing grouping information allows to further detect
				outliers only within their respective groups. Columns for which
				outliers have to be detected will be skipped when computing the groups.
			</p>
			<p>
				If an observation is flagged an outlier, one can either remove
				the whole row from the data or replace it by some other value.
			</p>
			<p>
				Missing values contained in the data will be ignored, i.e., they
				will neither be used for the outlier computation nor will they be
				flagged as an outlier.
			</p>
		</intro>
		<tab name="Outlier Selection (Outlier Settings)">
			<option name="Outlier selection">
				Allows the selection of columns for which outliers have to be
				detected
				and treated. If "Compute outlier statistics on groups" (see tab "Group Settings") is selected,
				the outliers for each of the columns are computed solely with respect
				to the different groups.
			</option>

		</tab>
		
		<tab name="General Settings (Outlier Settings)">
			<option name="interquartile range multiplier (k)">
				Allows to scale the interquartile range (IQR).
				The default is k = 1.5.
			</option>
			
			<option name="Update domain">
				If checked the domain of the selected outlier columns
				is updated.
			</option>

			<option name="Use heuristic for quartile calculation (memory friendly)">
				If use heuristic is selected the quartiles will be calculated using
				a different approach than otherwise. While this heuristic is strongly
				favorable for large data sets due to its lower memory requirements
				while being rather precise, its results can be pretty far away from the
				accurate results for smaller data.
				<br/>
				<br/>
				Consequently, we recommend to check this option only if the data set
				is large enough, or memory is an issue.			
			</option>

			<option name="Estimation type">
				Typically the value of the quartiles is not part of the input, but
				lies between two observations. The estimation type allows to specify
				how to deal with this problem, e.g., R_4 applies linear-interpolation.
				A detailed explanation of the different options can be found
				<a
					href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantile#Estimating_quantiles_from_a_sample"> here</a>
				<br/>
				<br/>
				Note this option is only available if the use heuristic option is not selected.
			</option>

		</tab>

		<tab name="Outlier Treatment (Outlier Settings)">

			<option name="Treatment option">
				Defines three different strategies to treat outliers:
				<ul>
					<li>
						<b>Replace outlier values:</b>
						Allows to replace outliers based on the selected "Replacement
						strategy"
					</li>
					<li>
						<b>Remove outlier rows:</b>
						Removes all rows from the input data that contain in any of the
						selected columns at least one outlier
					</li>
					<li>
						<b>Exclusively retain outlier rows:</b>
						Retains only those rows of the input data that contain at
						least one outlier in any of the selected columns
					</li>

				</ul>
			</option>
			
			<option name="Apply to">
				Allows to apply the selected treatment strategy to
				<ul>
					<li>
						<b>All outliers</b>
					</li>
					<li>
						<b>Outliers below lower bound</b>
					</li>
					<li>
						<b>Outliers above upper bound</b>
					</li>
				</ul> 
			</option>

			<option name="Replacement strategy ">
				Defines two different strategies to replace outliers:
				<ul>
					<li>
						<b>Missing values:</b>
						Replaces every outlier by a missing value
					</li>
					<li>
						<b>Closest permitted value:</b>
						Replaces the value of each outlier by the closest value within the
						permitted interval R. If the column type is an integer the
						replacement value is the closest integer within the permitted interval.
					</li>
				</ul>
				Note that this option is only enabled if outliers have to be replaced.
			</option>

		</tab>
		
		<tab name="Group Selection (Group Settings)">
			<option name="Compute outlier statistics on groups">
				If selected, allows the selection of columns to identify groups. A group comprises all
				rows of the input exhibiting the same values in every single column (similar to the GroupBy node).
				The outliers will finally be computed with respect to each of the
				individual groups.
			</option>
			<option name="Column Filter">
			     Move the columns defining the groups into the Include list. The group definition will take priority,
			     i.e. if a column is selected for both group definition and outlier handling, 
			     it will be used to define groups (no outlier handling done for that column). 
			</option>

		</tab>
		<tab name="Memory Policy (Group Settings)">
			<option name="Process groups in memory">
				Processes the groups in the memory. This option comes with higher
				memory requirements, but is faster since the table does not 
				need any additional treatment.
			</option>
		
		
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Input data">Numeric input data to evaluate + optional group information</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Treated table">Data table where outliers were either
			replaced, rows containing outliers were removed, or exclusively retained
		</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="Summary">Data table holding the number of members, i.e., non-missing values 
		and outliers as well as the lower and upper	bound for each outlier group
		</outPort>
		<outPort index="2" name="Model">Model holding the permitted interval bounds for each
			outlier group and the outlier treatment specifications
		</outPort>
	</ports>

</knimeNode>