<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./roc.png" type="Visualizer">
    <name>ROC Curve</name>
    <shortDescription>Shows ROC curves</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This node draws ROC curves for two-class classification problems. The input table
            must contain a column with the real class values (including all class values as possible values)
            and a second column with the probabilities that an item (=row) will be classified as being
            from the selected class. Therefore only learners/predictors that output class probabilities can
            be used.
            <br />
            In order to create a ROC curve for a model, the input table is first sorted by the class probabilities
            for the positive class i.e. rows for which the model is certain that it belongs to the positive class
            are sorted to front. Then the sorted rows are checked if the real class value is the actually the positive
            class. If so, the ROC curve goes up one step, if not it goes one step to the right. Ideally, all positive
            rows are sorted to front, so you have a line going up to 100% first and then going straight to right. As a
            rule of thumb, the greater the area under the curve, the better is the model.
            <br />
            You may compare the ROC curves of several trained models by first joining the class probability columns
            from the different predictors into one table and then selecting several column in the column filter
            panel.
            <br />
            The light gray diagonal line in the diagram is the random line which is the worst possible performance a
            model can achieve.
        </intro>

        <option name="Class column">
            Select the column that contains the two classes that the model was trained on.
        </option>
        <option name="Positive class value">Select the value from the class column that stands for the "positive" class, i.e.
        the value high probabilities in the probability column (see below) are assigned to.</option>
        <option name="Columns containing the positive class probabilities">Select the
        column(s) that contain the probabilities for the a row being from the positive class.        
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <dataIn index="0" name="Input table">Input data with actual values and class probabilities</dataIn>
        <dataOut index="0" name="Areas under curve">
            A one-column table with the area(s) under the ROC curve(s)
        </dataOut>
    </ports>
    <views>
        <view index="0" name="ROC Curves">ROC curves</view>
    </views>
</knimeNode>
