<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./string_manipulation.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>String Manipulation</name>
    <shortDescription>Can do various string manipulations on the input columns,
    appending result as a new column.</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
	        <p>
				Can do various string manipulations on the input columns,
                appending result as a new column.
	        </p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Column List">
		  The list contains the column that are available in the input table.
		  Double click any of the column names to insert the respective field
		  in the expression editor. It will replace your current selection or
		  simply insert at the current caret position.
		</option>
		<option name="Flow Variable List">
		  The list contains the flow variables that are currently available at
		  the node input. Double clicking any of the entries will insert the
		  respective identifier at the current cursor position (replacing the
		  selection, if any).
		</option>		
		<option name="Insert Missing As Null">
		  If selected, missing values in the input table will be represented
		  by <tt>null</tt> in the expression. It is your responsibility to check
		  for <tt>null</tt> in this case. If unselected,
		  a missing value in the relevant input cell will immediately produce
		  a missing output cell (snippet not called). 
		</option>
		<option name="Compile on close">
		  If unchecked, the syntax test is skipped when the settings are 
		  applied to the model, allowing the dialog to close even if there are
		  syntax errors encountered. This enables the user to temporarily close
		  the dialog, investigate the input table and then return to the
		  almost-complete-and-running snippet code in the dialog. The node will
		  not be executable (it will be red) if the code contains syntax errors.
		  This option is only for convenience, it does not have any effect on
		  the output of this node.
		</option>
		<option name="Array Return">
		  If the result is an array, check this box. It will be represented
		  by a KNIME collection cell.  
		</option>
		<option name="Replace/Append">
		  Specify here if you want the result to be put into a separate or 
		  existing column.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <inPort name="Input table" index="0">Input table with columns of string type.</inPort>
        <outPort name="Appended table" index="0">Input table with an additional calculated column
	        or one column replaced.
        </outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
