<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./delegateloopend.png" type="LoopEnd">
    <name>Recursive Loop End</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
    The loop end node for a recursive loop. This type of loop passes data from the Recursive Loop End node to the Recursive Loop Start node.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        
        <p>
       The Recursive Loop node pair enables the passing of a data table from the Recursive Loop End back to the Recursive Loop Start.</p>
        
        <p>The Loop Start requires an initialized table. This table is output by the Recursive Loop Start in the first iteration of the loop.</p>
        
        <p>The table received by the corresponding Recursive Loop End is passed back to the Recursive Loop Start node.
        Starting with the second iteration, the Recursive Loop Start node outputs the data as received by the Recursive Loop End.</p>
        
		<p>
			The loop runs until one of the three stopping criteria is met:
			<ul>
				<li>Maximum number of iterations: to ensure no endless loop is
					created, the loop will end after the set number of iterations. </li>
				<li>Minimal number of rows: to ensure enough rows are present for processing, 
				    the loop stops if it's input contains less rows than the set minimum.</li>
				<li>End loop with variable: the loop ends if the option is enabled and the value of the selected variable equals "true"</li>
			</ul>
		</p>
        
        <p>The data passed to port 0 is collected and passed to the output port. 
        The data in port 1 is returned to the Recursive Loop Start node.</p>
        </intro>
        <option name="Maximal number of iterations">The maximum number of iterations the loop will run.</option>
        <option name="Minimal number of rows">The minimal number of rows required to continue iterating.</option>
        <option name="End Loop with Variable">Whether the node execution is controlled by a variable, when enabled allows choosing the Flow Variable that ends the loop if it's value equals "true".</option>   
        <option name="Collect data from last iteration only">If this option is checked only the last input to the collecting data port is passed through to the outport. Hence, the data of earlier iterations is discarded.</option>  
        <option name="Add iteration column">Allows you to add a column containing the iteration number to the output table.</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Collecting data">Data to be collected for the output.</inPort>
          <inPort index="1" name="Recursion data">Data to be passed back to loop start.</inPort>
      
        <outPort index="0" name="Collected data"> The rows collected from the first in port. </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
