<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 1.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./bitvector.png" type="Manipulator">
	<name>Bitvector Generator</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
			    Generates bitvectors either from a table containing only numerical values, or from 
			    a string column containing the ids to be set.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>Generates bitvectors either from a table containing only numerical values or from
		a string column. In the case of numerical values, a threshold must be 
		defined. Assuming you have an n x m matrix A of numerical values: the 
		ouput would be n x 1, where the only column contains bitvectors of 
		length m. If the value in row n and column m is above the threshold, the
		m-th bit in the n-th bitvector is set.
		In the case of a string column, the string column is considered to consist
		of item ids present in this transaction, therefore, the string is parsed and
		for every id, the referring bit is set in the bitvector. Finally, all 
		bitvectors are of the length of the highest id+1.
		</intro>
		<option name="Parse ids from string column">
			Check, if the input for the bitvectors is a string column with the item 
			ids present in the referring transaction. Uncheck, if the data is a 
			table with numerical data only and all values above a certain threshold 
			should be set bits in the resulting bitvectors.
		</option>		
		<option name="String column containing the item ids">
			If the "parse from string column" is checked, select the column
			containing the item ids.
		</option>
		<option key="Threshold above bits are set">
			If the "parse from string column" is unchecked, definition of the threshold
			above the values is considered to be set bits. 
			The threshold is inclusive.
		</option>	
        <option name="Use a percentage of the mean values as threshold">
            Check, if a percentage of the mean of each column should serve as 
            threshold above which the bits are set.
        </option>	
        <option name="Percentage of the mean">
            Specify which percentage of the mean should have a value that is set to the 
            referring bit.
        </option>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<dataIn index="0" name="Input data to create bit vectors from">Datatable with numerical data or a string column to be parsed.</dataIn>
		<dataOut index="0" name="Bit vector data">Datatable with the generated bitvectors.</dataOut>
	</ports>	
	<views>
		<view index="0" name="Statistics View">
			 Provides information about the generation of the bitsets from  
			 the data. In particular this is the number of processed rows, 
			 the resulting bitvector length, the total number of generated 
			 zeros and ones and the resulting ratio from 1s to 0s.
		</view>
	</views>
</knimeNode>
