<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./sgm_market.png" type="Learner">
	<name>Association Rule Learner</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
		Searches for frequent itemsets with a certain minimum support 
	    in a set of bitvectors and optionally generates association rules 
	    with a particular confidence from them.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			Searches for frequent itemsets meeting the user-defined minimum support
			criterion and, optionally, creates association rules from them. 
			The column containing the bitvectors has to be selected. The minimum 
			support as an absolute number must be provided (therefore check the number
			of transactions to obtain a sensible criterion). If the frequent itemsets
			should be free (unconstrained) or closed or maximal has also be defined.
			Closed itemsets are frequent itemsets, which have no superset with the 
			same support, thus providing all the information from free itemsets 
			in a compressed form.  Maximal itemsets are itemsets which have no 
			frequent superset at all. The maximal itemset length must also be 
			defined. If only frequent itemset are mined (and no association rules
			generated) the output can be sorted by support of the itemsets or their
			length. If association rules are generated a confidence value has to be
			provided. The confidence is a value to define how often the rule is 
			right. Association rules generated here are in the form to have only one
			item in the consequence.
			The underlying data structure can be either an ARRAY or a TIDList. 
			Choose the former when there are many transactions an less items, and 
			the latter if the structure of the input data is vice versa.		
		</intro>
		
	<option name="Column containing bitvectors">
		Select the column containing the bitvectors to mine for frequent 
		itemsets or association rules. There ust be at least one, since this is
		the only valid input for the subgroup miner.
	</option>
	<option name="Minimum Support">
		An itemset is considered to be frequent if there are at least "minimum
		support" transactions, where the itemset occurs. Make sure, to have here
		a meaningful number in proportion of the number of rows of the input.
	</option>
	<option name="Itemset type">
		Choose either free, closed or maximal. Free are mostly redundant, closed
		provide the most information and maximal may hide some information.
	</option>
	<option name="Maximal itemset length">
		The maximal length of the resulting itemsets. A lower value may reduce 
		the runtime if there are very long frequent itemsets.
	</option>
	<option name="Sort output table">
		The sorting is only for the frequent itemsets available (not for the 
		association rules). They can be sorted either by itemset length or by
		their support. Choose NONE, if no sorting should be done.
	</option>	
	<option name="Output association rules">
		Check if association rules should be generated out of the frequent 
		itemsets. Note: association rules are always generated from free 
		frequent itemsets and are contrained to have only one item in the
		consequence.
	</option>	
	<option name="Confidence">
		The confidence is a measure for "how often the rule is right". Thus, how
		often, if the items in the antecedence appeared also the consequence 
		occured in the transactions.
	</option>	
	<option name="Underlying data structure">
		Either ARRAY or TIDList. Array is recommended when the number of 
		transactions (rows) is larger than the numer of items, and the TIDList
		if the number of rows is small and the number of items large. In
		general, the array needs more memory and is a bit faster, whereas the 
		TIDList need less memory but is a bit slower.
	</option>	
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<dataIn index="0" name="Bitvectors">Datatable containing bitvectors.</dataIn>
		<dataOut index="0" name="Frequent itemsets/Association rules">Datatable with discovered frequent itemsets or association rules.</dataOut>
        <modelOut index="0" name="Model">Frequent itemset or association rule model.</modelOut>
	</ports>	
</knimeNode>