<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./switch_esac_variable.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.6" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.6 http://knime.org/node/v3.6.xsd">
	<name>CASE Switch Variable (End)</name>
	
    <shortDescription>
        Merges 1-3 branches which were initially created by a CASE
        Switch Variable Node.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        	<p>This nodes takes the flow variables from the active input. If all branches are inactive the 
        	flow variables of the top branch are passed through.
			</p>
			<p>
				NOTE - Due to the way in which flow variables are handled within
				KNIME, the flow variable values for any existing flow
				variables beyond the corresponding
				"end" node will always be those at the top-most port of the "end" node. New
				variables created in any active branch will
				retain their correct values. If you need to change the value of existing
				variables, please either use
				a new flow variable, or use a
				<i>Variable to Table Row</i> node before a conventional <i>End CASE</i>
				node.
			</p>
        </intro>
        <option name="If multiple inputs are active">
            Choose the expected behavior of the node if two or more inputs are active. The default behavior is to fail
            during executing. Alternatively you can pass on the first active input (hence ignore any subsequent active
            port). In case all inputs are inactive the node itself will pass on an inactive object as well.
        </option>
        <link href="https://www.knime.com/knime-introductory-course/chapter7/section1/creation-and-usage-of-flow-variables">
            KNIME E-Learning Course: Creation and usage of Flow Variables in a KNIME workflow
        </link>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="First Flow Variable input">The first Flow Variable input port.</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Second (optional) Flow Variable input">The second optional Flow Variable input port.</inPort>
        <inPort index="2" name="Third (optional) Flow Variable input">The third optional Flow Variable input port.</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Flow Variable output">Flow Variable output port.</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
