<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./col_combine.png" type="Manipulator">
	<name>Column Combiner</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
	    Combines the content of a set of columns and appends the concatenated string
	    as separate column to the input table.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			Combines the content of a set of columns and appends the concatenated string
	    	as separate column to the input table. The user needs to specify in the dialog
	    	the columns of interest and some other properties, such as delimiter to separate
	    	the different cell contents and quoting options.
		</intro>
		
		
		<option name="Delimiter">Enter a delimiter string here. This string is used to separate 
		the different cell contents in the new, appended column.</option>
		<option name="Quote Character">The character entered here will be used to quote the cell content 
		in case that it contains the delimiter string (for instance if the cell content is
		<i>some;value</i>, the delimiter string is ';' (a single semicolon), and the quote character is '"' 
		(single quote char) the quoted string will be <i>"some;value"</i> 
		(including quotes)). You can force quotation by checking "Quote Always".	
		Alternatively, the user can also replace the delimiter	string in the cell content string (see below).</option>
		<option name="Replace Delimiter by">If the string representation of the cell content contains the
		delimiter string, it will be replaced by the string entered here (if you entered '-' here, the output of 
		the above example would be <i>some-value</i>).</option>
		<option name="Name of appended column">The name of the new column.</option>
		<option name="Column Selection">Move the columns of interest into the &quot;Include&quot; list.</option>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Input">Arbitrary input data.</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Input with appended column">Input data + additional column containing string combination</outPort>
	</ports>	
</knimeNode>
