<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Manipulator">
	<name>Split Collection Column</name>
	<shortDescription>
	   Splits a collection column into its sub components, adding one new column
	   for each.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
		  This node splits a column containing a collection of cells into its
		  sub-components. If a row contains more elements than implied by 
		  the various options (see below), the remaining elements are ignored. 
		  If it contains less elements than expected, the remaining columns
		  are filled with missing values.  
		</intro>
		<option name="Column Selection">
		  Select the column containing the collection value</option>
		<option name="Replace input column">
		  Select this when the column containing the collection is to 
		  be removed the output.</option>
		<option name="Determine most specific type">
		  The collection column often contains only general type information to
		  the individual elements. Selecting this option will determine the
		  most specific type of the newly appended column based on the 
		  actual content. If unsure, keep this option selected.  
		  </option>
		<option name="Element Count Policy">
		  Select the policy on how to determine how many elements the input
		  column contains. Three different modes are available:
		  <ol>
		      <li>Count in advance: Perform one additional scan on the table 
		          and count the occurrences. The names of the new column's are
		          auto-generated.</li>
		      <li>Use input table information: Use the "element names" field
		          in the collection column. This information may not always
		          be present in the input table, in which case the node will 
		          fail its execution. The column names are defined by the
		          element names.</li>
		      <li>Best effort: Try to use the information from the input 
		          table; if none is available, count the occurrences.</li>
		  </ol>
		  </option>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<dataIn index="0" name="Data wit collection column">
		  Input data with collection column to split</dataIn>
		<dataOut index="0" name="Input data with newly appended columns">
		The input data along with a newly append columns.</dataOut>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>