<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 1.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./smote.png" type="Manipulator">         
    <name>SMOTE</name>         
    <shortDescription>Oversamples data using the SMOTE algorithm by Chawla et. al.</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
			Oversamples data using the 
			<a href="http://www.cs.cmu.edu/afs/cs/project/jair/pub/volume16/chawla02a.pdf">
			SMOTE (Synthetic Minority Over-sampling Technique)</a> algorithm by 
			Chawla et al. The algorithm creates synthetic examples for classes
			of interest by extrapolating between a real sample of the class and
			one of the sample's neighbors. The paper describing this technique 
			is available online at
			<a href="http://www.cs.cmu.edu/afs/cs/project/jair/pub/volume16/chawla02a.pdf">
			http://www.cs.cmu.edu/afs/cs/project/jair/pub/volume16/chawla02a.pdf</a>.
		</intro>
		<option name="Class Column">
		    Pick the column that contains the class information.
		</option>
		<option name="Nearest neighbor">
			An option that determines how many nearest neighbors shall be considered.
			The algorithm picks an object from the target class, randomly selects 
			one of its neighbors and draws the new synthetic example along the 
			line between the sample and the neighbor.
		</option>
		<option name="Oversample by">
			Checking this option oversamples each class equally. You need to 
			specify how much synthetic data is introduced, e.g. a value of 2 
			will introduce two more portions for each class (if there are 50 
			rows in the input table labeled as "A"; the output will contain 
			150 rows belonging to "A").  
		</option>
		<option name="Oversample minority classes">
		    This option adds synthetic examples to all classes that are
			not the majority class. The output contains the same number
			of rows for each of the possible classes. 
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
    <ports>                 
        <dataIn index="0" name="Input data">Table containing labeled data for oversampling</dataIn>
        <dataOut index="0" name="Oversampled data">Oversampled data (input table with appended rows).</dataOut>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
