<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./smote.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>SMOTE</name>
    <shortDescription>Adds artificial data to improve the learning quality using the SMOTE algorithm</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
	        <p>
        	This node oversamples the input data (i.e. adds artificial rows) to enrich the 
        	training data. The applied technique is called 
        	<a href="http://www.cs.cmu.edu/afs/cs/project/jair/pub/volume16/chawla02a.pdf">
			SMOTE (Synthetic Minority Over-sampling Technique)</a> by 
			Chawla et al. 
			</p>
			<p>
			Some supervised learning algorithms (such as decision trees and neural nets)
			require an equal class distribution to generalize well, i.e. to get good 
			classification performance. In case of unbalanced input data,
			for instance there are only few objects of the &quot;active&quot; but 
			many of the &quot;inactive&quot; class, this node adjusts the class distribution 
			by adding artificial rows (in the example by adding rows for the &quot;active&quot; class). 
			</p>
			<p>
			The algorithm works roughly as follows: It creates synthetic rows by extrapolating 
			between a real object of a given class (in the above example &quot;active&quot;) 
			and one of its nearest neighbors (of the same class). It then picks a point
			along the line between these two objects and determines the attributes (cell values)
			of the new object based on this randomly chosen point.
			</p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Class Column">
		    Pick the column that contains the class information.
		</option>
		<option name="Nearest neighbor">
			An option that determines how many nearest neighbors shall be considered.
			The algorithm picks an object from the target class, randomly selects 
			one of its neighbors and draws the new synthetic example along the 
			line between the sample and the neighbor.
		</option>
		<option name="Oversample by">
			Checking this option oversamples each class equally. You need to 
			specify how much synthetic data is introduced, e.g. a value of 2 
			will introduce two more portions for each class (if there are 50 
			rows in the input table labeled as "A"; the output will contain 
			150 rows belonging to "A").  
		</option>
		<option name="Oversample minority classes">
		    This option adds synthetic examples to all classes that are
			not the majority class. The output contains the same number
			of rows for each of the possible classes. 
		</option>
		<option name="Enable static seed">
			Check this option if you want to use a seed for the random number 
			generator. This will cause consecutive runs of the node to produce
			the same output data. If unchecked, each run of the node generates
			a new seed. Use "Draw new seed" to randomly draw a new seed.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <dataIn index="0" name="Input data">Table containing labeled data for oversampling.</dataIn>
        <dataOut index="0" name="Oversampled data">Oversampled data (input table with appended rows).</dataOut>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
