<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./kmeans.ico" type = "Learner">
	<name>Fuzzy c-Means</name>
	<shortDescription>
	    Performs fuzzy c-means clustering.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>		
		<p>
			The fuzzy c-means algorithm is a well-known unsupervised learning 
			technique that can be used to reveal the underlying structure of the data.
			Fuzzy clustering allows each data point to belong to several clusters, with
			a degree of membership to each one.<br />
			<b>Make sure that the input data is normalized to obtain better clustering
			results.</b><br/>
			The list of attributes to use can be set in the second tab of the
			dialog.<br/>
			The first output datatable provides the original datatable with the 
			cluster memberships to each cluster. The second datatable provides 
			the values of the cluster prototypes.<br />
			Additionally, it is possible to induce a noise cluster, to detect noise
			in the dataset, based on the approach from R. N. Dave: 'Characterization
			and detection of noise in clustering'.
		</p>
	</intro>
	<option name="Number of clusters">
	Number of clusters to use for the algorithm.
    </option>
    <option name="Maximum number of iterations">
    This is the maximum number of iterations to be performed.
    </option>
    <option name="Fuzzifier">
    Indicates how much the clusters are allowed to overlap.
    </option>
    <option name="Induce noise cluster">
    Whether to induce a noise cluster or not.
    </option>
     <option name="Set delta">
    Delta is the fixed distance from every datapoint to the noise cluster.
    </option>
    <option name="Set delta automatically, specify lambda">
    Delta is updated in each iteration, based on the average interpoint 
    distances. However, a lambda paramater has to be set, according to the
    shape of the clusters.
    </option>
    <option name="Perform the clustering in memory">
    If this option is selected, the clustering is performed in the memory,
    which speeds up the process.
    </option>
    <option name="Compute cluster quality measures">
    Whether to calculate quality measures for the clustering. This can be
    time and memory consuming with large datasets.
    </option>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Training data">Datatable with training data. Make
		sure that the data are normalized!</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Cluster Memberships">Input table extended
		 by cluster membership</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="Prototypes">Cluster centers</outPort>
	</ports>
	<views>
		<view index="0" name="Statistics View">
			Shows the WithinClusterVariation and the BetweenClusterVariation, 
			which are indicators for 'good' clustering.
		</view>
	</views>	
</knimeNode>
