<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode type="Predictor" icon="./rule_engine.png" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.8 http://knime.org/node/v2.8.xsd">
	<name>Rule Engine</name>
	<shortDescription>
		 Applies user-defined business rules to the input table
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node takes a list of user-defined rules and tries to match them
			to each row in the input table. If a rule matches, its outcome value
			is added into a new column.
			The first matching rule in order of definition determines the outcome.
			<p>
				Each rule is represented by a line.
				The comments start with
				<tt>//</tt>
				in a line, and anything after that is not interpreted as a rule in
				that line.
				Rules consist of a condition part (antecedent), which must
				evaluate to
				<i>true</i>
				or
				<i>false</i>
				, and an outcome (consequent, after the =&gt; symbol) which is put into
				the new column if the rule matches.
			</p>
			<p>The outcome of a rule may be any of the following: a string (between <tt>"</tt> or <tt>/</tt>), a number, a boolean constant, a reference
                to another column or the value of a flow variable value.
				The type of the outcome column is the common super
				type of all possible
				outcomes (including the rules that can never
				match).
				If no rule matches, the outcome is a missing value.
			</p>
			<p>
				Columns are given by their name surrounded by $, numbers are given
				in the usual decimal representation. Note that strings must not
				contain (double-)quotes. Flow variables are represented by
				<b>$${</b>
				TypeCharacterAndFlowVarName
				<b>}$$</b>
				.
				The TypeCharacter should be 'D' for double (real) values, 'I' for
				integer values and 'S' for strings.
                You can insert column names or flow variables by hand or by clicking in the respective lists in the
                dialog.
			</p>
            <p>The logical expressions can be grouped with parentheses. The
                precedence rules for them are the following: <tt>NOT</tt> binds most, <tt>AND</tt>,
                <tt>XOR</tt> and finally <tt>OR</tt> the least.
                Comparison operators always take
                precedence over logical connectives.
                All operators (and their names)
                are case-sensitive.
            </p>
			<p>
				The
				<tt>ROWID</tt>
				represents the row key string, the
				<tt>ROWINDEX</tt>
				is a the index of the row (first row has
				<tt>0</tt>
				value), while
				<tt>ROWCOUNT</tt>
				stands for the number of rows in the table.
			</p>
			<p>Some example rules (each should be in one line):</p>
			<pre>
// This is a comment
$Col0$ > 0 => "Positive"
</pre>
			When the values in Col0 are greater than 0, we assign Positive to the
			result column value (if no previous rule matched).
			<pre>
$Col0$ = "Active" AND $Col1$ &lt;= 5 => "Outlier"
</pre>
			You can combine conditions.
			<pre>
$Col0$ LIKE "Market Street*" AND 
    ($Col1$ IN ("married", "divorced") 
        OR $Col2$ > 40) => "Strange"
$Col0$ MATCHES $${SFlowVar0}$$ OR $$ROWINDEX$$ &lt; $${IFlowVar1}$$ =>
    $Col0$
</pre>
			With parentheses you can combine multiple conditions. The result in
			the second case comes from one of the columns.
			<pre>
$Col0$ > 5 => $${SCol1}$$
</pre>
			The result can also come from a flow variable.
			<p>
				You can use either Ctrl+Space to insert predefined parts, or
				select them from the upper controls.
			</p>
			
			<p>
			The following comparisons result true
			(other values are neither less, nor greater or equal to missing and NaN values):
			<ul>
			<li><b>?</b> =,&lt;=,&gt;= <b>?</b></li>
			<li><b>NaN</b> =,&lt;=,&gt;= <b>NaN</b></li>
			</ul>
			</p>
		</intro>

		<tab name="Rule Editor">
			<option name="Column List">Available columns, which can be used as variables
				in a rule.
			</option>
			<option name="Flow Variable List">Available flow variables, which can be used as
				variables in a rule.
			</option>
			<option name="Category">The operator categories.</option>
			<option name="Function">A list of valid operators in the selected
				category.
			</option>
			<option name="Description">Short help about the operator.</option>
			<option name="Expression">The rule editor. You can complete the expressions
				with Ctrl+Space. Each row represents a rule. A red background of the
				line signals an error and the left side of the editor then shows an error icon.
			</option>
			<option name="Append Column">Name of the newly appended column,
				which contains the outcome of the rules.
			</option>
			<option name="Replace Column">The column to replace</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Table">Any datatable</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Classified values">The input table with an additional
			column containing the outcome of the matching rule for each row.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>