<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode type="Manipulator" icon="./rule_engine_splitter.png"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.8 http://knime.org/node/v2.8.xsd">
	<name>Rule-based Row Splitter</name>
	<shortDescription>
		 Splits the input table based on user-defined business rules
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node takes a list of user-defined rules and tries to match them
			to each row in the input table in the defined order. If a rule matches and the outcome is
			<tt>TRUE</tt>, the row will be selected for inclusion in the first output table. If the first matching rule
            yields <tt>FALSE</tt> the row will be included in the second output table.
			If no rule matches this row will be put to the second output table (like when the last rule would be <tt>TRUE => FALSE</tt>).
            The roles of first and second output table can be exchanged, see option below.
			<p>
				Each rule is represented by a line.
				The comments start with
				<tt>//</tt>
				in a line, and anything after that is not interpreted as a rule in
				that line.
				Rules consist of a condition part (antecedent), which must
				evaluate to
				<i>true</i>
				or
				<i>false</i>
				, and an outcome (consequent, after the => symbol) which is either
				<tt>TRUE</tt>
				or
				<tt>FALSE</tt>
				.
			</p>
			<p>
				If no rule matches, the outcome is treated as if it were
				<tt>FALSE</tt>
				.
			</p>
			<p>
				Columns are given by their name surrounded by $, numbers are given
				in the usual decimal representation. Note that strings must not
				contain (double-)quotes. The flow variables are
				represented by
				<b>$${</b>
				TypeCharacterAndFlowVarName
				<b>}$$</b>
				.
				The TypeCharacter should be 'D' for double (real) values, 'I' for
				integer values and 'S' for strings.
			</p>
			<p>The logical expressions can be grouped with parentheses. The
				precedence rules for them are the following: <tt>NOT</tt> binds most, <tt>AND</tt>,
				<tt>XOR</tt> and finally <tt>OR</tt> the least.
				Comparison operators always take
				precedence over logical connectives.
				All operators (and their names)
				are case-sensitive.
			</p>
			<p>
				The
				<tt>ROWID</tt>
				represents the row key string, the
				<tt>ROWINDEX</tt>
				is a the index of the row (first row has
				<tt>0</tt>
				value), while
				<tt>ROWCOUNT</tt>
				stands for the number of rows in the table.
			</p>
			<p>Some example rules (each should be in one line):</p>
			<pre>
// This is a comment
$Col0$ > 0 => TRUE
</pre>
			When the values in Col0 are greater than 0, we select the row to the
			first outport (if no previous rule matched with FALSE outcome).
			<pre>
$Col0$ = "Active" AND $Col1$ &lt;= 5 => TRUE
</pre>
			You can combine conditions.
			<pre>
$Col0$ LIKE "Market Street*" AND 
    ($Col1$ IN ("married", "divorced") 
        OR $Col2$ > 40) => FALSE
</pre>
			With parentheses you can combine multiple conditions.
			<pre>
$Col0$ MATCHES $${SFlowVar0}$$ OR $$ROWINDEX$$ &lt; $${IFlowVar1}$$ =>
    FALSE
</pre>
			The flow variables, table constants can also appear in conditions.
			<p>
				You can use either Ctrl+Space to insert predefined parts, or
				select them from the upper controls.
			</p>
		</intro>

		<option name="Column List">Available columns, which can be used as variables
			in a rule.
		</option>
		<option name="Flow Variable List">Available flow variables, which can be used as
			variables in a rule.
		</option>
		<option name="Category">The operator categories.</option>
		<option name="Function">A list of valid operators in the selected
			category.
		</option>
		<option name="Description">Short help about the operator.</option>
		<option name="Expression">The rule editor. You can complete the expressions
            with Ctrl+Space. Each row represents a rule. A red background of the
            line signals an error and the left side of the editor then shows an error icon.
		</option>
		<option
			name="TRUE to first, FALSE to second output table">
			A row will be included in the first output table if the first
			rule that matches has TRUE outcome. If the first matching rule yields FALSE the row will go to the second
            output table. If unchecked, the roles of the first and second output table will be switched.
		</option>

	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Input table">Any data table that should be splitted</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="First output">First output table with rows that are evaluated to TRUE</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="Second output">Second output table with rows that are evaluated to FALSE</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>