<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="urltofilepath.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>URL to File Path (Variable)</name>
    <shortDescription>Converts URLs into file paths.
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
			Converts the url strings of the specified string flow variable 
			into file path strings. Four string flow variables will be
			set. The first contains the complete file path, the second the 
			parent folder of the file, the third contains the file name 
			(without extension), and the last contains the file extension.
			<br/>
			It can be specified whether the node will fail if an invalid url 
			string occurs or a file location does not exist. If failing is 
			switched off (default) empty strings will set as values for each 
			output variable.
		</intro>
        <option name="Add prefix to variable identifiers">
            If checked, the name of the specified input variable is used as
            prefix for the names of the output variables.
        </option>
        <option name="Fail if URL has invalid syntax">
            If checked, node will fail if an invalid url string occurs,
            otherwise an empty string will be set as file path, parent folder, 
            file name, and file extension variables.
        </option>
	    <option name="Fail if file does not exist">
            If checked, node will fail if a file location does not exist,
            otherwise an empty string will set as file path parent folder, file
            name, and file extension variables.
        </option>        
	</fullDescription>
		
	<ports>
        <inPort name="Flow variable containing URL string" index="0">
            A string flow variable containing the url string to convert.
        </inPort>
        <outPort name="Flow variables containing converted strings" index="0">
        	Four additional string flow variables containing the file path, 
        	parent folder, the file name, and the file extension.
        </outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>