<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./add_empty_rows.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Add Empty Rows</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Adds a certain number of empty rows with missing values or a given 
        constant to the input table.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Adds a certain number of empty rows with missing values 
            (or a constant) to the input table. This can be useful when
            used in a report table to ensure that a table has a 
            minimum number of rows, which are then shown as blank rows. 
            The content of the appended rows can be defined in the dialog, the
            default is to fill the corresponding cells with missing values. Note
            that the reporting engine allows you to format cells containing 
            missing values (or any other specific value) using the "Map" 
            feature. For instance, if you want to format missing values (shown 
            as NaN in the report) as blank fields, add a map rule 
            isNaN(row["Column x"]), which needs to evaluate to True.
        </intro>
        
        <option name="Number of rows in output">Choose whether to add a fixed 
            number of rows to the input table ("Additional"), independent of the
            input table's row count; or to add rows to the table only in case 
            there are less rows than indicated ("At least"). The latter will
            not change the input table if there are already more rows than
            specified in the corresponding field.</option>
        <option name="Fill Data">Specify the content of newly added rows. For
            common base types (Double, Int, String), choose either a fixed value
            or "Missing", which then fills in a missing value. Columns with 
            another type than listed here are always filled with missing values.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input table">Any input table</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Output table">
            Input table augmented by additional rows</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
