<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./SVM_learn.png" type = "Learner">
	<name>SVM Learner</name>
	<shortDescription>
	    Trains a support vector machine.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>		
		<p>
	This node trains a support vector machine on the input data.
	It supports a number of different kernels (HyperTangent, Polynomial and RBF).
	The SVM learner supports multiple class problems as well (by computing the
	hyperplane between each class and the rest), but note that this will increase
	the runtime.
	</p>
	<p>
	The SVM learning algorithm used is described in the following papers:
	<a href="http://research.microsoft.com/~jplatt/smo-book.pdf">
	Fast Training of Support Vector Machines using Sequential Minimal 
	Optimization</a>, by John C. Platt and
	<a href="http://coblitz.codeen.org:3125/citeseer.ist.psu.edu/cache/papers/cs/11207/http:zSzzSzguppy.mpe.nus.edu.sgzSz~mpesskzSzsmo_mod.pdf/improvements-to-platt-s.pdf">
	Improvements to Platt's SMO Algorithm for SVM Classifier Design</a>, by
		S. S. Keerthi et. al.
	</p>
	<p>
	If the optional PMML inport is connected and contains 
    preprocessing operations in the TransformationDictionary those are 
    added to the learned model.
    </p>
	</intro>
	<option name="Class column">
	Choose the column that contains the nominal target variable.
    </option>
    <option name="Overlapping penalty">
	The overlapping penalty is useful in the case that the input data is
	not separable. It determines how much penalty is assigned to each point
	that is misclassified. A good value for it is 1.
    </option>
	<option name="Kernel type">
	There are a number of kernels to choose from. Each kernel has
		its own parameters, which appear in the configuration dialog
		just under the kernel.
    </option>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name = "Training Data">Datatable with training data</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="PMML Preprocessing">Optional PMML port object containing preprocessing operations.</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name = "Trained SVM">Trained Support Vector Machine</outPort>
	</ports>	
	
	<views>
		<view index="0" name="SVM View">
			Shows the trained Support Vector Machines for each class
			with their corresponding support vectors.
		</view>
	</views>	
</knimeNode>