<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="collumnappend.png" type="Manipulator">
	<name>Column Appender</name>

	<shortDescription>
		A fast way to reverse the operation of a splitter
		node.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
	<intro>
		The Column Appender takes two tables and quickly combines them by
		appending the columns of the second table to the first table. It
		performs a similar function to the Joiner but can be
		faster for large
		tables. However, it only should be used if certain preconditions are
		met. For more details please read the description of the "Identical row
		keys and table lengths"-option below. When in doubt, use the Joiner.
		<br></br>
		If the input tables share some column names, the offending column
		names from the bottom table will be appended with "(#1)".
		<br></br>
		<br></br>
		Hint for streaming: the node is only streamable if the option
		"Identical row keys and table lengths" is NOT checked.
	</intro>
	<tab name="Options">
		<option name="Identical row keys and table lengths">
			If the row keys in both input tables exactly match (i.e. the row key
			names, their order, and their number have to match) this option can
			be checked in
			order to allow a faster execution with less memory consumption. However,
			the node won't be streamable.
			<br></br>
			<br></br>
			If the option
			<i>is NOT checked</i>
			the result table is newly created. This might result in a longer
			processing time. However, in this case the number of rows in the input tables can differ
			and missing values are added accordingly. The row keys are either taken from the first table, second table, or generated entirely new (see options below).
		</option>
		<option name = "Use row keys from FIRST table">
			Only available if "Identical row keys and table lengths" is not
			checked. The row keys of the first input table are used. If the first table
			is longer than the second table, missing values are inserted. If the
			first table is shorter, the second table is truncated.
		</option>
	     <option name = "Use row keys from SECOND table">
			Only available if "Identical row keys and table lengths" is not
			checked. The row keys of the second input table are used. If the second table
			is longer than the first table, missing values are inserted. If the
			second table is shorter, the first table is truncated.
		</option>
		<option name = "Generate new row keys">
		    Only available if "Identical row keys and table lengths" is not
			checked. Row keys are newly generated. If one of the input table is longer than the other, missing values are inserted accordingly.
		</option>
	</tab>

</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Table 1">If the option "Identical row keys and table lengths" is checked: a sorted table with n rows. Otherwise a table without restrictions.</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="Table 2">If the option "Identical row keys and table lengths" is checked: Another sorted table with n rows. Otherwise a table without restrictions.
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Appended table">A table with the columns from both
			Table 1 and Table 2
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>

