<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="bindictionary.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Binner (Dictionary)</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Categorizes values in a column according to a dictionary table with
        min/max values.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>
              Categorizes values in a column according to a dictionary table 
              with min/max values. The table at the first input contains a
              column with values to be categorized. The second table contains
              a column with lower bound values, a column with upper bound
              values and a column with label values. The latter will be used as
              outcome in case a given value is between the corresponding lower
              and upper bound. Each row in the second table represents a rule, 
              whereby the rules are evaluated top-down, i.e. rules with low
              row index have higher priority than rules in the subsequent rows.
            </p>
            <p>
              Either the lower or upper bound test can be disabled by unsetting
              the corresponding checkbox in the dialog. Missing values in the 
              columns containing upper and lower bounds will always evaluate 
              the bound check to true. That is, a missing value in the lower 
              bound column will always be smaller and a missing value in the
              upper bound column will always be larger than the value. Missing
              values in the value column (1st input) will result in a missing
              cell output (no categorization).
            </p>
            <p>
              <b>Note:</b> The table containing bound and label information 
              (2nd input) will be read into memory during execution; it must be
              a relatively small table!
            </p>
        </intro>
        <option name="Value Column to bin (1st port)">
          Select the column in the first input table containing the values
          to be categorized.
        </option>
        <option name="Lower Bound Column (2nd port)">
          If enabled, select the column containing the lower bound values. 
          Choose whether a value must be strictly smaller or smaller or equal
          than the lower bound value by selecting the "Inclusive" checkbox
          (if checked it will be smaller or equal).
        </option>
        <option name="Upper Bound Column (2nd port)">
          If enabled, select the column containing the upper bound values. 
          Choose whether a value must be strictly larger or larger or equal
          than the upper bound value by selecting the "Inclusive" checkbox 
          (if checked it will be larger or equal).
        </option>
        <option name="Label Column (2nd port)">
          Select the label column from the 2nd input that will be appended as
          category column to the output table.
        </option>
        <option name="If no rule matches">
          Choose the behavior if none of the rules in the 2nd input fires for
          a given value: Select "Fail" to make this node fail during execution
          (reasonable when the rule table is assumed to cover the entire domain)
          or "Insert Missing" to insert missing values as result. 
        </option>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input to be categorized">
            Arbitrary input data with column to be binned.
        </inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Rule/Dictionary table">
            Table containing categorization rules with lower and upper bound
            and the label column.
        </inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Categorized data">
            Input table amended by column with categorization values.
        </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
