<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./string_replace_dict.png" type="Manipulator">
	<name>String Replace (Dictionary)</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
	   Replaces the values in a column by matching entries of a dictionary file.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
		<p>
			This node replaces the cells in a selected column by elements of a 
			dictionary. The cell is compared against the keys in the dictionary file and
			- given that a matching key is found - the cell content is then replaced by
			 the value of the respective dictionary entry. 
		 </p>
		<p>
		 	The dictionary must be plain text file, whereas rows in the file correspond
		 	to entries in a dictionary. Each line should be of the format
		 </p>
		 <pre>    value, key1, key2, key3, ...</pre>
		 <p>
			 The <i>value</i> string corresponds to the replacement string (matching
			 keys are replaced with this value).The keys are given by the strings after 
			 the value (<i>key1</i>, <i>key2</i>, ... in the example), i.e. there are 
			 multiple keys possible. If no key matches the input string, the cell content
			 remains the same. Only exact matches are possible.
		 </p>
		 <p>
		 	Note: The dictionary does not get saved to the archive when the flow is
		 	exported. The dictionary file needs to be saved/exported separately.
		 </p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Target Column">The column containing the to-be-replaced elements.</option>
		<option name="Dictionary Location">The plain text file containing the dictionary entries (see above).</option>
		<option name="Delimiter in Dictionary">The delimiter character used in the dictionary file. In the above 
		example this is a single comma (',') but can be (almost) any character. Special characters available are
		'\t' for a tab and '\\' for a single backslash.</option>
		<option name="Append Column">If checked, the replaced values will be put into a separate new column, 
		which is appended to the table (specify the name in the textfield). If unchecked, the target column is replaced.</option>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<dataIn index="0" name="Input">Arbitrary input data.</dataIn>
		<dataOut index="0" name="Input with amended column">Input data but with input target column replaced or with an additional column.</dataOut>
	</ports>	
</knimeNode>
