<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="polyRegLearner.png" type="Learner">
    <name>Polynomial Regression (Learner)</name>

    <shortDescription>Learner that builds a polynomial regression model from the input data</shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This node performs polynomial regression on the input data and computes the coefficients that minimize the
            squared error. The user must choose one column as target (dependent variable) and a number of independent variables. By
            default, polynomials with degree 2 are computed, which can be changed in the dialog.
            <br />
            If the optional PMML inport is connected and contains 
    		preprocessing operations in the TransformationDictionary those are 
    		added to the learned model.
        </intro>
        <tab name="Regression settings">
            <option name="Target column">The column that contains the dependent "target" variable.</option>
            <option name="Polynomial degree">The maximum degree the polynomial regression function should have.</option>
            <option name="Column Selection">Select the columns containing the independent variables and
                move them to the "include" list. </option>                
        </tab>
        <tab name="View settings">
            <option name="Number of data points to show in view">
                This option can be use to change the number of data points in
                the node view if e.g. there are too many points. The default
                value is 10,000 points.            
            </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort name="Training data" index="0">
            The input samples, which of the columns are used as independent variables can be configured in the dialog.
             The input must not contain missing values, you have to fix them by e.g. using the Missing Values node.
        </inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="PMML Preprocessing">Optional PMML port object containing preprocessing operations.</inPort>
        <outPort name="Data with training error" index="0">
            Training data classified with the learned model and the corresponding errors.
        </outPort>
        <outPort name="Regression Coefficients" index="1">
            The computed regression coefficients as a model for use in the Polynomial Regression Predictor.
        </outPort>
    </ports>

    <views>
        <view index="0" name="Learned Coefficients">Shows all learned coefficients all attributes.</view>
        <view index="1" name="Scatter Plot">
            Shows the data points and the regression function in one dimension.
        </view>
    </views>
</knimeNode>
