<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Manipulator" icon="./crosstable.png">
	<name>Crosstab</name>
	<shortDescription>Creates a cross-tabulation (also referred as
		contingency table or cross-tab).</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>Creates a cross table (also referred as 
			     <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contingency_table">
			     contingency table</a> or cross tab). It can be used to analyze
			    the relation of two columns with categorical data and does 
			    display the frequency distribution of the categorical variables
			    in a table.</p>
			<p>This node provides chi-square test statistics and, in case of a
				cross tabulation of 2x2 dimension, Fisher's exact test. Both
				statistics test the null hypothesis of no association between the
				row variable and the column variable. The p-values are provided in
				the view and in the second output port.</p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Row variable">
			The input column used as the row variable in the
			cross-tabulation. 
		</option>
		<option name="Column variable">
			The input column used as the column variable in
			the cross-tabulation. 
		</option>
		<option name="Weight column">
			Applies a numeric weight for each record in the
			input causing the Crosstab node to treat each record as if it were
			repeated WEIGHT number of times. 
        </option>
		<option name="Enable hiliting">
			If enabled, the hiliting of a cell in the crosstab will hilite all
			cells with same categories in attached views. Depending on the number
			of rows, enabling this feature might consume a lot of memory.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Input Table">
			Input table containing columns with
			categorical data.
        </inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Cross-Table">
			The cross table in list form.
		</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="Statistics Table">
			The table with the statistics.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
	<views>
		<view name="Cross tabulation" index="0">
			The following properties are displayed in the cross tabulation view:
			<br />
			<i>Frequency:</i> The cell frequency.
			<br />
			<i>Expected:</i> The expected frequency which is computed as 
			  (<i>column total</i> / <i>total</i>) * <i>row total</i>.
			<br />
			<i>Deviation:</i> The deviation is computed as
			  <i>Frequency</i> - <i>Expected</i>.
			<br />
			<i>Percent:</i> The percent is the relative frequency computed as
			  <i>Frequency</i> / <i>total</i>.
			<br />
			<i>Row Percent:</i> The row percent is computed as
			  <i>Frequency</i> / <i>row total</i>.
			<br />
			<i>Column Percent:</i> The column percent is computed as
			  <i>Frequency</i> / <i>column total</i>.
			<br />
			<i>Cell Chi-Square:</i> The contribution of this cell to the value
			of the Chi-Square statistic. The Cell Chi-Square sums up to the
			value of the Chi-Square statistic.
			<br />
			<br />
			For some properties the row totals and column totals are displayed
			beside the table and underneath the table, respectively.
			<br />
			You can control the size of the displayed table with the 
			<i>Max rows</i> and the <i>Max columns</i> controls.
			<br />
			<br />
			The statistics table provides chi-square test statistics and, in 
			case of a cross tabulation of 2x2 dimension, Fisher's exact test. 
			Both statistics test the null hypothesis of no association between 
			the row	variable and the column variable. You can reject the null 
			hypothesis when the p-value (Prop) is less than a significance value
			which is typically 0.01 or 0.05. In this case the result is said to
			be statistically significant. Please bear in mind that the 
			Chi-Square test	is based on	<a
				href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pearson%27s_chi-square_test#Assumptions">
				some assumptions</a>.

		</view>
	</views>
</knimeNode>


