<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 1.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd" >
<knimeNode icon="groupBy.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>GroupBy</name>
    <shortDescription>
    	Groups the table by the selected column(s) and aggregates the remaining
    	columns using the selected aggregation method.
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
    	<intro>
    		The node groups the row by the selected column(s). The remaining
    		rows are aggregated by the defined method. The user can choose an
    		aggregation method for all none numerical columns and an aggregation
    		method for all numerical columns. In order to save resources and
    		allow the handling of large tables the node sorts the input table
    		by the selected group columns prior calculating the aggregation 
    		values.
    		<p>
    		If the number of unique values per group exeeds the defined number 
    		of unique values the calculation of this group is skipped, the
    		aggregation result is a missing value and an appropriate warning 
    		is displayed after execution.
    		</p>
    		<p>
    		If the 'Sort in memory' option is checked the complete table is 
    		loaded into the memory to speed up the sorting process.
    		</p>
    		<p>
			 Aggregation methods available for none numerical and numerical 
			 columns:
    		<ul>
    			<li>First: Takes the first value per group.</li>
    			<li>Last: Takes the last value per group.</li>
    			<li>Mode: Takes the value with the most occurrences per group. 
    			If multiple values match this criterion one of these values is 
    			randomly chosen.</li>
    			<li>Count: Counts members per group.</li>
    		</ul>
			Aggregation methods only available for numerical columns:
			<ul>
    			<li>Minimum: Calculates the minimum per group.</li>
    			<li>Maximum: Calculates the maximum per group.</li>
    			<li>Mean: Calculates the mean per group.</li>
    			<li>Sum: Calculates the sum per group.</li>
    			<li>Variance: Calculates the variance per group.</li>
    		</ul>
    		</p>
    		<p>
	    		<b>All aggregation methods ignore missing values.</b>
    		</p>
    	</intro>    	
        <option name="None numerical aggregation method">
        	The aggregation method to use for none numerical columns. The
        	following methods can be applied: First, Last, Mode, Count
        </option>
        <option name="Numerical aggregation method">
        	The aggregation method to use for numerical columns. The
        	following methods can be applied: Minimum, Maximum, Mean, Sum, 
        	Variance, First, Last, Mode, Count
        </option>
        <option name="Maximum unique values per group">
	        Defines the maximum number of unique values per group to avoid 
	        memory exceptions. This option is only enabled if a memory 
	        consuming method like Mode is selected. All groups with more unique
	        values are skipped during calculation and the result is a 
	        missing value.
        </option>
        <option name="Move group column(s) to front">
			Moves the selected group column(s) to the front of the result table.
        </option>
        <option name="Sort in memory">
			Performs the necessary sorting in the memory. Speeds up the process
			but consumes much more memory.
        </option>
        <option name="Enable hiliting">
			If enabled the hiliting of a group row will hilite all rows of this
			group in other views. Builds a map with the group row keys and
			the related input table row keys.
        </option>
        <option name="Group by column(s)">
	        Select one or more column(s) to perform a grouping on.
		</option>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <dataIn index="0" name="Data table">
	        Input table with at least two columns to perform the grouping.
        </dataIn>
        <dataOut index="0" name="Pivoting table">
        	Result table with a row per unique group column value pair.
		</dataOut>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
