<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="groupBy.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.6" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.6 http://knime.org/node/v3.6.xsd">
    <name>GroupBy</name>
    <shortDescription>
    	Groups the table by the selected column(s) and aggregates the remaining
    	columns using the selected aggregation method.
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
    	<intro>
    	   <p>
    	    Groups the rows of a table by the unique values in the selected group columns.
    	    A row is created for each unique set of values of the selected group column. 
    	    The remaining columns are aggregated based on the specified aggregation settings.
            The output table contains one row for each unique value combination of the selected 
            group columns.
           </p>
           <p>
           The columns to aggregate can be either defined by selecting the columns directly, 
           by name based on a search pattern or based on the data type. Input columns are handled in
           this order and only considered once e.g. columns that are added directly on the
           "Manual Aggregation" tab are ignored even if their name matches a search pattern on the 
           "Pattern Based Aggregation" tab or their type matches a defined type on the
           "Type Based Aggregation" tab. The same holds for columns that are added based on a search pattern. 
           They are ignored even if they match a criterion that has been defined in the "Type Based Aggregation" tab.
           </p>
           <p>
            The "Manual Aggregation" tab allows you to change the aggregation method of more than one 
            column. In order to do so select the columns to change, open the context menu with a right mouse click
            and select the aggregation method to use.
           </p>
           <p>
            In the "Pattern Based Aggregation" tab you can assign aggregation methods to columns based on a  
            search pattern. The pattern can be either a string with wildcards or a
            <a href="http://www.java.sun.com/javase/6/docs/api/java/util/regex/Pattern.html#sum">regular expression</a>.
            Columns where the name matches the pattern but where the data type is not compatible with the
            selected aggregation method are ignored. Only columns that have not been selected as group column or 
            that have not been selected as aggregation column on the "Manual Aggregation" tab are considered.
           </p>
           <p>
            The "Type Based Aggregation" tab allows to select an aggregation method for all columns that are compatible 
            with the selected data type. For example to apply an operation on all numeric columns simply select DoubleCell.
            This will include all numeric cells that are compatible with DoubleCell such as IntCell and LongCell.
            Only columns that have not been handled by the other tabs e.g. group, column based and pattern based are considered.
            The data type list to choose from contains basic types e.g String, Double, etc. and all data types 
            the current input table contains.
           </p>
           <p>
            A detailed description of the available aggregation methods can be
            found on the 'Description' tab in the node dialog.
   		   </p>
    	</intro>
        <tab name="Groups">
        <option name="Group settings">
            Select one or more column(s) according to which the group(s) 
            is/are created.
        </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Advanced settings">
            <option name="Maximum unique values per group">
                Defines the maximum number of unique values per group to avoid 
                problems with memory overloading. All groups with more unique
                values are skipped during the calculation and a missing value is set 
                in the corresponding column, and a warning is displayed.
            </option>
            <option name="Column naming">
                The name of the resulting aggregation column(s) depends on the 
                selected naming schema.
                <ul>
                    <li>Keep original name(s):
                    Keeps the original column names.
                    Note that you can use all aggregation columns only once with 
                    this column naming option to prevent duplicate column names.
                    </li>
                    <li>Aggregation method (column name): 
                    Uses the aggregation method first and appends the column name
                    in brackets
                    </li>
                    <li>Column name (aggregation method):
                    Uses the column name first and appends the aggregation method
                    in brackets
                    </li>
                </ul>
                All aggregation methods get a * appended if the missing value option 
                is not ticked in the aggregation settings in order to distinguish
                between columns that considered missing values in the aggregation
                process and columns that do not.
            </option>
            <option name="Enable hiliting">
                If enabled, the hiliting of a group row will hilite all rows of this
                group in other views. Depending on the number of rows, enabling this 
                feature might consume a lot of memory.
            </option>
            <option name="Value delimiter">
                The value delimiter used by aggregation methods such as concatenate. 
            </option>
            <option name="Process in memory">
                Process the table in the memory. Requires more memory but is faster
                since the table needs not to be sorted prior aggregation. 
                The memory consumption depends on the number of unique groups and
                the chosen aggregation method. The row order of the input table is 
                automatically retained.
            </option>
            <option name="Retain row order">
                Retains the original row order of the input table. 
                Could result in longer execution time.
                The row order is automatically retained if the process in memory
                option is selected.
            </option> 
        </tab>
        <tab name="Manual Aggregation">
            <option name="Aggregation settings">
                Select one or more column(s) for aggregation from the available 
                columns list. Change the aggregation method in the Aggregation 
                column of the table. You can add the same column multiple
                times. In order to change the aggregation method of more than one 
                column select all columns to change, open the context menu with a 
                right mouse click and select the aggregation method to use.
            </option>
            <option name="Missing">
                Missing values are considered during aggregation if the missing 
                option is ticked for the corresponding row in the column 
                aggregation table.
                Some aggregation methods do not support the changing of the missing
                option such as means.
            </option>
            <option name="Parameter">
                The parameter column shows an "Edit" button for all 
                aggregation operators that require additional information. 
                Clicking on the "Edit" button opens the parameter dialog 
                which allows changing the operator specific settings.
            </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Pattern Based Aggregation">
            <option name="Aggregation settings">
                Use the "Add" button to add a new row with a search pattern to the aggregation settings.
                The search pattern can either be a string with wildcards or a 
                <a href="http://www.java.sun.com/javase/6/docs/api/java/util/regex/Pattern.html#sum">regular expression</a>.
                Supported wildcards are * (matches any number of characters) and ? (matches one character) e.g. KNI*
                would match all strings that start with KNI such as KNIME whereas KNI? would match only strings that start
                with KNI followed by a fourth character. 
                Double click the "Search pattern" cell to edit the pattern. 
                The cell is colored in red if the pattern is invalid.
            </option>
            <option name="RegEx">Tick this option if the search pattern is a regular expression otherwise
            it is treated as string with wildcards ('*' and '?').</option>
            <option name="Missing">
                Missing values are considered during aggregation if the missing 
                option is ticked for the corresponding row in the column 
                aggregation table.
                Some aggregation methods do not support the changing of the missing
                option such as means.
            </option>
            <option name="Parameter">
                The parameter column shows an "Edit" button for all 
                aggregation operators that require additional information. 
                Clicking on the "Edit" button opens the parameter dialog 
                which allows changing the operator specific settings.
            </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Type Based Aggregation">
            <option name="Aggregation Settings">
                Select one or more data type from the available type list. 
                Change the aggregation method in the Aggregation 
                column of the table. You can add the same data type multiple
                times. The list contains standard types e.g. Double, String etc. and all types of the input table.
            </option>
            <option name="Missing">
                Missing values are considered during aggregation if the missing 
                option is ticked for the corresponding row in the column 
                aggregation table.
                Some aggregation methods do not support the changing of the missing
                option such as means.
            </option>
            <option name="Parameter">
                The parameter column shows an "Edit" button for all 
                aggregation operators that require additional information. 
                Clicking on the "Edit" button opens the parameter dialog 
                which allows changing the operator specific settings.
            </option>
        </tab>
		<link href="https://www.knime.com/knime-introductory-course/chapter3/section2/classic-aggregations-with-groupby-node">
			KNIME E-Learning Course: Classic Aggregations with GroupBy node
		</link>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Data table">
	        The input table to group.
        </inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Group table">
        	Result table with one row for each existing value combination of 
        	the selected columns.
		</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
