<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Manipulator" icon="date_time_difference.png">
	<name>Date&amp;Time Difference</name>
	<shortDescription>Calculates differences between two date&amp;time
		cells.</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			Calculates differences between two date&amp;time cells and appends a new column. The output can be either a
			duration or a selected granularity (years, months, weeks, days, hours, minutes,	seconds, millis, nanos). It
			can be configured to use as second date&amp;time either a second column, the execution date&amp;time, a
			selected fixed date&amp;time or the date&amp;time contained in the previous row.
		</intro>
		<tab name="Base column">
			<option name="Column Selector">
				The first date&amp;time column can be chosen.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Calculate difference to">
			<option name="second column">
				Calculates the difference between the chosen second column and the first column. The first column will
				be subtracted from the second column (<i>second column - first column</i>).
			</option>
			<option name="execution date&amp;time">
				Calculates the difference between the execution date&amp;time and the chosen first column. The first
				column will be subtracted from the execution date&amp;time (<i>execution date&amp;time - first column</i>).
			</option>
			<option name="fixed date&amp;time">
				Calculates the difference between the chosen fixed date&amp;time and the chosen first column. The first
				column will be subtracted from the fixed date&amp;time (<i>fixed date&amp;time - first column</i>).
			</option>
			<option name="previous row">
				Calculates the difference between the date&amp;time in row <i>n</i> and row <i>n-1</i> in the chosen
				column. The <i>n-1</i>th row will be subtracted from the <i>n</i>th row ( <i>n</i>th row - <i>n-1</i>th
				row ).
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Output options">
			<option name="Granularity">
				Calculates the difference and outputs it in the chosen granularity (years, months, weeks, days, hours,
				minutes, seconds, millis, or nanos).
			</option>
			<option name="Duration">
				Calculates the difference and outputs it as duration or period. If the difference between two dates is
				calculated, a period column will be the output, otherwise a duration column. This implies that if the
				difference between local or zoned date&amp;time columns is calculated, differences of years, months,
				or days will be converted to hours.
			</option>
			<option name="New column name">
				The name for the new column can be chosen.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Input table">
			Input table.
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Output table">
			Output table containing an appended column with the calculated differences.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>