<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./scatter.gif" type="Visualizer" deprecated="true">
	<name>Scatterplot (deprecated)</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
        This node is obsolete! Please use the new Scatter Plotter located 
        in the Data Views category.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>		
		        <p>
        This node is obsolete! Please use the new Scatter Plotter located in 
	    the Data Views category.</p>
		
	    <p>Creates a scatterplot of two selectable attributes.
		</p>
		<p>It is possible to open the view multiple times and to select two
		arbitrary columns. Nominal values are jittered if more than one dot
		is rendered on the same value.
		</p>
		<p>By default the mouse pointer is in selection mode. This means by dragging
		or clicking (holding Ctrl for multiple selection) the dots can be marked.
		The selected dots can be hilited or unhilited via the pop-up or 
		drop-down menu.
		</p>
		<p>Clicking the zoom button (the button stays down) activates the
		zoom mode (the mouse pointer changes). In zoom mode - similar to selection
		mode - it is possible to drag a rectangle. After releasing the mouse 
		button, the selected part of the plot is enlarged 
		to fit into the visible area. The rest of the plot is accessible via the 
		scroll bars. Once the zoom has been performed, 
		mouse mode reverts to selection mode.
		</p>
		<p>For large data tables the number of displayed rows can be 
		set in the node's dialog. By default, only the first one thousand
		data rows are displayed.
		</p>
		<p> The "More settings..." dialog enables you to make changes to the 
		coordinate axis range and dot size.
		</p>
		</intro>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<dataIn index="0" name="Display data">Datatable with data to display</dataIn>
	</ports>	
	<views>
		<view index="0" name="Scatterplot">
			The scatterplot displaying the data.
		</view>
	</views>
</knimeNode>