<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Manipulator" icon="correlation_filter.png">
	<name>Correlation Filter</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Filters out correlated columns.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
	 	<p>
	 		This node uses the model as generated by a <i>Correlation</i> node 
	 		to determine which columns are redundant (i.e. correlated) and 
	 		filters them out. The output table will contain the reduced set
	 		of columns. 
	 	</p>
	 	<p>
	 		The filtering step works roughly as follows: For each column in 
	 		the correlation model the count of correlated columns is determined  
	 		given a threshold value for the correlation coefficient 
	 		(specified in the dialog). The column with the most correlated 
	 		columns is chosen to &quot;survive&quot; and all correlated columns
	 		are filtered out. This procedure is repeated until no more columns
	 		can be identified. The problem of finding a minimum set of columns
	 		to satisfy the constraints is difficult to solve analytically. 
	 		This method applied here is known to be good approximation, however.
	 	</p>
		</intro>
		
		<option name="Columns from Model">
			Displays the set of columns for which the model has information. 
			These columns must also be present in the input data table. 
			The (automatically) selected elements in the list will be present
			in the output table. This list can not be edited.
		</option>
		<option name="Correlation Threshold">
			Choose the correlation threshold here. The higher the value the 
			fewer columns get filtered out. Hit Enter or click the 
			&quot;Calculate&quot; to see a preview of the filtered columns. The
			counts of included vs. excluded columns are shown in the label.
		</option>
		<option name="Calculate">
			Click this button to update the statistics. It will determine the 
			reduced set of columns using the procedure outlined above.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<inPort name="Correlation Model" index="0">
			The model from the correlation node.</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="Input data">Numeric input data to filter. 
			It must contain the set of columns that were used to create 
			the correlation model. (Typically you connect the input data from the 
			correlation node here.)</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Filtered data from input">
			Filtered data from input.</outPort>
	</ports>
	
</knimeNode>