<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./cell_replace.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Cell Replacer</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Replaces cells in a column according to dictionary table (2nd input).
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
			<p>Replaces cells in a column according to dictionary table
			(2nd input). The node has two inputs: The first input contains a
			target column whose values are to be replaced using the dictionary 
			table (2nd input). From the dictionary table, choose one column 
			(or the rowID column) that is used as lookup criterion. Any 
			occurrence in the target column (1st input) that matches the lookup
			value is replaced by the corresponding value of the output column,
			which is another column in the dictionary table.
			</p>
			
			<p>Missing values are treated as ordinary values, that is, they are
			valid as lookup and replacement value. If there are duplicates in 
			the	lookup column in the dictionary table, the last occurrence 
			(bottom most row) defines the replacement pair.
			</p>
			
			<p>If the input/lookup column is a collection type, each of the 
			contained values in the collection is a search element.
			</p>
		</intro>
        
        
        <option name="Input table, Target column">The column in the first input
            table whose values will be replaced.</option>
        <option name="Dictionary table, Input (Lookup)">Search column in the 
            second input table.</option>
        <option name="Dictionary table, Output (Replacement)">Column in the  
            second input table containing the replacement values.</option>
        <option name="If no element matches, use:">Define how values in the 
            input table, which do not match any search pattern, are treated. 
            "Input" will leave the value unmodified, "Missing" replaces the 
            value by a missing value.</option>
        <option name="Append/Replace Result Column">Select the checkbox and 
            enter a new column name that will contain the mapped output. 
            If unselected, the result will replace the target column.</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input Table">Table containing column whose 
            values are to be replaced.
        </inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Dictionary Table">Dictionary table containing 
            two columns: one lookup column and one replacement column.
        </inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Table with replaced column">
            Input table with replaced target column.
         </outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
