<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./many2one.png" type="Manipulator" deprecated="true">
    <name>Many2One (PMML)</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Transforms the values of multiple columns into a single column while generating PMML. 
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        Transforms the values of multiple columns into a single column
        depending on the include method and documents the transformation in PMML. 
        If set to binary the condensed
        column's value is set to the name of the first column with value 1.
        If the include method is maximum or minimum the value of the
        condensed column is set to the name of the column which, of all
        included columns, has the largest or smallest value. If the include
        method is binary and all columns are 0 the condensed column will
        contain a missing value.
        </intro>
            <option name="Columns">
                The columns to be condensed into a single column using
                the selected include method.
            </option>
            <option name="Condensed column name">
                The name of the appended column.
            </option>
            <option name="Include method">
                The method to condense multiple columns into one.<br/>
                Binary: Name of first column with value 1<br/>
                Maximum: Name of column with the largest value<br/>
                Minimum: Name of column with the smallest value<br/>
                RegExPattern: Name of first column that matches the given pattern (currently not supported in PMML,
                uses option Binary within the generated PMML document)
            </option>
            <option name="Include pattern">
                When include method is RegExPattern, this is the pattern used.
            </option>
            <option name="Keep original columns">
                Determines whether the included columns are kept or not.
            </option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Data to process">Data</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="PMML Document">PMML</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Processed data">Data with transformed columns</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Created PMML">Transformed PMML input</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
