<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./joiner.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Joiner</name>
    <shortDescription>Joins two tables</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This node joins two tables in a database-like way. The join is based 
            on the joining columns of both tables.
        </intro>
        <option name="Join mode">
            If a row from the left table cannot be joined with a row from the right table (and vice versa) there are
            several options of handling this situation. After an
            <b>Inner Join</b>
            only matching rows will show up in the output table. A
            <b>Left Outer Join</b>
            will fill up the columns that come from the right table with missing values if no matching row exists in
            the right table. Likewise, a
            <b>Right Outer Join</b>
            will fill up the columns from the left table with missing values if no matching row in the left table
            exists. A
            <b>Full Outer Join</b>
            will fill up columns from both the left and right table with missing values if a row cannot be joined.
        </option>        
        <option name="Joining columns">
            Select the columns from the left input table and the right input 
            table that should be used for joining. You may selected a real
            column or the table's row ID here. You must make sure, that the type 
            of selected columns matches. The row IDs are interpreted as 
            StringCells.
            <br/>
            <b>Match all of the following:</b> 
            A row of the left input table and a row of the right input table 
            match if they match in all specified column pairs.
            <br/>
            <b>Match any of the following:</b>
            A row of the left input table and a row of the right input table 
            match if they match in at least one specified column pairs.            
        </option>
        <option name="Performance Tuning">
            <b>Maximum number of open files:</b> The maximum number of opened
            temporary files. Increase it for better performance.
            <b>Enable hiliting:</b> Select, if hiliting is enabled between 
            input and output data. Disable, for reducing memory consumption.
        </option>
        <option name="Row ID separator in joined table">
            The row IDs of the joined table are a concatenation of the row ID
            of the left input table, this separator and the row ID of the right
            input table.
        </option>
        <option name="Column Selection (Left Table and Right Table)">
            <br/>
            <b>Exclude:</b> This list contains the column names of the input table that are 
            excluded.
            <br/>
            <b>Select:</b> Use these buttons to move columns between the Include and Exclude 
            list.
            <br/>
            <b>Include:</b> This list contains the column names that are included.
            <br/>
            <b>Search:</b> Use one of these fields to search either within the Include
            or Exclude list for certain column names or name substrings.
            Repeated clicking of the search button marks the next column that 
            matches the search text. The check box 'Select all search hits' causes
            all matching columns to be selected making them movable between
            the two lists.
            <br/>
            <b>Always include all columns:</b> If set, all columns are moved to
            the include list and if input changes all new columns will be in the 
            include list, too.
        </option>        
        <option name="Duplicate column handling">
            The option allows you to change the behaviour if the include
            lists of both input tables contain columns with the same name. 
            <br/>
            <b>Filter duplicates:</b> Only the columns from the left input table
            will show up in the output table.
            <br/>
            <b>Don't execute:</b> Don't allow to execute this node if there are
            duplicate column names in the include lists. 
            <br/>
            <b>Append suffix:</b> Append a suffix to the duplicate column names
            from the right input table so that they also show up in the output
            table.
        </option>
        <option name="Joining columns handling">
            The option allows to filer the left/right joining columns, i.e. the
            joining columns defined in the Joiner Settings tab will not show up
            in the output table.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Left table">Table contributing to the left part of the output table</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Right table">Table contributing to the right part of the output table</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Joined table">Joined Table</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
