<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./mds.png" type="Learner">
	<name>MDS</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
		Multi dimensional scaling node, mapping data of a high dimensional 
		space onto a lower dimensional space by applying the Sammons mapping.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
	<intro>
	   This node maps data of a high dimensional space onto a lower (usually
	   2 or 3) dimensional space. Therefore the Sammons mapping is applied,
	   which iteratively decreases the difference of the distances of high and 
	   low dimensional data. Each original data point is represented by
	   a data point of a lower dimension. The Sammons mapping tries to keep
	   the distance information of the high dimensional data by adjusting
	   the low dimensional data points in a certain way. Each low dimensional
	   data point is moved around a bit towards or back from the other points
	   accordant to its high dimensional distances. This procedure is repeated
	   a specified number of epochs or iterations respectively.
	</intro>
	
	<option name="Number of rows to use">
	   Specifies the number of rows to apply the MDS on.
	</option>
    <option name="Output dimension">
        Specifies the dimension of the mapped output data.
    </option>	
    <option name="Epochs">
        Specifies the number of epochs to train.
    </option>
    <option name="Learn rate">	   
        Specifies the learning rate to use. The learning rate
        is decreased automatically over the trained epochs.
	</option>
	<option name="Random seed">
	   Specifies the random seed to use, which allows to reproduce a mapping 
	   even if the initialization is done randomly.
	</option>
	<option name="Distance metric">
		The distance metric to use Euclidean or Manhattan. 
		The Euclidean distance metric is used by default.
	</option>
	<option name="Input data">
	   Specifies the columns to use by the mapping.
	</option>
	</fullDescription>
		
	<ports>
		<dataIn name="Any input table" index="0">
			Data table containing the data to map.
		</dataIn>
		<dataOut name="The input data and the mapped data" index="0">
			The input data and the mapped data.
		</dataOut>
	</ports>	
</knimeNode>

