<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./fixedColumnHistogram.gif" type="Visualizer">
	<name>Histogram</name>	
	<shortDescription>
		Displays data in a histogram view. Hiliting is not supported.
	</shortDescription>	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
		<p>Displays a histogram view with different viewing options.</p>
		<p>The user can change the following view properties on the fly:
			<ol>
			<li>Aggregation method (count, summary, average)</li>
			<li>Bar size</li>
			<li>Show empty intervals</li>
			<li>Show missing value bar</li>
			<li>Layout</li>
			<li>Zooming</li>
			<li>...</li>
			</ol>
			The bars are colored in proportion to the aggregation value.
			Hiliting is not supported.
		</p>
		<p>All automatically created bins, except the first one, are
		left open intervals (a,b] where a is excluded and b is included in 
		the interval. To cover all values the first interval is a closed 
		interval [a,b] where a and b are included. In order to provide nicer bin 
        intervals the left border is set to 0 if possible.</p>
		<p>This view is particularly well suited for extremely large datasets.
		For more interaction and hiliting support use the 
		"Interactive Histogram" node.</p>
		<p><b>Only columns with a valid domain are available in this view.
		To set the domain use the DomainCalculator or ColumnFilter node!</b></p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Display all rows">
		    If selected the histogram view displays all rows of the incoming data.
	    </option>
	    <option name="No. of rows to display">
		    Defines the number of rows to be displayed in the histogram.
		    This option is disabled if the 'Display all rows' option is selected.
	    </option>
	    <option name="Binning column">
	     	This is the column to be shown on the x axis of the histogram view.
	     	For numerical values the number of bars can be adjusted later 
	     	in the 'Bar settings' section of view properties.
   	    </option>
   	  	<option name="Aggregation column">
   	  		This is the column to be used as the bar value and displayed on the
   	  		y axis. Only numerical values with a valid domain are allowed. 
   	  		The aggregation method can be adjusted later in the 
   	  		'Aggregation setting' section of view properties .
   	    </option>
   	  	<option name="Number of bins">
   	  		The number of bins to create for a numerical x axis column.
   	  		If the selected x column is nominal this value is ignored.
   	    </option>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<dataIn index="0" name="Data in port">
			The data table to be displayed.
		</dataIn>
	</ports>	
	<views>
		<view index="0" name="Histogram View">
			Displays the data in a histogram view.
		</view>
	</views>
</knimeNode>