<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 1.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./fixedColumnHistogram.gif" type="Visualizer">
	<name>Histogram</name>	
	<shortDescription>
		Displays data in a histogram view.
	</shortDescription>	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
		<p>Displays an histogram view with different viewing options.</p>
		<p>The user can change the following properties on the fly in the 
		view properties:
			<ol>
			<li>Aggregation method (count, summary, average)</li>
			<li>Number of bins for numerical attributes (incl. empty bars, 
			excl. missing value bar)</li>
			<li>The width of the bars</li>
			<li>Show empty intervals</li>
			<li>Show missing value bar</li>
			<li>Zooming</li>
			<li>...</li>
			</ol>
		The bars are colored by the number of rows per color attribute.
		</p>
		<p>All automatically created bins, with exception to the first one, are
		left opened intervals (a,b] where a is excluded and b is included in 
		the interval. To cover all values the first interval is a closed 
		interval [a,b] where a and b are included.</p>
		<p>To allow the work with huge data sets the user has to specify the 
		desired x and aggregation column before opening the view. For more 
		interaction use the "Interactive Histogram" node.</p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Display all rows">
		    If selected the histogram view displays all rows of the incoming data.
	    </option>
	    <option name="No. of rows to display: ">
		    Defines the number of rows which are displayed in the histogram view.
		    This option is disabled if the 'Display all rows' option is selected.
	    </option>
	    <option name="X column: ">
	     	The column which should be shown on the x axis of the histogram view.
	     	For numerical values the number of bars could be adjusted later 
	     	in the view properties in the 'Bar settings' section.
   	    </option>
   	  	<option name="Aggregation column: ">
   	  		The column which should be used as bar value and displayed on the
   	  		y axis. Only numerical values are allowed. The aggregation method
   	  		could be adjusted later in the view properties in the 'Aggregation setting'
   	  		section.
   	    </option>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<dataIn index="0" name="Data in port">
			The data table that should be displayed.
		</dataIn>
	</ports>	
	<views>
		<view index="0" name="Histogram View">
			Displays the data in a histogram view.
		</view>
	</views>
</knimeNode>