<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./interactiveHistogram.gif" type="Visualizer">
	<name>Histogram (interactive)</name>	
	<shortDescription>
		Displays data in an interactive histogram view with hiliting support.
	</shortDescription>	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
		<p>Displays an interactive histogram view with different viewing 
		options.The interactive histogram supports hiliting and the changing 
        of the x axis and aggregation column on the fly.</p>
		<p>The user can change the following view properties on the fly:
			<ol>
			<li>X axis</li>
			<li>Aggregation column (Y axis)</li>
			<li>Aggregation method (count, summary, average)</li>
			<li>Number of bins for numerical attributes (incl. empty bars, excl. 
			missing value )</li>
			<li>Bar size</li>
			<li>Show empty intervals</li>
			<li>Show missing value bar</li>
			<li>Layout</li>			
			<li>Zooming</li>
			<li>...</li>
			</ol>
			The bars are colored in proportion to the aggregation value.
			Hiliting is supported.
		</p>
		<p>All automatically created bins, with exception to the first one, are
		left open intervals (a,b] where a is excluded and b is included in 
		the interval. To cover all values the first interval is a closed 
		interval [a,b] where a and b are included. In order to provide nicer bin 
        intervals the left border is set to 0 if possible.</p>
		<p><b>Please note: This node caches all data in the main memory to 
		provide interactive functions. If you plan to visualize extremely large 
		datasets the non interactive "Histogram" node may be better suited.</b>
		</p>
		<p><b>Only columns with a valid domain are available in this view.
		To set the domain use the DomainCalculator or ColumnFilter node!</b></p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Display all rows">
		    If selected the histogram view displays all rows of the incoming data.
	    </option>
	    <option name="No. of rows to display: ">
		    Defines the number of rows to be displayed in the histogram.
		    This option is disabled if the 'Display all rows' option is selected.
	    </option>
	    <option name="Binning column: ">
	     	This is the column to be shown on the x axis of the histogram view.
	     	For numerical values the number of bars can be adjusted later 
	     	in the 'Bar settings' section of view properties.
   	    </option>
   	    <option name="Aggregation column">
            This is the column to be used as the bar value and displayed on the
            y axis. Only numerical values with a valid domain are allowed. 
            The aggregation method can be adjusted later in the 
            'Aggregation setting' section of view properties .
        </option>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<dataIn index="0" name="Data in port">
			The data table to be displayed.
		</dataIn>
	</ports>	
	<views>
		<view index="0" name="Interactive Histogram View">
			Displays the data in an interactive histogram view.
		</view>
	</views>
</knimeNode>