<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 1.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Source" icon="./filereader.ico">
	<name>File Reader</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
	    Flexible reader for ASCII files.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>		
		This node can be used to read data from an ASCII file or URL location.
		It can be configured to read in various formats.<br />
		When you open the node's configuration dialog and provide a filename, 
		it will try to guess
		the reader's settings by analyzing the beginning of the file.
		Check the results of these settings in the preview table. If the 
		data shown is not correct or an error is reported, you can adjust the
		settings manually (see below).<br />
		When the node is executed it reads in the entire file and caches it in a
		temporary file for faster access by the connected successor nodes. It 
		also stores all possibles values it came accross for each column.
		</intro>
		
		<option name="ASCII file location">Enter a valid file name or URL. When
			you press ENTER, the file is analyzed and the settings pre-set.
			You can also choose a previously read file from the drop-down list,
			or select a file from the "Browse..." dialog.
			</option>		
		<option name="Read row headers">If checked, the first column in the file
			is used as row IDs. If not checked, default row headers are
			created.</option>
		<option name="Read column headers">If checked, the items in the first 
			line of the file are used as column names. 
			Otherwise default column names are created.</option>
	    <option name="Column delimiter">Enter the character(s) that separate
	    	the data tokens in the file, or select a delimiter from the list.
			</option>
	    <option name="Ignore spaces and tabs">If checked, spaces and the TAB
		    characters are ignored (not in quoted strings though).
		    </option>
	    <option name="Java style comment">Everything between '/*' and '*/' is
	    	ignored. Also everything after '//' until the end of the line.
			</option>
	    <option name="Single line comment">Enter one or more characters that
	    	will indicate the start of a comment (ended by a new line).
			</option>
	    <option name="Advanced...">Opens a new dialog with advanced settings.
	    	At the current time, there is more advanced support for quotes and for the
	    	decimal separator in floating point numbers.	    
			</option>
	    <option name="Click on the table header">If the column header in the 
	    	preview table is clicked, a new dialog 
	    	opens where column properties can be set: name 
	    	and type can be changed (and will be fixed then).
	     	A pattern can be entered that will cause a "missing
	        cell" to be created when it's read for this column.
		    </option>	      	
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<dataOut index="0" name="File Table">Datatable just read from the file</dataOut>
	</ports>	
</knimeNode>