<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Source" icon="./filereader.ico">
	<name>Variable Based File Reader</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
	    ASCII file reader from variable locations
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>		
		This node can be used to read data from an ASCII file or URL location.
		The location is read from a scope variable, provided by the input port.
		It can be configured to read in various formats.<br />
		When you open the node's configuration dialog and provide a variable name
		that contains a valid file location, it tries to guess
		the reader's settings by analyzing the content of the file.
		Check the results of these settings in the preview table. If the 
		data shown is not correct or an error is reported, you can adjust the
		settings manually (see below).<br />
		In order for the available variables to have values assigned to them, the
		predecessor node should be executed before the settings are adjusted.<br />
		In most cases a node will be connected to the port that assigns 
		different values to variables in a loop.
		<p />
		If a big file is selected (or the analysis of the file takes longer) the
		dialog shows a &quot;Start Analysis&quot; button. The analysis is then
		not triggered every time you change one setting, but only when you 
		click this button. You can also cut the analysis short by clicking
		the &quot;Stop Analysis&quot; button. Then the analyzer doesn't examine
		the entire file to check the column types but stops after determining
		the types. Execution of the node could then fail, if an incompatible
		data item occurs in the data file.<br />
		It is recommended to trigger file analysis before applying the dialog
		settings to the node. If you click OK (or Apply) and didn't analyze the 
		data file before, an analysis is launched that can't be canceled and
		that will examine the entire file. Make sure a preview table is visible
		before you apply the settings.     
		</intro>
		
		<option name="Location variable name">Select the name of the variable that
		    holds the location of the file. When
			you press ENTER, the file is analyzed and the settings pre-set.
			</option>		
		<option name="Preserve user settings"> If checked, the checkmarks and
		    column names/types you explictly entered are preserved even if 
		    you select a new file. By default, the analyzer starts with fresh
		    default settings for each new file location.
		    </option>
		<option name="Read row IDs">If checked, the first column in the file
			is used as row IDs. If not checked, default row headers are
			created.</option>
		<option name="Read column headers">If checked, the items in the first 
			line of the file are used as column names. 
			Otherwise default column names are created.</option>
	    <option name="Column delimiter">Enter the character(s) that separate
	    	the data tokens in the file, or select a delimiter from the list.
			</option>
	    <option name="Ignore spaces and tabs">If checked, spaces and the TAB
		    characters are ignored (not in quoted strings though).
		    </option>
	    <option name="Java style comment">Everything between '/*' and '*/' is
	    	ignored. Also everything after '//' until the end of the line.
			</option>
	    <option name="Single line comment">Enter one or more characters that
	    	will indicate the start of a comment (ended by a new line).
			</option>
	    <option name="Advanced...">Opens a new dialog with advanced settings.
	    	There is support for quotes, different decimal separators in 
	    	floating point numbers, and character encoding. Also, for 
	    	ignoring whitespaces, for allowing rows with too few data items, 
	    	for making row IDs unique (not recommended for huge files), 
	    	for missing value pattern,
	    	and for limiting the number	of rows read in.	    
			</option>
	    <option name="Click on the table header">If the column header in the 
	    	preview table is clicked, a new dialog 
	    	opens where column properties can be set: name 
	    	and type can be changed (and will be fixed then).
	     	A pattern can be entered that will cause a "missing
	        cell" to be created when it's read for this column. Additionally,
	        possible values of the column domain can be updated by selecting
	        "Domain". And, you can choose to skip this column entirely, i.e. it
	        will not be included in the output table then.
		    </option>	      	
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<dataOut index="0" name="File Table">Datatable just read from the file</dataOut>
	</ports>	
</knimeNode>