<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="doublerounding.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Round Double</name>
    <shortDescription>Rounds double values to the specified decimal place.
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        <p>
			Rounds double values to the specified decimal place or significant 
			figures, applying the specified rounding method. The columns 
			containing the double values can be specified. The rounded values 
			can be appended as additional columns, or the old values are 
			replaced by the rounded values. If rounded values are appended as 
			additional columns, a column suffix for the columns to append needs 
			to be specified.<br />
			To round the values seven different rounding modes are available:
			UP, DOWN, CEILING, FLOOR, HALF_UP, HALF_DOWN, HALF_EVEN. For the
            detailed description of each rounding mode please see the			
			<a href="http://docs.oracle.com/javase/6/docs/api/index.html?java/math/RoundingMode.html">Java documentation</a>.		
		</p>
		<p>
		  The output formatting can be of different types, which are described by example below. Rounding the 
		  numbers 1.23501, 0.00000035239 and -3.123103E9 to 3 significant digits (HALF_UP) will produce:
		</p>
		<table>
		  <tr>
		    <th>Input</th>         <th>Double(*)</th>           <th>Standard String</th>    <th>Plain String (no exponent)</th>     <th>Engineering String</th>
	      </tr>
		  <tr>
			<td>1.23501</td>       <td>1.24</td>             <td>"1.24"</td>             <td>"1.24"</td>                         <td>"1.24"</td>
		  </tr>
		  <tr>
			<td>0.00000035239</td> <td>0.000000352</td>      <td>"3.52E-7"</td>          <td>"0.000000352"</td>                  <td>"352E-9"</td>
          </tr>
		  <tr>
			<td>-3123103001</td>   <td>-3120000000</td>      <td>"-3.12E+9"</td>         <td>"-3120000000"</td>                  <td>"-3.12E+9"</td>
          </tr>
		</table>
		<p>(*)Note that the "Double" output option may yield unexpected results due to numerical precision issue when representing floating point numbers. 
		For example a number such as 0.1 can sometimes be represented as 0.09999999999999999.</p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Column selection">
			The columns containing double values to round.
		</option>
        <option name="Append as new columns (specify suffix)">
            If checked the rounded values will be appended as additional 
            columns. For each selected column one additional column containing
            the rounded values will be appended. If not checked, the input 
            double values will be replaced by the rounded values. The names of the 
            new columns are those of the original columns with the specified suffix 
            appended.
        </option>
        <option name="Output format">
            Specify the output format here. See table above. 
        </option>        
        <option name="Precision">
            The scale of the double values to round to. If the scale is reduced
            the specified rounding mode is applied.
        </option>
        <option name="Precision mode">
            The type of precision to which the values are rounded. Decimal 
            places, the default option rounds to the specified decimal places,
            whereas significant figures rounds to significant figures or 
            numbers. 
        </option>
        <option name="Rounding mode">
            The rounding mode which is applied when double values are rounded.
            The rounding mode specifies the rounding behavior. Seven different
            rounding modes are available:<br />
            <ul>
            <li>UP: Rounding mode to round away from zero.</li> 
            <li>DOWN: Rounding mode to round towards zero.</li>
            <li>CEILING: Rounding mode to round towards positive infinity.</li>
            <li>FLOOR: Rounding mode to round towards negative infinity.</li>
            <li>HALF_UP: Rounding mode to round towards "nearest neighbor" unless both neighbors are equidistant, in which case round up.</li>
            <li>HALF_DOWN: Rounding mode to round towards "nearest neighbor" unless both neighbors are equidistant, in which case round down.</li>
            <li>HALF_EVEN: Rounding mode to round towards the "nearest neighbor" unless both neighbors are equidistant, in which case, round towards the even neighbor.</li>
            </ul>
            For a detailed description of each rounding mode please see the           
            <a href="http://docs.oracle.com/javase/6/docs/api/index.html?java/math/RoundingMode.html">Java documentation</a>.
        </option>
	</fullDescription>
		
	<ports>
        <inPort name="Table containing double values" index="0">
            The input table containing double values to convert.
        </inPort>
        <outPort name="Table containing rounded double values" index="0">
        	The output table containing the rounded double values.
        </outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>