<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd" >
<knimeNode icon="pivot.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Pivoting</name>
    <shortDescription>Node computes an aggregation value between all 
        co-occurrences of two column, pivot and group column. The aggregation 
        can be based on a third numeric column, or just the number of 
        occurrences.
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
    	<intro>The node counts the co-occurrences of all value pairs between 
    	the group and pivot column. If an aggregation 
    	column is selected, the value between the co-occurrences is 
    	computed based on the selected aggregation method. In the resulting 
    	pivot table, the possible values of the group column appear as row IDs
    	and the values of the pivot column as column names. The value in each 
    	cell of the table is the aggregation value, either the number of
    	occurrences or the computed aggregation value.
    	</intro>
        <option name="Pivot column">Select a column to find all co-occurrences
        among the values of the group column. The values of this column define
        the column header.
        </option>
        <option name="Group column">Select a column to perform a grouping on.
		The column values are then used as row IDs.
		</option>
		<option name="Enable aggregation">If selected, the aggregation is 
		performed based on one selected numeric column to which the selected 
		aggregation method is applied.
        </option>
        <option name="Aggregation column">Select a numeric column used to 
        aggregate all occurrences of the pivot values within one group.
        </option>
        <option name="Aggregation method">
        If no aggregation column has been selected, simply the numbers of
        co-occurrences are counted between the group and pivot column. The 
        following methods can be applied to the aggregation column: SUM, MEAN,
        MIN, MAX, VARIANCE, and STD DEVIATION.
        </option>
        <option name="Enable hiliting">
        Select, if hiliting is enabled between input and output data.
        </option>
        <option name="Ignore missing values">
        Ignore rows containing missing values in pivot column.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Data table">Input table with at least two 
        columns used to group against the pivot column. In addition, an 
        aggregation column can be applied.
        </inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Pivoting table">Pivoting table with aggregated 
            values of co-occurrences between pivot and group column.
		</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
