<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd" >
<knimeNode icon="pivot.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Pivoting</name>
    <shortDescription>
    	Pivots and groups the input table by the selected columns for pivoting 
    	and	grouping; enhanced by column aggregations.
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
    	<intro>
    	   <p>
        	Performs a pivoting on the given input table using a selected number
        	of columns for grouping and pivoting. The group columns will result
        	into unique rows, whereby the pivot values turned into 
        	columns for each set of column combinations together with each 
        	aggregation method. In addition, the node returns the total 
        	aggregation (a) based on only the group columns and (b) based on
        	only the pivoted columns resulting in a single row; optionally, 
        	with the total aggregation without pivoting.
           </p>
           <p>
            To change the aggregation method of more than one column select all
            columns to change, open the context menu with a right mouse click
            and select the aggregation method to use.
           </p>
           <p>
            A detailed description of the available aggregation methods can be
            found on the 'Description' tab in the node dialog.
   		   </p>
            <p>
            If the 'Sort in memory' option is checked the complete table is 
            loaded into the memory to speed up the sorting process.
            </p>
    	</intro>
    	<tab name="Group settings">
          <option name="Group columns">
            Select one or more columns according to which the group rows 
            are created.
          </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Pivot settings">
          <option name="Pivot columns">
            Select one or more columns according to which the pivot columns 
            are created.
          </option>
          <option name="Ignore missing values">
            Ignore rows containing missing values in pivot column.
          </option>
          <option name="Append overall totals">
            Appends the overall pivot totals with each aggregation performed 
            together on all selected pivot columns.
          </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Aggregation settings">
          <option name="Aggregation methods">
            Select one or more columns for aggregation from the available 
            columns list. Change the aggregation method in the Aggregation 
            column of the table. You can add the same column multiple
            times. In order to change the aggregation method of more than one 
            column select all columns to change, open the context menu with a 
            right mouse click and select the aggregation method to use.
          </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Advanced settings">
          <option name="Maximum unique values per group">
	        Defines the maximum number of unique values per group to avoid 
	        problems with memory overloading. All groups with more unique
	        values are skipped during the calculation and a missing value is set 
            in the corresponding column, and a warning is displayed.
          </option>
          <option name="Enable hiliting">
			If enabled, the hiliting of a group row will hilite all rows of this
			group in other views. Depending on the number of rows, enabling this 
			feature might consume a lot of memory.
          </option>
          <option name="Column naming">
            The name of the resulting aggregation column(s) depends on the 
            selected naming schema. 
          </option>
          <option name="Process in memory">
            Process the table in the memory. Requires more memory but is faster
            since the table needs not to be sorted prior aggregation. 
            The memory consumption depends on the number of unique groups and
            the chosen aggregation method. The row order of the input table is 
            automatically retained.
          </option>
          <option name="Sort in memory">
            Performs necessary sorting in the memory. Speeds up the process
            but consumes much more memory.
          </option>
          <option name="Retain row order">
            Retains the original row order of the input table. 
            Could result in longer execution time. 
          </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Data table">
	        The input table to pivot.
        </inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Pivot table">
        	Pivot table.
		</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="Group totals">
		    A table containing the totals for each defined group. That is, the 
		    aggregation for each group ignoring the pivoting groups. This table
		    can be joined with the Pivot table; the RowIDs of both tables represent
		    the same groups). The table will contain as many rows as there are 
		    different groups in the data and as many columns as there are selected
		    aggregations. The table is identical to the output of a GroupBy node,
		    in which the group and aggregation columns are chosen accordingly.
        </outPort>
        <outPort index="2" name="Pivot totals">
        	A single row table containing the aggregated values of the Pivot table.
        	The table structure is identical to the Pivot table (possibly enriched
        	by overall totals if the "Append overall totals" is selected. This
        	table is usually concatenated with table that results from joining
        	the Pivot table with the Group table.
        </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
