<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./pca_apply.png" type="Manipulator">
<name>PCA Apply</name>
<shortDescription>Apply principal components projection</shortDescription>
<fullDescription>
<intro>
	        This node applies a projection to the principal components on the given
	        input data. The data model of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Principal_component_analysis">PCA</a> 
	        computation node can be applied to arbitrary data
	        to reduce it to a given number of dimensions.<br/>
	        The information preservation rates in the selection of the target dimensions give the expected
        approximation rates based on the training data fed into the connected PCA Compute
        node. These rates assume that data fed into the predictor is equally distributed
        as the data the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Principal_component_analysis">PCA</a> was computed for initially.  
	        
		</intro>
		<option name="Fail if missing values are encountered">
          If checked, execution fails, when the selected columns contain missing values. 
          By default, rows containing missing values are ignored and not considered in the computation of the principal components.
        </option>
        <option name="Target dimensions">
        Determine the number of dimensions the input data is projected to. 
        The number of target dimensions can either be selected directly or by specifying the 
        minimal amount of information to be preserved.
        If selected directly, the number of dimensions must be lower or equal than the number of input columns.
        If the PCA compute node is connected and executed the possible choices for information preservation 
        correspond to the number of dimensions.
        Each of the choices for the minimum fraction of information to be
         preserved corresponds to a possible number of dimensions to reduce to.
        </option>
        <option name="Replace original data columns">
        If checked, the columns containing the input data are removed in the output table.
        </option>
		</fullDescription>
		<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="PCA model">Principal Components of training data</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="Table to transform">Input data for the PCA</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Projected data">Data projected to its principal components</outPort>
		</ports>
		</knimeNode>
