<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./pca_compute.png" type="Manipulator">
	<name>PCA Compute</name>
	<shortDescription>Principal component analysis computation</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node performs a
			<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Principal_component_analysis">
				principal component analysis (PCA)</a>
			on the given input data.
			The directions of maximal variance (the principal components) are
			extracted and can be used in the PCA Apply node
			to project the input into a space of lower dimension while preserving a
			maximum of information.
		</intro>
		<option name="Fail if missing values are encountered">
			If checked, execution fails, when the selected columns contain missing
			values.
			By default, rows containing missing values are ignored and not
			considered in the computation of the principal components.
		</option>
		<option name="Columns">
			Select the columns that are included in the analysis of principal
			components, i.e. the numerical features of the data.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Table to transform">Input data for the PCA</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Covariance matrix">Covariance matrix of the input columns</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="Spectral decomposition">
			Table containing parameters extracted from the PCA. Each row in the
			table represents one principal component, whereby the rows are sorted
			with decreasing eigenvalues, i.e. variance along the corresponding
			principal axis. The first column in the table contains the component's
			eigenvalue, a high value indicates a high variance (or in other words,
			the respective component dominates the orientation of the input data).
			<br />
		    Each subsequent column (labeled with the name of the selected 
		    input column) contains a coefficient representing the influence
		    of the respective input dimension to the principal component. 
		    The higher the absolute value, the higher the influence of the
		    input dimension on the principal component. 
			<br />
		    In order to component an input rows mapping to, e.g. the first
		    principal axis, you need to apply the following calculation (all 
		    done in the PCA Apply node): For each dimension in the original 
		    space subtract the dimension's mean value, then multiple the 
		    resulting vector with the vector given by this table (the 
		    first row in the spectral decomposition table to get the value on
		    the first PC, the second row for the second PC and so on).    
		</outPort>
		<outPort index="2" name="Projection model">Model with projection to principal
			components, used in the PCA Apply node to apply the transformation
			to, e.g. another validation set.
	    </outPort>

	</ports>
</knimeNode>

