<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./linear_regression_learn.png" type="Learner">
    <name>Linear Regression Learner</name>
    <shortDescription>Performs a multivariate linear regression.</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            Performs a multivariate linear regression. Select in the dialog a 
            target column (combo box on top), i.e. the response. The two
            lists in the center of the dialog allow you to include only certain 
            columns which represent the (independent) variables.
            Make sure the columns you want to have included being in the right
            "include" list.
            
            See article in wikipedia about 
            <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linear_regression">linear regression</a>
            for an overview about the topic.            
		</intro>
        <option name="Target">
            To select the target column. Only columns with numeric data are allowed.
        </option>
        <option name="Values">
            To specify the independent columns the should be included in the regression model. 
            Numeric and nominal data can be included, whereby for nominal data dummy variables are automatically
            created as described in section 
            <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Categorical_variable#Categorical_variables_in_regression">
            Categorical variables in regression</a>.
        </option>  		
        <option name="Predefined Offset Value">
            By default, the regression model includes a constant term. 
            Selecting this option the given constant term is used. The value works like
            a user defined intercept.
        </option>   
        <option name="Missing Values in Input Data">
			Define wether missing value in the input are ignored or whether the node execution should fail
			on missing values. 
        </option>      
        <option name="Scatter Plot View">
			Specify the rows that shall be available as data points in the scatter plot view. 
        </option>             
	</fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input data">Table on which to perform regression.</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Model for Predictor">Model to connect to a predictor node.</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Coefficients and Statistics">Coefficients and statistics of the linear regression model.</outPort>
	</ports>
	<views>
		<view index="0" name="Linear Regression Result View">
    		Displays the estimated coefficients and error statistics.
		</view>
		<view index="1" name="Linear Regression Scatterplot View">
			Displays the input data along with the regression line in a 
			scatterplot. The y-coordinate is fixed to the response column
			(the column that has been approximated) while the x-column can be
			chosen among the independent variables with numerical values. 
			Note: If you have multiple input
			variables, this view is only an approximation. It will fix the value
			of each variable that is not shown in the view to its mean. Thus, 
			this view generally only makes sense if you only have a few input variables.
		</view>		
	</views>
</knimeNode>
