<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./rules2table.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.10" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    <name>Ruleset to Table</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Converts PMML RuleSets (with firstHit) to table containing the rules.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Converts PMML <a href="http://www.dmg.org/v4-2-1/RuleSet.html">RuleSet</a> models (with <tt>firstHit</tt> rule selection method) to table containing the rules. This table is suitable for the Rule Engine (Dictionary) node as a rule input (even with PMML output generation). Use cases for this node: Convert the PMML model to ordinary table to <ul>
        <li>concatenate different rule tables</li>
        <li>(row) filter out certain outcomes</li>
        <li>re-level/recode outcomes</li>
        </ul></intro>
        
        
        <option name="Split rules to condition and outcome columns">When checked, two columns will be created for the rules, <b>Condition</b> and <b>Outcome</b>, otherwise the rules will reside in a single column, <b>Rule</b>.</option>
        <option name="Add confidence and weight columns">From PMML the <a href="http://www.dmg.org/v4-2-1/RuleSet.html#xsdGroup_Rule">confidence and weight</a> attributes are extracted to columns.</option>
        <option name="Add Record count and Number of correct statistics columns">In PMML, the <tt>recordCount</tt> and the <tt>nbCorrect</tt> attributes provide statistics about the input (training/test/validation) data, with this option, this information can be extracted to the columns: <b>Record count</b> and <b>Number of correct</b></option>
        <option name="Use additional parentheses to document precedence rules">If checked the output will contain additional parenthesis around rule parts to clearly document precedence. For instance, NOT is a stronger operator than AND than OR - using parenthesis improves readability. Checking this option does not change any of the rule logic.</option>
        <option name="Provide score distibution record count in table with column name prefix">Information about the record count of score distribution is saved to the table with the specified prefix.</option>
        <option name="Provide score distibution probability in table with column name prefix">Information about the probabilities of score distribution is saved to the table with the specified prefix</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="PMML RuleSet model">The PMML RuleSet model</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Rules table">The table contains the rules' text (in single (<b>Rule</b>) or two columns (<b>Condition</b>, <b>Outcome</b>), the rule <b>Confidence</b> and <b>Weight</b> information and optionally the <b>Record count</b> (for how many rows did the ruleset matched when created) and <b>Number of correct</b> values where the outcome of the rule matched the expected label when the model was created.</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
