<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./sampling.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Row Sampling</name>
    <shortDescription>Extracts a sample (a bunch of rows) from the input data.</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This node extracts a sample (a bunch of rows) from the input data. The dialog enables you to specify the
            sample size. The following options are available in the dialog:
        </intro>
        <option name="Absolute">
            Specify the absolute number of rows in the sample. If there are less rows than specified here, all rows are
            used.
        </option>
        <option name="Relative">
            The percentage of the number of rows in the sample. Must be between 0 and 100, inclusively.
        </option>
        <option name="Take from top">This mode selects the top most rows of 
            the table.</option>
        <option name="Linear sampling">
            This mode always includes the first and the last row and selects the remaining rows linearly over the whole
            table (e.g. every third row). This is useful to downsample a sorted column while maintaining minimum and
            maximum value.
        </option>
        <option name="Draw randomly">
            Random sampling of all rows, you may optionally specify a fixed seed (see below).
        </option>
        <option name="Stratified sampling">
            Check this button if you want stratified sampling, i.e. the distribution of values in the selected column is
            (approximately) retained in the output table. You may optionally specify a fixed seed (see below). 
        </option>
        <option name="Use random seed">
            If either random or stratified sampling is selected, you may enter a fixed seed here
            in order to get reproducible results upon re-execution. If you do not specify a seed,
            a new random seed is taken for each execution. 
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <dataIn index="0" name="Table to sample from">Table to sample from.</dataIn>
        <dataOut index="0" name="The sampled table">The sampled table.</dataOut>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
