<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Manipulator" icon="lowVar.png">
	<name>Low Variance Filter</name>
	<shortDescription>
		 Filters out numeric columns, which have a low variance.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
		  <p>
			Filters out double-compatible columns, whose variance is below
			a user defined threshold. Columns with low variance are likely to 
			distract certain learning algorithms (in particular those which are
			distance based) and are therefore better removed.
		  </p>
		  <p>
			Note, the input table should not be normalized.
		  </p>		
		</intro>

      <tab name="Column Filter">      
		
		<option name="Variance Upper Bound">
			Choose a variance value here. The higher the value, the more columns
			are likely to get filtered out. Choose 0 to filter for columns, which
			only contain one constant value.
		</option>
				
        <option name="Exclude">
            This list contains the column names of the input table that 
            will be left untouched (i.e. will also be present
            in the output table independent of their variance).
        </option>

        <option name="Enforce Exclusion">
            Select this option to enforce the current exclusion list to stay
            the same even if the input table specification changes. If some
            of the excluded columns are not available anymore, a warning
            is displayed. (New columns will automatically be added to the
            inclusion list.)
        </option>
		
        <option name="Select">
            Use these buttons to move columns between the Include and Exclude 
            list.
        </option>
        
        <option name="Search">
            Use one of these fields to search either within the Include
            or Exclude list for certain column names or name substrings.
            Repeated clicking of the search button marks the next column that 
            matches the search text. The check box 'Mark all search hits' causes
            all matching columns to be selected making them movable between
            the two lists.
        </option>
        
        <option name="Include">
            This list contains the column names that are considered for
            filtering. Any other column will be left untouched (i.e. will also be present
            in the output table independent of their variance).
        </option>
        
        <option name="Enforce Inclusion">
            Select this option to enforce the current inclusion list to stay
            the same even if the input table specification changes. If some
            of the included columns are not available anymore, a warning
            is displayed. (New columns will automatically be added to the
            exclusion list.)
        </option>
        
        </tab>	
		
<!--		<option name="Column Filter">
			Only columns in the &quot;include&quot; list will be considered for
			filtering. Any other column will be left untouched (i.e. will also be present
			in the output table independent of their variance).
		</option> -->
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Input data">Numeric input data. (Non-numeric columns will be left untouched.)</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Filtered data">Filtered data.</outPort>
	</ports>
	
</knimeNode>