<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./scatter.png" type="Visualizer">
	<name>Scatter Plot</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
	    Creates a scatterplot of two selected attributes.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>		
	    <p>Creates a scatterplot of two selectable attributes. Then each datapoint is
	    displayed as a dot at its corresponding place, dependent on it's values
	    of the selected attributes. The dots are displayed in the color defined by
        the Color Manager, the size defined by the Size Manager, and the shape
        defined by the Shape Manager.
		</p>
		
		<h3>HiLiting:</h3>
		<p> The data points may be selected by either dragging
		a rectangle with the mouse over the points or 
		by clicking on points.
		Hold control pressed for multiple selection. 
		The selected datapoints may be 
		hilited by either right-click to get the context menu or via the hilite
		menu in the menu bar.</p>
		
		<h3>Tooltip</h3>
		<p>
		Move the mouse over the data points to get detailed information about 
		the data point (Row ID, and the x and y value).
		</p>
		
		<h3>Properties: </h3>
		<p>Default Settings:
			<ul>
			<li>Mouse Mode: choose "Selection" to select the datapoints or
			"Zooming" to zoom in. If you have zoomed in you may choose "Moving" 
			to navigate in the zoomed display.</li>
			<li>"Fit to screen" fits the display again to the available space.</li>
			<li>"Background color lets you choose the background color of the display. </li>
			</ul>
		</p>
		<p>Column Selection:
		Choose the columns you want to have displayed as x and y coordinate.
		With the "X attribute" and "Y attribute" spinners the range of the axes
		can be adjusted. The left spinner changes the lower end, the right 
		spinner the upper end.
		</p>
		<p>Appearance:
			<ul>
			<li>"Dot Size" lets you define the size of the dots.</li>
			<li>"Jitter": if a nominal column is selected you may adjust how much
			the values are jittered (scattered around there origin).</li>
			</ul>
		</p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Nr. of rows to display">Enter the maximum number of rows
		the plotter should display. Setting a higher value than the default value 
		might dramatically decrease performance.</option>
		<option name="Enable Anti-aliasing">Check if the view should enable anti-aliasing
		(make a smoother drawing). This will slow down performance as well.</option>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<dataIn index="0" name="Display data">Datatable with data to display</dataIn>
	</ports>	
	<views>
		<view index="0" name="Scatterplot">
			The scatterplot displaying the data.
		</view>
	</views>
</knimeNode>