<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="line.png" type="Visualizer">
	<name>Financial Bar Chart</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
	    Plots the high-low price bar for each row and the close price 
	    as a point inside the bar.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
	
		<intro>		
	    <p>Plots the high-low price bars and reports the corresponding times 
	    on the x-axis. Four columns are needed in the input table with 
	    the following names: High, Low, Close, Open.   
		</p>
		
		<h3>HiLiting:</h3>
		<p> The data points may be selected by either dragging
		a rectangle with the mouse over the points or 
		by clicking on points 
		(if the dots are not displayed you won't see the selection or hilite since
		only data points can be selected or hilited). 
		Hold control pressed for multiple selection. 
		The selected datapoints may be 
		hilited by either right-click to get the context menu or via the hilite
		menu in the menu bar.</p>
		
		<h3>Tooltip</h3>
		<p>
		Move the mouse over the data points to get detailed information about 
		the data point (date, and high, low, open and close prices).
		</p>
		
		<h3>Properties: </h3>
		<p>Default Settings:
			<ul>
			<li>Mouse Mode: choose "Selection" to select the datapoints or
			"Zooming" to zoom in. If you have zoomed in you may choose "Moving" 
			to navigate in the zoomed display.</li>
			<li>"Fit to screen" fits the display again to the available space.</li>
			<li>"Background color lets you choose the background color of the display. </li>
			</ul>
		</p>
		<p>Legend: 
		Since the colors of the lines do not depend on the colors of the rows
		(since not the rows, but the columns are displayed as lines) the colors are created
		automatically. Click "Change.." in the legend to change the color of the referring line.
		</p>
		</intro>
		
		<option name="Column containing Timestamp">
        Select the input column containing timestamp cells
        that will be reported on the x-axis</option>
		
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<dataIn index="0" name="Display data">Datatable with data to display</dataIn>
	</ports>	
	<views>
		<view index="0" name="Financial Bar Chart">
			The bar chart displaying the data.
		</view>
	</views>
</knimeNode>