<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="loop_start_window.png" type="LoopStart"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
	<name>Window Loop Start</name>

	<shortDescription>Sliding window over input table.</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>In each iteration the node selects a set of rows specified by a
			window, which defines the output table. The window is either defined
			by the number of rows it contains, or by selecting a certain time or
			date interval.
		</intro>
		<option name="Row based">
			The window size and step size are chosen as a
			number of rows. In each iteration a window will be returned with
			the
			exact number of rows as specified by the window size.
		</option>
		<option name="Time based">
			The window size and step size are given as duration. If no row lies
			within the next time window, the window will be moved forward until
			it at least contains a single row or no rows are left.
			The chosen time
			column has to be sorted in ascending order or the node will fail
			<i>(see 'Sorter' Node)</i>
			. Note the size of the output table can vary per iteration.
		</option>
		<option name="Window size">
			The window size is either defined as
			the number of
			rows it contains (row based) or as a duration (time based).
			Depending
			on the chosen method the number of rows returned in each iteration
			are static or variable.
		</option>
		<option name="Step size">
			The step size, which is either given as the number
			of rows (event triggered) or as a temporal amount (time triggered).
			The step size defines on how the window will move as it either
			defines the number of elements or the time it will skip after each
			iteration.
		</option>
		<option name="Limit window to table">
			If selected, the sliding window will never overlap
			with the start or the end of the table. If false, undefined rows will
			be added as missing values.
		</option>
		<option name="Start at">
			If selected, the window will start at the
			specified date and time. Otherwise, the window will choose the
			date
			and time of the first row as a starting point.
		</option>

		<option name="Forward">
			Looks window size forward from the current row.
		</option>
		<option name="Central">
			Looks half the window size backward from the
			current row and half forward.
		</option>
		<option name="Backward">
			Looks window size backward from the current row.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Any table">Any input table. Each iteration will
			process one part of this table.
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Windowed input">Window
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
