<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="loop_start_window.png" type="LoopStart"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
	<name>Window Loop Start</name>

	<shortDescription>Sliding window over input table.</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>The Window Loop Start node takes a table as input, defines a window of a
certain size onto the table, breaks the table into chunks of the size of
this window, and outputs these chunks one by one as it loops over the table.
The size of the window is defined in terms of either the number of rows
it contains or the date/time interval it covers.
		</intro>
		<option name="Row based">If this option is selected, both window size and step size (the distance between the starting point of one iteration and the starting point of the next) can be defined in terms of number of rows. With each iteration, the node then returns a table with the specified number of rows.
		</option>
		<option name="Time based">
		If this option is selected, both window size and step size (the distance between the starting point of one iteration and the starting point of the next) can be defined in terms of a date/time interval. If the window contains no row, it is moved forward until it contains at least one row or no rows are left.   The chosen time column has to be sorted in ascending order or the node will fail (see Sorter node). Note that the size of the output table can vary from one iteration to the next, and that the loop terminates as soon as the last line of the input table appears in the window or in the step interval.  
		</option>
		<option name="Window size">
			The window size is defined either as
			the number of
			rows it contains (in case it is row based) or as the date/time interval it covers (in case it is time based).
			Depending
			on the chosen method, the number of rows returned in each iteration
			is static or variable.
		</option>
		<option name="Step size">
			The step size is the distance between the starting point of one iteration and the starting point of the next.  It is defined in terms of number
			of rows covered (in case it is event triggered) or time elapsed (in case it is time triggered).
		</option>
		<option name="Limit window to table">
			If this option is selected, the moving window will not extend beyond the beginning or the end of the table. If this option is not selected, undefined rows with missing values will be added.
		</option>
		<option name="Start at">
			If this option is selected, the window will start at the
			specified date and time. If this option is not selected, the window will start with the date and time of the first row.
		</option>

		<option name="Forward">
			If this option is selected, the current row will be the first row of the window.
		</option>
		<option name="Central">
			If this option is selected, the current row will be midway between the first and the last row of the window.
		</option>
		<option name="Backward">
			If this option is selected, the current row will be the last row of the window.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Any table">Any input table. Each iteration will
			process one part of this table.
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Windowed input">Window
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
