<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="featureselection-filter.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Feature Selection Filter</name>

    <shortDescription>Applies a feature filter model built during feature selection</shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
		This node takes a model built with a feature selection loop as input and lets you choose the subset of columns you want to include in the output table.  The dialog shows all computed subsets together with their scores.  You can select a subset manually or specify a score threshold.  If you specify a threshold, the smallest features set whose score meets the threshold requirement is selected.  If the "Minimize Score" option was checked in the Feature Selection Loop End node, this is the smallest feature set with a score below the specified threshold; if the "Minimize Score" option was left unchecked in the Feature Selection Loop End node, this is the smallest feature set with a score above the specified threshold.
        </intro>

        <option name="Include static columns">
		If this option is checked, any static columns are included in the output table, otherwise they are filtered out.
        </option>
        <option name="Select features manually">By selecting this option you can choose a set of features in the table below.</option>
        <option name="Select features automatically by score threshold">By selecting this option you can set a
        prediction score threshold.</option>
        <option name="Prediction score threshold">Enter a prediction score threshold here.  The smallest feature set with a score below the specified threshold (if the score is to be minimized) or above the specified threshold (if the score is to be maximized) is selected.</option>       
        <option name="Feature set table">
		The feature sets are listed on the right side, their scores and the number of features in these sets on the left side.  Clicking on a score on the left side highlights the corresponding feature set on the right side.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Selection model">A feature selection model</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Any datatable">Any data table that should contain the same columns as used in the
        selection loop
        </inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Filtered table">The input table with some columns filtered out</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
