<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./sota.png" type="Learner">
	<name>SOTA Learner</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
	    Clusters numerical data with SOTA.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
	<intro>		
	<p>Clusters numerical and fuzzy data hierarchically with the self organizing 
	tree algorithm and visualizes the cluster tree similarly like a dendogram.
	Additionally it builds a model for class prediction of new data. The model can be
	load into the SOTA Predictor node.
	</p>	
	<p>The SOTA Learner node has a dialog, in which you can choose the winner, ancestor and
	sister learning rate, to adjust the cluster representants: with the 
	minimal resource and variability value to stop the growing of the tree; the
	minimal error, to end a cycle and the distance metric (cosinus, euclidean).
	The node will cluster the given data hierarchically by use of the self
	organizing tree algorithm and will produce a cluster tree, which is
	visualized by the view afterwards, similar to a dendogram.
	The data is also displayed and can be hilit, as well as each cluster 
	representative.
	Class information can be trained too by selecting the "Use class column"
	option for uses of class prediction by the SOTA Predictor node.
	</p>
	<p>For more information about the SOTA clustering see:
	Herrero J., Valencia A., Dopazo J.:
	A hierarchical unsupervised growing neural network for clustering gene 
	expression patterns.
	</p>
	</intro>
	<option name="Winner learningrate">
		Set the winners learning rate which is used to adjust the winning cluster
		representative to the given data.
	</option>
	<option name="Sister learningrate">
		Set the sisters learning rate which is used to adjust the sister-cluster
		representative of the winner to the given data.
	</option>
	<option name="Ancestor learningrate">
		Set the ancestors learning rate which is used to adjust the 
		ancestor-cluster representative of the winner to the given data.
	</option>
	<option name="Minimal variability">
		Set the minimal variability value, which is the threshold for stopping
		the growing of the tree, if the "Use variability" checkbox is checked.
		If minimal variability is set to 0 the clustering will not stop before
		each datapoint is represented by a cluster representative.
	</option>
	<option name="Minimal resource">
		Set the minimal resource value, which is the threshold for stopping
		the growing of the tree, if the "Use variability" checkbox is <b>not</b> 
		checked. The resource value is used as threshold to stop the growing 
		by default. If minimal resource is set to a very small number i.e. 0.01
		the clustering will not stop before each datapoint is represented by a
		cluster representant. The minimal resource value cannot be set to 0
		but only to very small numbers.
	</option>
	<option name="Minimal error">
		Set the minimal error value to control the epochs per cycle. If the
		minimal error value is small, more epochs will be needed to end a cycle.
		This means, that all cluster representatives will be pulled closer to 
		their data.
	</option>
	<option name="Use variability">
		Check this if the minimal variability value should be used to
		stop the growing of the tree, or leave it unchecked to use the
		minimal resource value. Be aware that the computation of the minimal
		variability value is very time consuming when clustering large amounts
		of data. The complexity is n*n.
	</option>
	<option name="Distance metric">
		Choose the euclidean or cosinus distance metric, to measure the distance
		between datapoints and cluster representatives.
	</option>
	<option name="Use hierarchical fuzzy data">
		Check to cluster hierarchical fuzzy rules hierarchically. The column
		with the fuzzy rule level has to be selected in the drop down menu on 
		the right. The drop down menu will be enabled when the checkbox is
		checked.
	</option>
	<option name="Hierarchical level">
		If the checkbox on the left is checked, to cluster hierarchical fuzzy
		rules, the column with the fuzzy rule level must be chosen by 
		selecting it in the drop down menu.
	</option>
	<option name="Use class column">
		Check to use the class data specified by the drop down box below.
		The class data will be trained too for the use of class prediction by the
		SOTA Predictor node.
	</option>	
	<option name="Class column">
		Specifies the column containing the class data. Only string columns can
		be chosen as class columns.
	</option>		
	</fullDescription>
		
	<ports>
		<dataIn name="Any input table" index="0">
			Datatable with integer columns to do clustering on
		</dataIn>
		<modelOut index="0" name="The model of the trained SOTA">
			The model of the trained SOTA.
		</modelOut>
	</ports>	
		
	<views>
		<view index="0" name="SOTA Tree View">
			Displays the results of the SOTA clustering
		</view>
	</views>
	
</knimeNode>

