<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./cellsplitter.png" type="Manipulator">
	<name>Cell Splitter</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
	    Splits cells in one column of the table into separate columns based on a specified delimiter.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>This node uses a user-specified delimiter character to
		split the content of a selected column into parts. It appends a fixed
		number of columns to the input table, each carrying one part of the 
		original column.<br />
		If the column contains more delimiters than needed 
		(leading to more parts than appended columns are available) the 
		additional delimiters are ignored (resulting in the last column containing
		the unsplit rest of the column).<br />
		If the selected column contains too
		few delimiters (leading to less parts than expected), empty columns
		will be created in that row.<br />
		The content of the new columns will be trimmed (i.e. leading and trailing
		spaces will be deleted).
		</intro>
		<option name="Column selection"> 
			Select the column whose values are split.
		</option>
		<option name="Delimiter">Specify the delimiter in the value, that 
		splits each part.
		</option>
        <option name="Use escape character">If enabled, the backslash ("\")
        can be used to escape characters, such as "\t" for tabs. You can use
        the full escape capabilities of Java.
        </option>
	    <option name="Quotation character">Specify the quotation character, if 
	    the different parts in the value are quoted. (The character to escape
	    quotes is always the backslash.) If no quotation character
	    is needed leave it empty.
		</option>
		<option name="Set Array Size">Check this and specify the number of columns
		to append. All created columns will be of type String. (See above for 
		what happens if the split produces a different number of parts.)
		</option>
		<option name="Guess Size and Column Types">If this is checked, the node
		performs an additional scan through the entire data table and computes 
		the number of columns needed to hold all parts of the split. In addition
		it determines the column type of the new columns. 
		</option>
		<option name="Missing Value Handling">If select, the node creates 
		empty string cell instead of missing value cells. 
        </option>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Input Table">Input data table with column containing the cells to split</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Output Table">Output data table with additional columns.</outPort>
	</ports>	
</knimeNode>
