<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Other" icon="rankcorrelation.png">
    <name>Rank Correlation</name>
    <shortDescription>
        Computes correlation coefficients for pairs of columns, based on the sorting of its values only.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
          <p>
                Calculates for each pair of selected columns a correlation
                coefficient, i.e. a measure of the correlation of the two variables.
        </p>
            <p>
            All measures are based on the rank of the cells. Where the rank of a cell value refers 
            to its position in a sorted list of all entries. All correlation can be calculated on any kind of DataColumn.
            However please note that we use the default ordering of the values. If there is no ordering defined in the
            column, a string representation will be used.
            
            <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spearman%27s_rank_correlation_coefficient"> Spearman's rank correlation coefficient </a> is a statistical measure of the strength of a monotonic relationship between paired data. Where the monotonic relationship is characterised by a relationship between ordered sets that preserves the given order, i.e., either never increases or never decreases as its independent variable increases.
            The value of this measure ranges from -1 (strong negative correlation) to 1 (strong positive correlation). A perfect Spearman correlation of +1 or −1 occurs when each of the variables is a perfect monotone function of the other. 

            <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Goodman_and_Kruskal%27s_gamma"> Goodman and Kruskal's gamma</a> as well as <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kendall_tau_rank_correlation_coefficient">Kendall's tau rank correlation coefficient</a> is used to measure the strength of association between two measured quantities. Both are based on the number of concordant and discordant pairs. Kendall's Tau A and Tau B coefficients can be considered as standardized forms of Gamma. The difference between Tau A and Tau B is that Tau A statistic does not consider tied values, while Tau B makes adjustments for them. By tied observations we consider two or more observations having the same value. Both Kruskal's gamma and Kendall's Tau A are mostly suitable for square tables, whereas Tau B is most appropriately used for rectangular tables. The coefficients must be in the range from −1 (100% negative association, or perfect inversion) to +1 (100% positive association, or perfect agreement). A value of zero indicates the absence of association.


            <br /> 
            </p>
            <p> Rows containing Missing Values will be ignored, not used for the calculations. For other behaviors please resolve them before. 
            </p>
        </intro>
    <tab name="Column Filter">
          <option name="Include">
            This list contains the column names for which correlation values shall
            be computed.
        </option>
        
        <option name="Enforce Inclusion">
            Select this option to enforce the current inclusion list to stay
            the same even if the input table specification changes. 
            New columns will automatically be added to the exclusion list.
        </option>
      
        <option name="Select">
            Use these buttons to move columns between the Include and Exclude 
            list.
        </option>
        
        <option name="Search">
            Use one of these fields to search either within the Include
            or Exclude list for certain column names or name substrings.
            Repeated clicking of the search button marks the next column that 
            matches the search text. The check box 'Mark all search hits' causes
            all matching columns to be selected making them movable between
            the two lists.
        </option>
        
        <option name="Exclude">
            This list contains the column names of the input table that are 
            left out of the calculation.
        </option>
        
        <option name="Enforce Exclusion">
            Select this option to enforce the current exclusion list to stay
            the same even if the input table specification changes. 
            New columns will automatically be added to the inclusion list.
        </option>
        
      </tab>
      <tab name=" ">

        <option name="Correlation Type">
            Chose the type of correlation here. There are the Spearman Correlation, two types of Kendalls Tau 
            and  Goodman and Kruskal's Gamma.
        </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Numeric input data">Numeric input data to evaluate</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Correlation measure">Correlation variables in a square
            matrix</outPort>
        <outPort name="Correlation Model" index="1">
            A model containing the correlation measures. This model is appropriate to be read by the Correlation Filter node.</outPort>            
        <outPort name="Rank table" index="2">
            A table containing the ranks of the columns. Where the rank corresponds to the values position in a sorted table.</outPort>
    </ports> 
    <views>
        <view name="Correlation Matrix" index="0">Squared table view showing
            the
            pair-wise correlation values of all columns. The color range varies from
            dark red (strong negative correlation), over white (no correlation) to
            dark blue (strong positive correlation). If a correlation value for a
            pair
            of column is not available, the corresponding cell contains a missing
            value
            (shown as cross in the color view).</view>
    </views>
</knimeNode>