<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Manipulator" icon="dateshift.png" deprecated="true">
    <name>Date/Time Shift </name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Adds a value in a defined granularity to an existing date.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro> The node shifts a date/time with a defined granularity. The user can select the date reference and the shift value.
        The date can be chosen as a Date/Time column, as the execution time or as a fixed entered date.
        The shift value can be achieved by using a numerical column, however, it is also possible to enter 
        a constant shift value.
        The numerical shift value is added to the selected date. The value is interpreted based on the selected
        granularity (year, quarter, month, week, day, hour, minute).
        </intro>
        
        <option name="Use shift value from column">Select to chose the shift value from a numerical column.</option>
        <option name="Use static shift value">Select to use a constant shift value.</option>
        <option name="Shift value">Define the constant value for your shift.</option>        
        <option name="Select shift column">Select the column containing the value to apply.</option>
        <option name="Select granularity of shift">The granularity of the numerical value 
        	(in years, months, weeks, days, hours, minutes, seconds, milliseconds)</option>
        <option name="Replace column">If selected, the input column will be replaced by the computed result. </option>  
        <option name="Appended column name">Name of the newly appended column containing the calculate date/time. </option>  
        
        
        <option name="Use execution time">Select the execution time as the basic date.</option>
        <option name="Use date/time column">Select a date/time column as the basic date.</option>
        <option name="Use fixed date">Define a specific date in the fixed time section as the basic date.</option>
        
        
        <option name="Select a date column">Select a column containing a date as the baseline of the calculations.</option>
        <option name="Fixed time">The fixed time for the corresponding option. </option>  
        <option name="Use date">Check for using the date in the output date column. </option>      
        <option name="Use time">Check for using the time in the output date column. </option>      
        <option name="Use milliseconds">Check for using the milliseconds in the output date column. </option>                              
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input table">Table to be shifted or empty table</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Shifted date">Out data with the shifted date appended</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
