<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./chopper.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Chopper</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Reads items from a string of one column and stores these in one column as vector/collections or in multiple 
        columns. 
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>This node takes a string that consists of tokens which are separated by a certain patter (e.g. 
        TAB, space, etc.) and separates a certain number of these tokens from the beginning of the string. It
        converts them either in floating point numbers or keeps them as strings. The new values are stored in 
        one new column (as a collection or a vector) or each in a separate new column. 
        If the string consists of more than the extracted tokens, the remaining part of the string can be stored in
        a new column for further processing.<br/>
        The string must be comprised of simple tokens; there is no support for quoted tokens, different decimal 
        separators, or comment lines in the file. <br/>
        The node operates row-based. It can be executed in streaming mode.
        </intro>
        <option name="Column with string to split">
        Select the column that contains the string with the tokens that should be extracted and converted. Only columns
        of type String can be selected.
        </option>
        <option name="Number of items">
        Enter the number of tokens that should be extracted from the string. Tokens are taken from the start (from the 
        left) of the string. If less tokens are in the string, an empty string or NaN (Not a Number) is inserted. 
        </option>
        <option name="Select the type of the items">
        Specify if the tokens extracted should be converted to a &quote;Double&quote; (floating point) or should be 
        stored as string.
	    </option>
        <option name="Select the type of new appended column(s)">
        The extracted tokens are stored in a new column. Either in one new column in a &quote;Vector&quote; or a 
        &quote;Collection&quote;, or in multiple columns (&quote;Cells&quote;) - one for each token of type Double or 
        String (depending on the selected type of the items from above).
        </option>
        <option name="Prefix/name of new column(s)">
        Specify the name of the new column that contains the extracted tokens. If multiple columns are appended (option
        &quote;type of appended column&quote; above), this serves as prefix for the generated column names.
        </option>
        <option name="Keep column with left over string">
        If this option is selected the rest of the string (after chopping off the extracted tokens) is stored in a new
        column for further processing.  
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input">DataTable with column to extract tokens from</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Extracted Tokens">DataTable with additional column(s) 
        carrying the extracted items from the input column
        </outPort>
    </ports>    

</knimeNode>
