<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./logistic_regression_learn.png" type="Learner">
    <name>Logistic Regression Learner</name>
    <shortDescription>Performs a multinomial logistic regression.</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            Performs a multinomial logistic regression. Select in the dialog a 
            target column (combo box on top), i.e. the response. The two
            lists in the center of the dialog allow you to include only certain 
            columns which represent the (independent) variables.
            Make sure the columns you want to have included being in the right
            "include" list.
            
            See article in wikipedia about 
            <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logistic_regression">logistic regression</a>
            for an overview about the topic.
            
            This particular implementation uses an iterative optimization procedure
            termed Fisher's scoring in order to compute the model. 
            <br />
            If the optional PMML inport is connected and contains 
    		preprocessing operations in the TransformationDictionary those are 
    		added to the learned model.
		</intro>
        <option name="Target">
            Select the target column. Only columns with nominal data are allowed. The reference category is empty
            if the domain of the target column is not available. In this case the node determines the domain values right 
            before computing the logistic regression model and chooses the last domain value as the targets reference 
            category.<br />
            By default the target domain values are sorted lexicographically in the output, but you can enforce the 
            order of the target column domain to be preserved by checking the box.
            <br />
            Note, if a target reference column is selected in the dropdown the checkbox will have no influence on the
            coefficients of the model except that the output representation (e.g. order of rows in the coefficient table)
            may vary.
        </option>
        <option name="Values">
            Specify the independent columns that should be included in the regression model. 
            Numeric and nominal data can be included.<br />
            By default the domain values (categories) of nominal valued columns are sorted lexicographically, 
            but you can check that the order from the column domain is used. Please note that the first
            category is used as a reference when creating the 
            <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Categorical_variable#Categorical_variables_in_regression">
            dummy variables</a>.
        </option>  		
	</fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input data">Table on which to perform regression. The input must not contain missing values, you have to fix them by e.g. using the Missing Values node.</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="PMML Preprocessing">Optional PMML port object containing preprocessing operations.</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Model for Predictor">Model to connect to a predictor node.</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Coefficients and Statistics">Coefficients and statistics of the logistic regression model.</outPort>
	</ports>
	<views>
		<view index="0" name="Logistic Regression Result View">
    		Displays the estimated coefficients and error statistics. Note, 
    		that the estimated coefficients are not reliable when the standard
    		error is high.
		</view>
	</views>
</knimeNode>
