<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Source" icon="./icon_fwfr.png">
	<name>Fixed Width File Reader</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
	    Fixed column width reader for ASCII files.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>		
		This node can be used to read data from an ASCII file or URL location.
		It reads files where a column is defined by the number of characters
		and not by a column delimiter.<br />
		When you open the node's configuration dialog and provide a filename, 
		the reader creates one column. This column shows only the remaining characters 
		in the preview table and won't be appended to the output table.<br />
		
		<p />

		The preview shows only the first couple of lines. It could happen then, that
		the preview appears looking fine, but the execution of the Fixed Width File Reader
		fails. <br />
		</intro>
		
		<option name="ASCII file location">Enter a valid file name or URL. When
			you press ENTER, a preview of the file is shown.
			You can also choose a previously read file from the drop-down list,
			or select a file from the "Browse..." dialog.
			</option>		
		<option name="Preserve user settings"> If checked, the checkmarks and
		    column names/types you entered are preserved even if 
		    you select a new file. By default, the dialog starts with fresh
		    default settings for each new file location.
		    </option>
		<option name="Click on add">A new dialog opens where column properties can be set: 
			<ul>
			<li>Number of columns to add: Specify a number of columns you would like to add.</li>
			<li>Name/Prefix: Set a unique column name or prefix if more than one column should be added.</li>
			<li>Width: The width of the column in number of characters.</li>
			<li>Type: Choose a type. </li>
			<li>Missing Value Pattern: Pattern for which a "missing cell" will be created.</li>
			<li>DON'T include: The Fixed Width File reader skips this column.</li>
			</ul>
			</option>
		<option name="Click on edit">A new dialog opens with the column settings set. Each entry 
			can be changed and the current column will be replaced.
			</option>
		<option name="Click on remove">The selected columns will be removed. <br />
			Note: You can't remove the first column if "Read row IDs" is selected.</option>
		<option name="Read row IDs">If checked, the first column in the file
			is used as row IDs. If not checked, a default row headers are
			created.</option>
		<option name="Read column headers">If checked, the items in the first 
			line of the file are used as column names. 
			Otherwise default column names are created.</option>
	    <option name="Click on the table header">If the column header in the 
	    	preview table is clicked the edit dialog will open.
		    </option>	      	
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<outPort index="0" name="File Table">Datatable just read from the file</outPort>
	</ports>	
</knimeNode>