<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="treeensemble.png" type="Learner">
	<name>Tree Ensemble Learner</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Learns an ensemble of decision trees (such as random forest variants).
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
            Learns an ensemble of decision trees (such as random forest variants).
            <p>
                <i>This node is lacking documentation, it will be added for the open source release</i>
            </p>
		</intro>
	    <option name="Target Column">
	       Select the column containing the value to be learned. Rows with
	       missing values in this column will be ignored during the learning
	       process.
        </option>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
	    <inPort index="0" name="Input Data">The data to learn from. It must
	    contain at least one nominal target column and either a fingerprint
	    (bitvector) column or another numeric or nominal column.</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Out-of-bag error estimates">The input data with
		  the out-of-bag error estimates, i.e. for each record the majority vote
		  of all models that were not used in the training of the that models.
		  If the entire data was used to train the individual models, then this
		  output will contain the input data with missing prediction and 
		  confidence values. The appended columns are equivalent to the columns
		  appended by the corresponding predictor node. There is one additional
		  column <i>model count</i>, which contains the number of models used
		  for the voting (that is, the number of models that did not use the 
		  record throughout the learning.)
	    </outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="Attribute Statistics">A statistics table on the
		attributes used in the different tree learners. Each row represents
		one training attribute with these statistics: <i>#splits (level	x)</i>
		as  the number of models, which use the attribute as split on 
		level <i>x</i> (with level 0 as root split); <i>#candidates (level 
		x)</i> is the number of times an attribute was in the attribute sample
		for level <i>x</i> (in a random forest setup these samples differ from
		node to node). If no attribute sampling is used this is the 
		number of models. Note, these numbers are uncorrected, i.e. if an 
		attribute is selected on level 0 but is also in the candidate set
		of level 1 (but will not be split on level 1 because it has been split 
		one level up), the #candidate number will still count the attribute 
		as candidate.</outPort>
		<outPort index="2" name="Tree Ensemble Model">The trained model.</outPort>
	</ports>
	<views>
      <view name="Tree Views" index="0">An decision tree viewer for all the 
        trained models. Use the spinner to iterate through the different models.
      </view>
    </views>
</knimeNode>
