<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./dectree2rules.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.10" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    <name>Decision Tree to Ruleset</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Converts a decision tree model to PMML RuleSet model.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Converts (a single) decision tree model to PMML <a href="http://www.dmg.org/v4-2-1/RuleSet.html">RuleSet</a> model and also to a table containing the rules in a textual form. The resulting rules are independent of each other, the order of rules is not specified, can be changed. Missing value strategies are ignored, it will always evaluate to missing value.</intro>
        
        
        <option name="Split rules to condition and outcome columns">When checked, two columns will be created for the rules, <b>Condition</b> and <b>Outcome</b>, otherwise the rules will reside in a single column, <b>Rule</b>.</option>
        <option name="Add confidence and weight columns">From PMML the <a href="http://www.dmg.org/v4-2-1/RuleSet.html#xsdGroup_Rule">confidence and weight</a> attributes are extracted to columns. (It will create columns with missing values.)</option>
        <option name="Add Record count and Number of correct statistics columns">In PMML, the <tt>recordCount</tt> and the <tt>nbCorrect</tt> attributes provide statistics about the input (training/test/validation) data, with this option, this information can be extracted to the columns: <b>Record count</b> and <b>Number of correct</b></option>
        <option name="Use additional parentheses to document precedence rules">If checked the output will contain additional parenthesis around rule parts to clearly document precedence. For instance, NOT is a stronger operator than AND than OR - using parenthesis improves readability. Checking this option does not change any of the rule logic.</option>
        <option name="Provide score distibution record count in PMML">PMML will store the information obtained from the rules on record counts of score distribution (how many times were the different values were present in the training data, not necessarily integer)</option>
        <option name="Provide score distibution record count in table with column name prefix">Information about the record count of score distribution is saved to the table with the specified prefix.</option>
        <option name="Provide score distibution probability in PMML">PMML will store the information obtained from the rules on probabilities of score distribution (in the training data what was the probability of certain values for that decision tree leaf)</option>
        <option name="Provide score distibution probability in table with column name prefix">Information about the probabilities of score distribution is saved to the table with the specified prefix</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="PMML Decision Tree">A PMML Decision Tree model.</inPort>
        <!-- possibly more input ports here-->
        <outPort index="0" name="PMML RuleSet">The decision tree model represented as PMML RuleSets (with <tt>firstHit</tt> rule selection method).</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Rules table">The table contains the rules' text (in single (<b>Rule</b>) or two columns (<b>Condition</b>, <b>Outcome</b>), the rule <b>Confidence</b> and <b>Weight</b> information and optionally the <b>Record count</b> (for how many rows did the ruleset matched when created) and <b>Number of correct</b> values where the outcome of the rule matched the expected label when the model was created.</outPort>
        <!-- possibly more output ports here-->
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
