<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd" >
<knimeNode icon="columnAggregator.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Column Aggregator</name>
    <shortDescription>
    	Groups the selected columns per row and aggregates their cells using the 
    	selected aggregation method.
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
    	<intro>
    	   <p>
    	    Groups the selected columns per row and aggregates their cells 
    	    using the selected aggregation method.
           </p>
           <p>
            To change the name of the new created aggregation column double
            click on the name column.
           </p>
           <p>
            A detailed description of the available aggregation methods can be
            found on the 'Description' tab in the node dialog.
   		   </p>
    	</intro>
    	<tab name="Columns">
	        <option name="Columns">
	            Select one or more column to aggregate.
	        </option>
	        <option name="Enforce exclusion">
                Select this option to enforce the current exclusion list to stay 
                the same even if the input table specification changes. 
                If some of the excluded columns are not available anymore, 
                a warning is displayed. 
                (New columns will automatically be added to the inclusion list.)
            </option>
	        <option name="Enforce inclusion">
	            Select this option to enforce the current inclusion list to stay 
	            the same even if the input table specification changes. 
	            If some of the included columns are not available anymore, 
	            a warning is displayed. 
	            (New columns will automatically be added to the exclusion list.)
	        </option>
	    </tab>
	    <tab name="Options">
       <option name="Aggregation settings">
            Select one or more aggregation method from the available 
            method list. Only methods that are compatible to the selected 
            aggregation columns are displayed.
            Change the name of the aggregation column by double clicking
            the name cell. You can add the same method multiple
            times. However you have to change the name of the result column.
            Tick the missing box to include missing values. This option might
            be disabled if the aggregation method does not support missing
            values.
            The parameter column shows an "Edit" button for all 
            aggregation operators that require additional information. 
            Clicking on the "Edit" button opens the parameter dialog 
            which allows changing the operator specific settings.
        </option>
        <option name="Remove aggregation column">
            Select this option to remove the selected aggregation columns from
            the result table.
        </option>
        <option name="Remove retained column">
            Select this option to remove the retained columns from the 
            result table.
        </option>
        <option name="Maximum unique values per row">
	        Defines the maximum number of unique values per row to avoid 
	        problems with memory overloading. All row with more unique
	        values are skipped during the calculation and a missing value is set 
            in the corresponding row, and a warning is displayed.
        </option>
        <option name="Value delimiter">
            The value delimiter used by aggregation methods such as concatenate. 
        </option>
        <option name="Revert selected names">
            This option is available in the context menu and reverts the name
            of the result columns of the selected methods to their default names.
        </option>
        <option name="Missing">
            Missing values are considered during aggregation if the missing 
            option is ticked for the corresponding row in the column 
            aggregation table.
            Some aggregation methods do not support the changing of the missing
            option such as means.
        </option>
      </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Data table">
	        The input table to aggregate.
        </inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Table with aggregation columns">
        	Result table with the aggregation columns per row.
		</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
