<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./rowfilter.gif" type="Manipulator">
	<name>Row Filter</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Allows filtering of datarows by certain criteria, such as row ID, 
		attribute value, and row number range.  
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>The node allows for row filtering according to certain criteria. 
		It can include
 		or exclude: certain ranges (by row number), rows with
 		a certain row ID, and rows with a certain value in a
 		selectable column (attribute). Below are the steps on how to configure the node
 		in its configuration dialog. Note: The node doesn't change the domain of the 
 		data table. I. e. the upper and lower bounds or the possible values in the
 		table spec are not adapted, even if one of the bounds or one value is
 		fully filtered out. 
		</intro>

		<option name="In- or exclude rows by criteria">You must first select which criteria should
		 be used for filtering from the left-hand side. Also choose
			whether to include or exclude rows according to the selected criteria. 
			Depending on the choice, you will then have to adjust the filter parameters in the right-hand panel.
		</option>
		<option name="Column value matching">If filter by attribute value is 
			selected, select the name of the column whose value should be matched. Then,
			either enter a pattern for string matching, or a value range,
			for range filtering. When using a pattern match, you can set checkmarks
			according to whether the pattern contains wildcards or is a regular 
			expression. Wildcard patterns contain '*' (matching any sequence of
			characters) and '.' (matching any one character). Examples of regular
			expressions are given below. Also, a case sensitive match can be enabled
			by the according checkmark. Note: if you select a pattern from the drop-down
			menu of the pattern text field, the node still performs a comparison of
			the string representation of the data values.<br />
			If a range is specified, and you specify only one boundary, the other 
			is then set to (plus or minus) infinity. <br />
			Here are some examples of regular expressions:<br />
			"<tt>$foo.*</tt>" matches anything that starts with "foo". The dollar
			stands for the beginning of the word, the dot matches any (one) character,
			and the asterisk allows any number (including zero) of the previous character.<br />
			"<tt>[0-9]*</tt>" matches any string of digits (including the empty string).
			The <tt>[</tt> <tt>]</tt> define a set of characters (they could be
			added individually like <tt>[0123456789]</tt>, or by range). This set
			matches any (one) character included in the set.<br />
            For a complete explanation of regular expressions see e.g. the JavaDoc
            of the <tt>java.util.regex.Pattern</tt> class.
		</option>
	    <option name="Row number range">If filter by range is selected, specify
		    the first row number to in/exclude. The end of the range can either 
		    be specified by row number, or set to the end of the table, causing 
		    all remaining rows to be in/excluded.
		</option>
	    <option name="Row ID pattern">If filter by row ID is selected, specify
	    	a regular expression, which is matched against the row ID of each row.
	    	A checkmark can be set, if a case sensitive match should be performed
	    	and if the row ID should start with the specified pattern.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<dataIn index="0" name="To be filtered">Datatable from which to filter rows.</dataIn>
		<dataOut index="0" name="Filtered">Datatable with rows meeting the specified criteria</dataOut>
	</ports>	
</knimeNode>