<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./missing.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Missing Value</name>
    <shortDescription>Filters or replaces missing values in a table.</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
	        This node helps handle missing values found in cells of the input table.
		    The first tab in the dialog (labeled "Default") provides default handling
		    options for all columns of a given type 
		    (i.e. Double, String, Integer, and all other unknown column types). 
		    These settings apply to all columns in the input table that are not
		    explicitly mentioned in the second tab, labeled "Individual". This
		    second tab permits individual settings for each available column 
		    (thus, overriding the default). To make use of this second approach,
		    select a column or a list of columns (with the same type) which needs
		    extra handling, click "Add", and set the parameters. To remove this 
		    extra handling (and instead use the default handling), click the 
		    "Remove" button for this column. The possible options are summarized
		    below:
		</intro>
        <option name="Do nothing">
	        The missing values are retained, i.e. those missing cells are not 
			touched and will occur - as they are - in the output table.	
			This option is available for all column types.
		</option>
		<option name="Remove row">
			Any row that contains a missing value for this type, will be completely
			removed and will not be contained in the output table.
			This option is available for all column types.
		</option>
		<option name="Min, Max, or Mean">
			Missing values are replaced by either min, max, or the mean value in
			this column. This option is only available for numeric column types, i.e.
			Double or Integer. The Mean for integer columns is rounded.
	    </option>
		<option name="Most Frequent">
			This option is available for string and integer columns and replaces
			any occurrence of a missing value with the most frequent value in
			a column. If two (or more) different values occur equally often, 
			the first value being encountered is used. If a column contains 
			only missing values, the column stays untouched (containing only 
			missing values in the output table). 
	    </option>
		<option name="Fix Value">
			Replaces the missing values with a static value set by the user. 
			This option is available for Double, Integer, and String columns.
	    </option>
	</fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Table with missing values">Table potentially containing missing values.</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Corrected table">Table where missing values have been handled.</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
