<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./constvalcolfilter.png" type="Manipulator">
	<name>Constant Value Column Filter</name>
	<shortDescription> The Constant Value Column Filter filters columns
		containing only duplicates of the same value. 
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro> This node filters columns exclusively containing duplicates of
			the same value from the input data table. Examples include a column
			containing only zeroes, a column containing only identical Strings,
			or a column comprising only missing cells. In a dialog window, you
			can select which columns to apply the filter to (with all columns
			selected by default). From these selected columns, you can choose to
			remove either all constant value columns or columns containing only
			specific constant numeric, String, or missing values. Finally, you
			can also specify the minimum number of rows a table must have to be
			considered for filtering.
		</intro>
		<option
			name="Remove from the selected columns all constant value columns"> Select this option to remove all constant value columns from
			the columns selected in the Column Selection tab, independent of the
			specific value they contain in duplicates.
		</option>
		<option
			name="Remove from the selected columns constant value columns that only contain numeric values of"> Select this option to remove columns containing only a specific
			numeric value from the columns selected in the Column Selection tab.
		</option>
		<option
			name="Remove from the selected columns constant value columns that only contain String values of"> Select this option to remove columns containing only a specific
			String value from the columns selected in the Column Selection tab.
		</option>
		<option
			name="Remove from the selected columns constant value columns that only contain missing values"> Select this option to remove columns containing only empty
			cells / missing values from the columns selected in the Column
			Selection tab.
		</option>
		<option name="Minimum number of rows"> The minimum number of rows a table must have to
			be considered for filtering. If the table size is below the specified
			value, the table will not be filtered / altered.
		</option>
		<option name="Apply filter"> This list contains the column names of the input
			table that are to be considered for filtering.
		</option>
		<option name="Enforce Inclusion"> Select this option to enforce the current "Apply
			filter" list to stay the same even if the input table specification
			changes. If some of the listed columns are not available anymore, a
			warning is displayed. (New columns will automatically be added to the
			"Do not apply filter" list.)
		</option>
		<option name="Do not apply filter (retain column)"> This list contains the column names of the input
			table that are passed to the output without undergoing filtering.
		</option>
		<option name="Enforce Exclusion"> Select this option to enforce the current "Do not
			apply filter" list to stay the same even if the input table
			specification changes. If some of the listed columns are not
			available anymore, a warning is displayed. (New columns will
			automatically be added to the "Apply filter" list.)
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Table to be filtered"> Table from which columns are to be
			filtered.
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Filtered table"> Table excluding filtered columns.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>