<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./constvalcolfilter.png" type="Manipulator">
	<name>Constant Value Column Filter</name>
	<shortDescription> The Constant Value Column Filter filters columns
		containing only duplicates of the same value. 
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro> This node filters columns containing only duplicates of the
			same value from the input data table. Examples include a column
			containing only zeroes, a column containing only identical Strings,
			or a column comprising only empty / missing cells. In a dialog
			window, the user can specify whether to filter only columns with a
			specific constant numeric value or String, columns containing only
			missing values, or all constant columns. In addition, the user can
			choose which columns to consider for filtering. Columns excluded in
			this dialog are passed even if they contain only identical values.
		</intro>
		<option name="Filter all constant value columns"> Select this option to filter all constant value
			columns independent of the value they contain in duplicates.
		</option>
		<option name="Filter constant value columns with numeric value"> Select this option to filter columns containing
			only a specific numeric value.
		</option>
		<option name="Filter constant value columns with String value"> Select this option to filter columns containing
			only a specific String value.
		</option>
		<option name="Filter constant value columns with missing value"> Select this option to filter columns containing
			only empty cells / missing values.
		</option>
		<option name="Include"> This list contains the column names of the input
			table that are to be considered for filtering.
		</option>
		<option name="Enforce Inclusion"> Select this option to enforce the current
			inclusion list to stay the same even if the input table specification
			changes. If some of the included columns are not available anymore, a
			warning is displayed. (New columns will automatically be added to the
			exclusion list.)
		</option>
		<option name="Exclude"> This list contains the column names of the input
			table that are passed to the output without undergoing filtering.
		</option>
		<option name="Enforce Exclusion"> Select this option to enforce the current
			exclusion list to stay the same even if the input table specification
			changes. If some of the excluded columns are not available anymore, a
			warning is displayed. (New columns will automatically be added to the
			inclusion list.)
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Table to be filtered"> Table from which
			columns are to be filtered.
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Filtered table"> Table excluding
			filtered columns.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>