<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./ColumnAutoTypeCaster.png" type="Manipulator">
	<name>Column Auto Type Cast</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Converts a column of type String to a Numeric or Date
		type, if and only if all entries could be converted.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
            This node determines the most specific type in the configured string columns and changes the column
            types accordingly. The type order is to first check if the values are dates, then integer, long, double, and
            finally string. For dates a custom format can be specified.
		</intro>

		<option name="Include">This list contains the column names which will get
			converted if possible.
		</option>
		<option name="Enforce Inclusion">Select this option to enforce the current
			inclusion list to stay the same even if the input table specification
			changes. If some of the included columns are not available anymore, a
			warning is displayed. (New columns will automatically be added to the
			exclusion list.)
		</option>
		<option name="Select">Use these buttons to move columns between the
			Include and Exclude list.
		</option>
		<option name="Exclude">
			This list contains the column names that are
			included in the output table without modification.
		</option>
		<option name="Enforce Exclusion">Select this option to enforce the current
			exclusion list to stay the same even if the input table specification
			changes. If some of the excluded columns are not available anymore, a
			warning is displayed. (New columns will automatically be added to the
			inclusion list.)
		</option>
		<option name="Choose a date format">Choose or enter a date pattern. (y: Year, M: Month
			in year, d: Day in month, H: Hour in day, m: Minute in hour, s:
			Second in minute, S: Millisecond)
		</option>
		<option name="Missing value pattern">Choose or enter a missing value pattern. &lt;none&gt; is the default pattern 
			and &lt;empty&gt; represents the empty string. The entered string pattern is applied to all included columns.		
		</option>
		<option name="Quickscan">Check this checkbox if you want to speed up the node. The node will determine the 
			most specific type based on the first 1000 rows. 1000 is the default for the "number of rows to consider" 
			field. <br/>
			Note: With quickscan enabled this node could fail during execute. 
		</option>
	</fullDescription>


	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Input">Arbitrary input data.</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Type-casted columns">
			Input data with type-casted columns.
		</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="Type information">Information about the chosen type casting.</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
