<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Other" icon="./entropyscore.png">
	<name>Entropy Scorer</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Scorer for clustering results given a reference clustering.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			Scorer for clustering results given a reference clustering.
			Connect the table containing the reference clustering to the
			first input port (the table should contain a column with the
			cluster IDs) and the table with the clustering results to
			the second input port (it should also contain a column with
			some cluster IDs). Select the respective columns in both
			tables from the dialog. After successful execution, the view
			will show entropy values (the smaller the better) and some
			quality value (in [0,1] - with 1 being the best possible
			value, as used in
			<a
				href="http://www.inf.uni-konstanz.de/bioml2/publications/Papers2007/WiBe07_fcum_ijar.pdf">
				Fuzzy Clustering in Parallel Universes
			</a>
			, section 6: "Experimental results").
		</intro>
		<option name="Reference column">
			Column containing the reference clustering. This column is
			provided by the first input table.
		</option>
		<option name="Clustering column">
			Column containing the cluster IDs to evaluate. This column
			is provided by the second input table.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<dataIn index="0" name="Reference clustering">
			Table containing reference clustering.
		</dataIn>
		<dataIn index="1" name="Clustering to score">
			Table containing clustering (to score).
		</dataIn>
		<dataOut index="0" name="Quality Table">
			Table containing entropy values for each cluster. The last row
			contains statistics on the entire clustering. It corresponds to
			the table show in the Statistics View.
		</dataOut>
	</ports>
	<views>
		<view index="0" name="Statistics View">
			Simple statistics on the clustering such as number of
			clusters being found, number of objects in clusters, number
			of reference clusters, and total number of objects. Further
			statistics include:
			<ul>
				<li>
					Entropy: The accumulated entropy of all identified
					clusters, weighted by the relative cluster size. The
					entropy is not normalized and may be greater than 1.
				</li>
				<li>
					Quality: The quality value according to the formula
					referenced above. It is the sum of the weighted
					qualities of the individual clusters, whereby the
					quality of a single cluster is calculated as (1 -
					normalized_entropy). The domain of the quality value
					is [0,1].
				</li>
			</ul>
			The table at the bottom of the view provides statistics on
			<i>cluster size</i>, <i>cluster entropy</i>, 
			<i>normalized cluster entropy</i> and <i>quality</i>. The
			<i>entropy</i> of a clusters is based on the reference clustering (provided
			at the first input port) and the <i>normalized entropy</i>
			is this value scaled to an interval [0, 1]. More precisely,
			it is the entropy divided by log2(number of different
			clusters in the reference set). The quality value is only available
			in the last row (showing the overall statistics).
		</view>
	</views>
</knimeNode>
