<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./binner.gif" type="Manipulator">
	<name>Numeric Binner</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
	    Group values of numeric columns categorized string type.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>		
	    For each column a number of intervals - known as bins - can be defined. 
	    Each of these bins is given a unique name (for this column), a defined 
	    range, and open or closed interval borders. They automatically ensure 
	    that the ranges are defined in descending order and that interval 
	    borders are consistent. In addition, each column is either replaced with
	    the binned, string-type column, or a new binned, string-type column 
	    is appended.
		</intro>
		
		<option name="Select Column: ">
		First select a column (left side) and then use the "Add" button (right 
		side) to create the desired number of bins. Each bin can be modified in 
		the lower part of this panel once it has been selected.
        Each interval has to be defined independently or can be removed using
        the "Remove" button. Note that the range as well as the bin borders can
        be automatically adjusted, if necessary.
        The first bin's left and the last bin's right value are 
        automatically defined to infinitely cover the entire numeric axes in 
        this direction. Furthermore, each bin's left and right value can be 
        included or excluded from this bin by selecting the desired bracket:
        '[' or ']'.
        
		</option>
		<option name="Append new column: ">
		If selected, a new column name can be specified. This name is given to 
		the new binned column that is appended to the table; the input column 
		remains unchanged in the data.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<dataIn index="0" name="Input Data">Data to define bins</dataIn>
		<dataOut index="0" name="Binned Data">Data with bins defined</dataOut>
	</ports>	
</knimeNode>