<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./loop_start_column.png" type="LoopStart" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.6" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.6 http://knime.org/node/v3.6.xsd">
    <name>Column List Loop Start</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Iterates over a list of columns
	</shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>This loop starting node iterates over a list of columns of the input table.
            Its columns are divided into two sets, the "excluded" columns will always be included in any iteration,
            the "included" columns will be visible once in each iteration.
		</intro>
        <option name="Column Filter">
            Choose the columns to iterate over -- each column that matches the include criteria defines 
            one iteration (so the loop will run as often as there are columns included). Columns excluded are considered
            static and will always be passed into the loop body.
        </option>
        <option name="If include column list is empty">
            Define the behavior how to treat an empty input list. Two options are available: "Run one iteration" will
            execute the loop body once with all "excluded" columns passed unmodified into the loop body (so all columns
            in the input table). "Fail" will cause no loop iteration to be run; instead the loop start node will fail
            with an appropriate error message. The latter strictly follows the definition above -- so the number of
            iterations corresponds to the number of columns in the include filter.
        </option>
        <link href="https://www.knime.com/knime-introductory-course/chapter7/section2">
            KNIME E-Learning Course: Section 7.2. Re-executing Workflow Parts: Loops
        </link>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Any data table">The input data table</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Filtered columns">The input table with the included columns for each iteration only</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
