<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./enrichment.png" type="Visualizer">
    <name>Enrichment Plotter</name>
    <shortDescription>Draws enrichment curves</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This node draws enrichment curves often used in virtual screening. For this the user can choose a column by
            which the data is sorted and represents the x-axis. The values on the y-axis are formed by the sum of the
            hits in a second column that is also selected by the user. A row is considered a hit if the value is greater
            than 0. The steeper the resulting curve, the better the enrichment is. Optionally the y-axis can show the
            sum of the hit values instead of the number of hits.
            <br />
            The two gray lines in the view show the enrichment if the data points were ordered randomly (lower diagonal)
            and the optimal enrichment if all hits are ordered before the first non-hit (upper diagonal).
        </intro>

        <option name="Sort column">
            Select the column by which the rows should be sorted and plotted as the x-axis.
        </option>
        <option name="Hit column">Select the column that contains the hit values.</option>
        <option name="Sort descending">
            Checking this before adding a curve sorts the data points in the sort column descendingly instead if
            ascendingly. This is a setting specific to each curve.
        </option>
        <option name="Plot sum of hit values">
            Check this if the y-axis should show the sum of the values in the hit column.
        </option>
        <option name="Hit threshold">
            Check this and enter a threshold if the y-axis should show the sum of data points that have values equal or
            greater than the threshold.
        </option>
        <option name="Minimum molecules per cluster">
            If discovered clusters are plotted, this setting controls how many molecules from the
            cluster must have been found before the whole clusters is considered "found".
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <dataIn index="0" name="Input table">Input data with predicted values and actual values</dataIn>
        <dataOut index="0" name="Areas under curve">
            A one-column table with the area(s) under the enrichment curve(s)
        </dataOut>
        <dataOut index="1" name="Discovery rates">
            Table with the discovery rates (either hits or clusters) for the different curves at selected points (given
            as fraction of the complete dataset).
        </dataOut>
    </ports>
    <views>
        <view index="0" name="Enrichment Plot">Enrichment plot</view>
    </views>
</knimeNode>
