<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./linear_regression_learn.png" type="Learner">
    <name>Linear Regression (Learner)</name>
    <shortDescription>Performs a multivariate linear regression.</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
	        Performs a multivariate linear regression. Select in the dialog a 
			target column (combo box on top), i.e. the response. The two
			lists in the center of the dialog allow you to include only certain 
			(numeric) columns which represent the (independent) variables.
			Make sure the columns you want to have included being in the right
			"include" list. The checkbox at the bottom controls whether or not the error
			on the training data should be computed. The error value is then 
			available in the view. Calculating the error requires performing one extra scan on
			the data. <br/>
			Additionally, specify the rows that shall be available in the view. Specify
			the first row number and the total count.
		</intro>
	</fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <dataIn index="0" name="Input data">Table on which to perform regression.</dataIn>
        <modelOut index="0" name="Model for Predictor">Model to connect to a predictor node.</modelOut>
	</ports>
	<views>
		<view index="0" name="Linear Regression Result View">
			Displays statistics and the parameters of the resulting
			hyperplane.
		</view>
		<view index="1" name="Linear Regression Scatterplot View">
			Displays the input data along with the regression line in a 
			scatterplot. The y-coordinate is fixed to the response column
			(the column that has been approximated) while the x-column can be
			chosen in the view. Note: If you have multiple input
			variables, this view is only an approximation. It will fix the value
			of each variable that is not shown in the view to its mean. Thus, 
			this view generally only makes sense if you only have a few input variables.
		</view>
	</views>
</knimeNode>
