<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./timemissvalue.png" type="Other">
    <name>Time Series Missing Value</name>
    <shortDescription>This node handles missing values in a time series.
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
	        This node helps handle missing values found in cells of the input 
	        time series data. The first tab in the dialog (labeled "Default") provides 
	        default handling options for all numerical and non-numerical column. 
		    These settings apply to all columns in the input table that are not
		    explicitly mentioned in the second tab, labeled "Individual". This
		    second tab permits individual settings for each available column 
		    (thus, overriding the default). To make use of this second approach,
		    select a column or a list of columns (with the same type) which needs
		    extra handling, click "Add", and set the parameters. Click on the 
		    label with the column name(s), will select all covered columns 
		    in the column list. To remove this extra handling (and instead use 
		    the default handling), click the "Remove" button for this column. 
		    The possible options are summarized below:</intro>
        <option name="Do Nothing">
	        The missing values are retained, i.e. those missing cells are not 
			touched and will occur - as they are - in the output table.	
			This option is available for all column types.
		</option>
		
        <option name="Next">
        The missing values are replaced with the next found non missing cell. 
        Missings at the end of the table will remain missings.
			This option is available for all column types.
		</option>
		
        <option name="Last">
        The missing values are replaced with the last seen non missing cell. 
        Missings at the beginning of the table will remain missings.
			This option is available for all column types.
		</option>
		
        <option name="Average">
        The missing values are replaced with the average between the last and next found non missing cell. 
        Missings at the beginning of the table are assigned the first non missing and missings 
        at the end of the table are assigned the last non missing cell.	
			This option is available for all Int, Double, Long and Date/Time columns.
		</option>
		
        <option name="Linear">
        The missing values are replaced with a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linear_interpolation">
        linear interpolation</a> between the most recent and next observed non 
        missing cells. On either end of the table, leading missing values are assigned the first non missing value and
         trailing missing values are assigned the last seen value.	
			This option is available for all Int, Double, Long and Date/Time columns.
		</option>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <inPort name="Times series with missings" index="0">Time series potentially containing missing values.</inPort>
        <outPort name="TimeSeries without missings" index="0">Time series where missing values have been handled.</outPort>
    </ports>

</knimeNode>