<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./java_editvar.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Java Edit Variable (Heiko)</name>
    <shortDescription>Edit a flow variable using java code.</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>
              Edit a flow variable using java code. The node is analogous to
              the Java Snippet node: In the central panel, added java code
              to add or modify variables. The variables available
              at the input are listed on the left.
            </p>
        </intro>
        <option name="Flow Variable List">
          The list contains the flow variables that are currently available at
          the node input. Double clicking any of the entries will insert the
          respective identifier at the current cursor position (replacing the
          selection, if any).
        </option>
        <option name="Snippet text area">
          Enter your java code here. You can access input flow
          variables by defining them in the <b>Snippet fields for input</b>. A
          second way is to use the method <i>getFlowVariable(name, type)</i> 
          where <i>name</i> is the name of the flow variable, respectively. 
          You can use the following values for the <i>type</i> parameter. <br/>          
          <i>String</i> : String <br/>
          <i>Int</i>  : Integer <br/>
          <i>Double</i> : Double <br/>
          <p>Please define output flow variables by adding columns
          to <b>Snippet fields for output</b>. Values assigned to those field
          in the snippet text area will show up at the output.
          </p>
          <p>The snippet allows to define custom global variables and
          custom imports.</p>
        </option>
        <option name="Snippet fields for input">
          Define system input fields for the snippet text area. Every field 
          represents a flow variable of the input. 
        </option>
        <option name="Snippet fields for output">
          Define flow variables that will be added to stack of flow variables
          at the output.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <inPort name="Input variables (optional)" index="0">
            Input variables (optional).</inPort>
        <outPort name="Output variables" index="0">
            Output variables.
        </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
