<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./java_snippet.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Java Snippet</name>
    <shortDescription>Calculates a new columns or flow variables based on 
    java code snippets.</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>This node allows you to execute arbitrary java code to create
            a new columns or to replace an existing ones. Enter the java code in 
            the text area.</p>
            <p>An output columns is defined by creating a java field bound to 
            this column. The value assigned to this field will be written
            to the output.</p>
            <p>Note, that this node allows to add or modify flow variables
            in the same manner.</p>
        </intro>
        <option name="Column List">
          The list contains the columns that are available in the input table.
          Double click any of the column names to insert the respective field
          in the expression editor. It will replace your current selection or
          simply insert at the current caret position.
        </option>
        <option name="Flow Variable List">
          The list contains the flow variables that are currently available at
          the node input. Double clicking any of the entries will insert the
          respective identifier at the current cursor position (replacing the
          selection, if any).
        </option>
        <option name="Snippet text area">
          Enter your java code here. You can access input columns or flow
          variables by defining them in the <b>Input</b> table. A
          second way is to use the methods <i>getCell(name, type)</i> or 
          <i>getFlowVariable(name, type)</i> where <i>name</i> is the name of
          the input column or the flow variable, respectively. You can use
          the following values for the <i>type</i> parameter. <br/>          
          <i>String</i> : String (f)<br/>
          <i>Int</i>  : Integer (f)<br/>
          <i>Double</i> : Double (f)<br/>
          <i>Long</i> : Long<br/>
          <i>Boolean</i> : Boolean<br/>
          <i>Date</i> : java.util.Date<br/>
          <i>Calendar</i> : java.util.Calendar<br/>
          <i>XML</i> : org.w3c.document<br/>
          (f) These Types can be used for flow variables.
          
          <br/>
          <b>Java Snippet Methods:</b><br/>
          <i>getCell(name, type)*</i> : Get value of a cell by column name<br/>
          <i>isType(name, type)*</i> : Test for type by column name<br/>
          <i>isMissing(name, type)*</i> : Check if missing by column name<br/>
          <i>getColumnCount(index, type)</i>  : Number of columns in the input table<br/>
          <i>getColumnName(index)</i>  : Retrieve column name at index<br/>
          <br/>
          <i>getFlowVariable(name, type)</i> : Get value of a flow variable by name<br/>
          * Methods exist in a variant that takes the column index instead of its name.
          
          <p>You can hit <i>ctrl+space</i> to get an auto completion box with all
          available classes, methods and fields. When you select a class and hit
          <i>enter</i> a import statement will be generated if missing.</p>          
          <p>Note, that the snippet allows to define custom global variables and
          custom imports.</p>  
        </option>
        <option name="Input">
          Define system input fields for the snippet text area. Every field will 
          be populated with the data of the defined input during execution. 
        </option>
        <option name="Output">
          To define output columns and flow variables by adding columns
          to this table. Every row in the <b>Output</b> table
          defines a java field bound to a column. Values assigned to this field
          in the snippet will show up at the output.          
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <inPort name="Any input table" index="0">Input table.</inPort>
        <outPort name="Appended table" index="0">Input table with additional 
        or replaced columns.
        </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
