<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="variable_condition_loop_end.png" type="LoopEnd">
    <name>Variable Condition Loop End</name>

    <shortDescription>Loop end node that check for a condition in one of the flow variables</shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            In combination with a "Variable Condition Loop (Start)" node, this node lets you execute the body of the
            loop until a certain condition on one of the flow variables is met. In the dialog you can choose one of the
            available flow variables and which condition should cause the loop to finish.
        </intro>
        <option name="Available variables">
            In the list you can select one of the available flow variables. Below the list, you can choose, when the
            loop's execution should be finished, i.e. when the selected variable is, equal, greater, greater or equal,
            smaller, or smaller or equal than the given value. For string variables only the check for equality is
            possible.
        </option>
        <option name="Collect rows from last iteration">
            The default is to collect the rows from all the loop's iterations, including the last one after which the
            loop is stopped. If you de-select this option, the rows from the last iteration are not added to the output
            table.
        </option>
        <option name="Collect rows from last iteration only">
            If only the rows from the very last iteration should be collected, you have to enable this option.
        </option>
        <option name="Add iteration column">
            Allows you to add a column containing the iteration number to the output table.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Any datatable">Any datatable</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Collected results">Collected results from the loop body</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Variable values">The selected flow variable's values in each iteration</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
