<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Sink" icon="./db_delete.png">
	<name>Database Delete</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
	    Deletes the selected rows in the database based on the selected columns from the input table. 
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>		
	     Deletes data rows in the database based on the selected columns from the input table.
	     All selected column names need to exactly match the column names inside the database. Only the rows matching
	     the values of the selected column will be deleted. The output table contains an additional column with the 
	     number of rows affected by the DELETE statement.
	     <br/>
         The output table contains an additional column with the number of rows affected by the UPDATE statement. 
         A number greater than or equal to zero -- indicates that the command was processed successfully and is 
         an update count giving the number of rows in the database that were affected by the command's execution
         A value of -2 -- indicates that the command was processed successfully but that the number of rows affected 
         is unknown.    
	     <br/>
	     Make sure you have your vendor-specific database driver registered in
         the KNIME preference page (section Database Driver). By default, the 
         sun.jdbc.odbc.JdbcOdbcDriver (Windows and Linux) is only available.
		</intro>

    <tab name="Settings">
	  <option name="Database Driver">
		Enter the database driver here; it is a Java class (including the
		package path), for example: sun.jdbc.odbc.JdbcOdbcDriver
		Additional driver can be registered via KNIME's preference page
        (Database Driver).
	  </option>
	  <option name="Database URL">
        Enter the database name here, for example: 
        jdbc:odbc:database_name or jdbc:mysql://host:port/database_name
	  </option>
	  <option name="Workflow Credentials">
        If checked, the credentials (user and password) are used as defined on 
        the workflow. The credential name links to the specified user and 
        password. Those can be replaced or edit using the 'Workflow Credentials'
        menu available in the workflow context menu.
      </option>
	  <option name="User Name">
        Your log-in user name for the database.
	  </option>
	  <option name="Password">
        Your log-in password for the database. Note, the password is
        de- and encrypted before handling it internally and is not 
        stored inside the settings.
	  </option>
	  <option name="Table Name">
        Enter the name of the table in which rows should be deleted.
	  </option>
    </tab>
    <tab name="Column Selection">
	  <option name="WHERE columns">
        Select all columns used for the WHERE clause of the DELETE statement; 
        those column values need to match the corresponding value in the database 
        in order to run the delete. 
      </option>
    </tab>
    <tab name="Advance">
        <option name="Batch Size">
           Enter a number greater than 0 for the number of rows deleted in one batch job; 1 means on row at a time.
        </option>
    </tab>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Data to delete row in Database">
			Table with data rows to be deleted in the database
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Input Data with Delete Status">
            Input table with additional column providing number of affected rows in the database.
        </outPort>
	</ports>	
</knimeNode>