<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Source" icon="./db_reader.png">
	<name>Database Reader</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
	    Establishes and opens a database access connection to read a table from.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>		
	     Establishes and opens a database access connection to read data from.
	     <br/>
	     Make sure you have your vendor-specific database driver registered in
         the KNIME preference page (section Database Driver). By default, the 
         sun.jdbc.odbc.JdbcOdbcDriver (Windows and Linux) is only available.
		</intro>
		
	<option name="Database driver">
		Enter the database driver here; it is a Java class (including the
		package path), for example: sun.jdbc.odbc.JdbcOdbcDriver
		Additional driver can be registered via KNIME's preference page
		(Database Driver).
	</option>
	<option name="Database URL">
        Enter the database name here, for example 
        jdbc:odbc:database_name or jdbc:mysql://host:port/database_name
	</option>
	<option name="Workflow Credentials">
        If checked, the credentials (user and password) are used as defined on 
        the workflow. The credential name links to the specified user and 
        password. Those can be replaced or edit using the 'Workflow Credentials'
        menu available in the workflow context menu.
    </option>
	<option name="User name">
        Your log-in user name for the database.
	</option>
	<option name="Password">
        Your log-in password for the database. Note, the password is
        de- and encrypted before handling it internally.
	</option>
	<option name="SQL Statement">
        Enter SQL statement being execute here, for example SELECT * FROM table
	</option>
	<option name="Run SQL query without configure">
        The SQL query is execute as it is without accessing the meta info
        from the database during configure which result in an empty spec 
        after configure.
    </option>
	<option name="Flow Variable List">
        The list contains the flow variables that are currently available at
        the node input. Double clicking any of the entries will insert the
        respective identifier at the current cursor position (replacing the
        selection, if any).
    </option>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<outPort index="0" name="Data from Database">Table with data read from the database</outPort>
	</ports>	
</knimeNode>