<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Source" icon="./db_connector.png">
	<name>Database Connector</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
	    Creates a database connection to the specified database.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>		
	     Creates a database connection to the specified database. Note, this 
	     node does only open the connection to read the meta information, but
	     does not read any data at this point.
	     <br/>
	     Make sure you have your vendor-specific database driver registered in
         the KNIME preference page (section Database Driver). By default, the 
         sun.jdbc.odbc.JdbcOdbcDriver (Windows and Linux) is only available.
		</intro>
		
	<option name="Database Driver">
		Enter the database driver here; it is a Java class (including the
		package path), for example: sun.jdbc.odbc.JdbcOdbcDriver
		Additional driver can be registered via KNIME's preference page
        (Database Driver).
	</option>
	<option name="Database URL">
        Enter the database name here, for example 
        jdbc:odbc:database_name or jdbc:mysql://host:port/database_name
	</option>
	<option name="Workflow Credentials">
        If checked, the credentials (user and password) are used as defined on 
        the workflow. The credential name links to the specified user and 
        password. Those can be replaced or edit using the 'Workflow Credentials'
        menu available in the workflow context menu.
    </option>
	<option name="User Name">
        Your log-in user name for the database.
	</option>
	<option name="Password">
        Your log-in password for the database. Note, the password is
        de- and encrypted before handling it internally.
	</option>
	<option name="SQL Statement">
        Enter the SQL-like query here, for example SELECT * FROM table.
        <br/>
        Additional SQL commands (create, drop, set parameter, etc.) can be 
        arrange in front of the actual SELECT statement and are execute 
        together line-by-line during configure and execute. Note, those 
        additional SQL commands need to be separated by semicolon.
	</option>
    <option name="Database Browser">
        Click <i>Fetch Metadata</i> to connect to the database using the
        entered settings and to fetch all tables and display them grouped by 
        type in a tree view.
        Click on any table to retrieve all contained columns. Double-click on a table 
        or column to insert its name into the SQL query at the current 
        cursor position.
    </option>
	<option name="Flow Variable List">
       The list contains the flow variables that are currently available at
       the node input. Double clicking any of the entries will insert the
       respective identifier at the current cursor position (replacing the
       selection, if any).
    </option>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<outPort index="0" name="Database Connection">Database connection object</outPort>
	</ports>	
</knimeNode>