<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Sink" icon="./db_update.png">
	<name>Database Update</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
	    Writes the input table into a database while updating the given rows in the database. 
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>		
	     Writes the input table into a database while updating the given rows in the database.
	     All selected column names need to exactly match the column names inside the database.
	     <br/>
	     Make sure you have your vendor-specific database driver registered in
         the KNIME preference page (section Database Driver). By default, the 
         sun.jdbc.odbc.JdbcOdbcDriver (Windows and Linux) is only available.
		</intro>

    <tab name="Settings">
	  <option name="Database Driver">
		Enter the database driver here; it is a Java class (including the
		package path), for example: sun.jdbc.odbc.JdbcOdbcDriver
		Additional driver can be registered via KNIME's preference page
        (Database Driver).
	  </option>
	  <option name="Database URL">
        Enter the database name here, for example: 
        jdbc:odbc:database_name or jdbc:mysql://host:port/database_name
	  </option>
	  <option name="Workflow Credentials">
        If checked, the credentials (user and password) are used as defined on 
        the workflow. The credential name links to the specified user and 
        password. Those can be replaced or edit using the 'Workflow Credentials'
        menu available in the workflow context menu.
      </option>
	  <option name="User Name">
        Your log-in user name for the database.
	  </option>
	  <option name="Password">
        Your log-in password for the database. Note, the password is
        de- and encrypted before handling it internally and is not 
        stored inside the settings.
	  </option>
	  <option name="Table Name">
        Enter the name of the table in which the data should be updated.
	  </option>
    </tab>
    <tab name="Column Selection">
	  <option name="SET columns">
        Select all columns used for the SET clause of the UPDATE statement; 
        those column values are changing the data in the database. 
	  </option>
	  <option name="WHERE columns">
        Select all columns used for the WHERE clause of the UPDATE statement; 
        those column values need to match the corresponding value in the database 
        in order to make the update. 
      </option>
    </tab>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Data to update Database">
			Table with data to be updated in the database
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Input Data with Update Status">
            Input table with additional column providing update status received from the database
        </outPort>
	</ports>	
</knimeNode>