<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./rowID.png" type="Manipulator">
	<name>RowID</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
		Node to replace the RowID and/or to create a column with the values
		of the current RowID.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>		
		<p>This node can be used to replace the RowID of the input data with 
		the values of another column (by converting the values to a string) or
		a generated row id of the format: Row0, Row1, Row2, ... 
		The user has additional options to ensure uniqueness and to handle 
		missing values.</p>
		<p>
		It can also be used to create a new column, which contains the RowID
		as a value.</p>
		<p>If both options are selected the node appends a new column
		with the values of the current RowID to the table and replaces the 
		current RowID with the values of the selected column or the 
		generated row id.</p>
		<p><b>Note: Highlighting does not work across this node.</b></p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Replace RowID with selected column values">
		    If selected the node replaces each RowID with the corresponding
		    string value of the selected column or with a generated key.
	    </option>
		<option name="New RowID column: ">
			The column to replace the current RowID. If none is selected a
			row id is generated with the format: Row0, Row1, Row2, ...
	    </option>
		<option name="Ensure uniqueness">
			If checked the node ensures uniqueness by appending a counter (x) 
			to duplicates where x is incremented for each appearance.
	    </option>
		<option name="Handle missing values">
			All missing values are replaced with '?' if this check box is ticked.
			We recommend activating the 'Ensure uniqueness' check box to handle any duplicate missing values.
	    </option>
	    <option name="Enable hiliting">
            If enabled, a map is maintained joining the old with the new RowID. 
            Depending of the number of rows, enabling this feature might 
            consume a lot of memory.
        </option>
		<option name="Create new column with the RowID values">
			If this is selected the node creates a new column with the value of the 
			current RowID.
	    </option>
		<option name="New column name: ">
			The name of the new column that is being added to the table.
	    </option>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Data to process">
			The data table to be processed.
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Processed data">
			Data with the replaced RowID and/or a new column with the current RowID values.
		</outPort>
	</ports>	
</knimeNode>
