<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.10" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10"
	type="Manipulator" icon="outlier.png">
	<name>Outlier Detector</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Detects and handles outliers for all numerical
		columns.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>
				Detects and treats the outliers for each of the selected columns
				individually by means of
				<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Outlier#Tukey's_fences">interquartile range (IQR)</a>
				.
			</p>
			<p>
				To detect the outliers for a given column, the first and
				third
				quartile (Q<sub>1</sub>, Q<sub>3</sub>) is computed.
				An observation is flagged an outlier if it lies
				outside the range
				R = [Q<sub>1</sub> - k(IQR), Q<sub>3</sub> + k(IQR)] with
				IQR = Q<sub>3</sub> - Q<sub>1</sub>	and k &gt;= 0.
				Setting k = 1.5 the smallest value in R corresponds,
				typically, to the lower end of a boxplot's whisker and largest value
				to its upper end.
				<br />
				Additionally, providing grouping information allows to detect
				outliers only within their own group.
			</p>
			<p>
				If an observation is flagged an outlier, one can either remove
				the whole row from the data or replace it by some other value.
			</p>
			<p>
				Missing Values contained in the data will be ignored, i.e., they
				will neither be used for the outlier computation nor will they be
				flagged as an outlier.
			</p>
		</intro>
		<tab name="Outliers">
			<option name="Outlier settings">
				Allows to select the columns for which outliers have to be
				detected
				and treated. If "Compute outlier statistics on groups" is selected,
				the outliers for each of the columns are computed
				solely with respect
				to the different groups.
				<br />
				<br />
				<b>Options:</b>
				<ul>
					<li>
						<b>Include:</b>
						This list contains the column names for which the outliers have to
						be detected and treated.
					</li>
					<li>
						<b>Enforce Inclusion:</b>
						Select this option to enforce the current inclusion list to stay
						the same even if the input table specification changes. New
						columns will automatically be added to the exclusion list.
					</li>
					<li>
						<b>Select:</b>
						Use these buttons to move columns between the Include and Exclude
						list.
					</li>
					<li>
						<b>Search:</b>
						Use one of these fields to search either within the Include or
						Exclude list for certain column names or name substrings. Repeated
						clicking of the search button marks the next column that matches
						the search text. The check box 'Mark all search hits' causes all
						matching columns to be selected making them movable between the
						two lists.
					</li>
					<li>
						<b>Exclude:</b>
						This list contains the column names of the input table that are
						left out of the calculation.
					</li>
					<li>
						<b>Enforce Exclusion:</b>
						Select this option to enforce the current exclusion list to stay
						the same even if the input table specification changes. New
						columns will automatically be added to the inclusion list.
					</li>
				</ul>
			</option>

		</tab>
		<tab name="Groups">
			<option name="Group settings">
				Allows to select columns to identify groups. A group comprises all
				rows of the input exhibiting the same values in each of the columns.
				The outliers will finally be computed with respect to each of the
				individual groups.
				<br/>
				<br/>
				Note that if "Compute outlier statistics on groups" is not selected
				these settings will be ignored.

				<br/>
				<br/>
				<b>Options:</b>
				<ul>
					<li>
						<b>Include:</b>
						This list contains the column names for which the groups shall be
						formed.
					</li>
					<li>
						<b>Enforce Inclusion:</b>
						Select this option to enforce the current inclusion list to stay
						the same even if the input table specification changes. New
						columns will automatically be added to the exclusion list.
					</li>
					<li>
						<b>Select:</b>
						Use these buttons to move columns between the Include and Exclude
						list.
					</li>
					<li>
						<b>Search:</b>
						Use one of these fields to search either within the Include or
						Exclude list for certain column names or name substrings. Repeated
						clicking of the search button marks the next column that matches
						the search text. The check box 'Mark all search hits' causes all
						matching columns to be selected making them movable between the
						two lists.
					</li>
					<li>
						<b>Exclude:</b>
						This list contains the column names of the input table that are
						left out of the calculation.
					</li>
					<li>
						<b>Enforce Exclusion:</b>
						Select this option to enforce the current exclusion list to stay
						the same even if the input table specification changes. New
						columns will automatically be added to the inclusion list.
					</li>
				</ul>
			</option>

		</tab>

		<tab name="General settings">
			<option name="Compute outlier statistics on groups">
				Allows to specify groups via the "Group
				settings". If the outliers should not be computed on groups the
				included groups from the "Group settings" are being ignored.
			</option>

			<option name="IQR scalar">
				Allows to scale the interquartile range (IQR).
				The default is k = 1.5.
			</option>

			<option name="Process in memory">
				Process the table in the memory. Requires more
				memory, but is faster
				since the table does not need to be sorted in advance.
				If in memory is selected more accurate values of 
				Q<sub>1</sub> and Q<sub>3</sub>
				are computed, otherwise these quartiles will
				entirely be estimated
				irrespective of the selected "Estimation type".
				<br />
				<br />
				Note that the more accurate computation of the quartiles comes
				with higher memory requirements. If the additionally required memory
				exceeds the available memory this node will fail.
			</option>

			<option name="Estimation type">
				Typically the value of the quartiles is not part of the input, but
				lies between two observations. The estimation type allows to specify
				how to deal with this problem, e.g., by using linear-interpolation.
				A detailed explanation of the different options can be found
				<a
					href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantile#Estimating_quantiles_from_a_sample"> here</a>
			</option>

		</tab>

		<tab name="Outlier treatment">

			<option name="Treatment">
				Defines two different strategies to treat outliers:
				<ul>
					<li>
						<b>Replace Value:</b>
						Allows to replace outliers based on the selected "Replacement
						strategy"
					</li>
					<li>
						<b>Remove Row:</b>
						Removes all rows from the input data that contain in any of the
						selected columns at least one outlier
					</li>

				</ul>
			</option>

			<option name="Replacement strategy">
				Defines two different strategies to replace
				outliers:
				<ul>
					<li>
						<b>Missing values:</b>
						Replaces every outlier by a missing value
					</li>
					<li>
						<b>Closest allowed value:</b>
						Replaces the value of each outlier by the closest value within the
						allowed interval R. If the column type is an integer the
						replacement value is the closest integer within the allowed interval.
					</li>
				</ul>
			</option>

		</tab>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Numeric input data">Numeric input data to evaluate</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Outlier table">Data table where outliers are either
			replaced or rows containing outliers were removed
		</outPort>
	</ports>

</knimeNode>