<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./fixedPie.png" type="Visualizer">
    <name>Pie chart</name>    
    <shortDescription>
        Displays data in a pie chart. Hiliting is not supported.
    </shortDescription> 
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        <p>Displays a pie chart with different viewing options. Hiliting and
        changing of the pie and aggregation column on the fly is only supported 
        by the interactive pie chart.</p>
        <p>If the pie chart appears in gray no color information is set
        for the selected pie column. Use the 'Color Manager' node in order 
        to set the color appropriate.</p>
        <p>The user can change the following view properties on the fly:
            <ol>
            <li>Aggregation method (count, summary, average)</li>
            <li>Pie size</li>
            <li>Show missing value section</li>
            <li>Show pie section outline</li>
            <li>Draw selected section exploded</li>
            <li>Show details for selected sections</li>
            <li>Set value scale to percentage or original</li>
            <li>Pie size</li>
            <li>Explode size</li>
            </ol>
            Each distinct pie column value get its own colored section.
        </p>
        <p><b>Color selected sections:</b>
        If the color selected sections option is selected the pie displays also sub 
        sections for the selected sections. A sub section represents the rows
        color using the color manager. This option is only available if 
        row colors are set.</p>
        <p>This view is particularly well suited for extremely large datasets.
        For more interaction and hiliting support use the 
        "Pie chart (interactive)" node.</p>
        <p><b>The pie chart supports maximum 360 sections!</b></p>
        </intro>
        <option name="Display all rows">
            If selected the pie chart displays all rows of the incoming data.
        </option>
        <option name="No. of rows to display: ">
            Defines the number of rows to be displayed in the pie chart.
            This option is disabled if the 'Display all rows' option is selected.
        </option>
        <option name="Pie column: ">
            The values of this column are represent as colored section in the
            pie chart.
        </option>
        <option name="Aggregation method: ">
            The initial aggregation method to use. Can be changed in
            the view later on.
        </option>
        <option name="Aggregation column">
            The column to calculate the aggregation values from.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Data in port">
            The data table to be displayed.
        </inPort>
    </ports>    
    <views>
        <view index="0" name="Pie Chart">
            Displays the data in an pie chart.
        </view>
    </views>
</knimeNode>