<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../switches_case.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>CASE Switch Model (Start)</name>
    <shortDescription> Model (or generic port) CASE Switch to alter active branch for arbitrary port types.. 
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>This nodes takes a generic port object from the input port and passes it to exactly one active output port.
            </p>
            <p>
                NOTE - Due to the way in which flow variables are handled within KNIME, the flow variable values for any
                existing flow variables beyond the corresponding "end" node will always be those at the top-most port of
                the "end" node. New variables created in any active branch will retain their correct values. If you need
                to change the value of existing variables, please  use a new flow variable defined within the case and
                overwrite the value of original variable downstream of the switch.
            </p>
        </intro>
        <option name="Select active port">Select the active output port</option>
        <option name="Activate all outputs during configuration step">
            When set the node will keep all outputs active during workflow configuration (that is, while
            the traffic light of the node is 'yellow'). This allows the configuration of connected downstream nodes and
            simplifies the workflow design at the expense of additional configuration calls of nodes that are later on
            inactive. It's recommended to switch this flag off for production workflows as this avoids unnecessary
            configuration calls of the inactive branches.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Model input port">Generic port input</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="First output port">First output port</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Second output port">Second output port</outPort>
        <outPort index="2" name="Third output port">Third output port</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>