<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./append.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Concatenate</name>
    <shortDescription>Concatenates two tables row-wise.</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This node concatenates two tables. The table at inport 0 is given as the first
            input table (top input port), the table at inport 1 is the second table, resp. 
			Columns with equal names are concatenated (if the column types differ 
			the column type is the common base type of both input column types). 
			If one input table contains column names that the other table does not, the
			columns can either be filled with missing values or
			filtered out, i.e. they will not be in the output table.
			The dialog allows to set the following parameters:
		</intro>
        <option name="Skip rows"> Duplicate row identifiers (RowID) occuring in the 
	        second table are not appended to the output table. </option>
        <option name="Append suffix"> The output table will contain all rows, but
            duplicate row identifiers are labeled with a suffix. </option>
        <option name="Use intersection of columns">
        	Use ony the columns that appear in both input tables. Any other
        	column is ignored and won't appear in the output table.
        </option>
        <option name="Use union of columns">
        	Use all columns available in the input tables. Fill rows with 
        	missing values if they miss cells for some columns.
        </option>
        <option name="Enable hiliting">
            Enables hilting between both inputs and the concatenated output
            table.
        </option>
		</fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="First table to concatenate">Table contributing the rows of the first part of the output table.</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Second table to concatenate">Table contributing the rows of the second part of the output table.</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Concatenated table">Table with rows from both tables.</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>