<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="mailsend.png" type="Other">
	<name>Send Email</name>

    <shortDescription>
      Send an email using an external SMTP server.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
      <intro>
        <p>
			Use to send HTML or plaintext emails from an external SMTP server. Attachments from the filesystem may 
			also be included. Authentication is supported via workflow or node level credentials and connection 
			security via STARTTLS and SSL are both supported. 
        </p>
      </intro>
      <tab name="Mail">
        <option name="TO">
          Email address of the intended recipient
        </option>
        <option name="CC">
          <p>Carbon Copy: Additional recipients who may also be interested in the message.</p>
        </option>
        <option name="BCC">
          Blind Carbon Copy: Additional recipients to receive discrete copies of the message (TO and CC recipients will not see who is BCC'd).
        </option>
        <option name="Subject">
         The Subject of your message.
        </option>
        <option name="Body">
         The body of your message. Note that the list to the left of the text box allows you to reference flow variables in your message. 
        </option>
        <option name="Priority">
			The X-Priority flag in the mail header. Standard email clients display the email in different styles depending on the flag.
		</option>
        <option name="Text/HTML">
         Choose whether your message should be interpreted as plain text or HTML. Note, if HTML is chosen you will have to enter HTML tags manually. 
         This option is mostly useful when used in conjunction with flow variables, whereby a flow variable contributes the email text.  
        </option>
      </tab>
      <tab name="Attachments">
        <option name="File Chooser">
			Choose a file (or more than one) to attach to your email.  To include temporary data from your KNIME workflow, 
			consider using a Create Temp. Dir. node along with the relevant file writers to create your attachments. The trash icon will remove 
			the selected file, and the up/down arrows will reorder the attachments in the final email. 
        </option>
      </tab>
      <tab name="Mail Host (SMTP)">
        <option name="SMTP Host">
			The domain name of your SMTP server.
        </option>
        <option name="SMTP Port">
			The port on which to connect to your SMTP server (25, 465, 587 are popular choices, but check with you mail provider).
        </option>
        <option name="FROM">
			An alternate return address for this message (Only if supported by your SMTP host).   
        </option>
        <option name="SMTP Host Authentication">
			Check this box if your SMTP host requires authentication.
        </option>
        <option name="Workflow Credentials">
			Enable workflow level credentials. These must be defined for the workflow in the KNIME Explorer by selecting "Workflow Credentials" 
			from the context menu for an open workflow.
        </option>
        <option name="User Name / Password">
			Enter your user name and password if using simple authentication (as opposed to the Workflow Credentials described above).
        </option>        
		<option name="Connection Security">
			Choose a method for secure communication with your SMTP Host.  SSL or STARTTLS will use these methods respectively, while None 
			will send your data unencrypted over the network.  
        </option>
      </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
      <inPort index="0" name="Input Variables">
		  An an optional flow variable port which may be used to control the message content and node settings.
      </inPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
