<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Other" icon="correlation.png">
	<name>Linear Correlation</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Computes correlation coefficients for pairs of numeric or
		nominal columns.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>
				Calculates for each pair of selected columns a correlation
				coefficient, i.e. a measure of the correlation of the two variables.
	    </p>
			<p>
				Which correlation measure is applied depends on the types of the
				underlying variables:
				<br />
				<tt>numeric &lt;-&gt; numeric</tt>:
				<a
					href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pearson_product-moment_correlation_coefficient">
					Pearson's product-moment coefficient</a>.
				Missing values in a column are ignored in such a way that for the
				computation of the correlation between two columns only complete
				records are taken into account. For instance, if there are three
				columns A, B and C and a row contains a missing value in column A
				but not in B and C, then the row will be ignored for computing the
				correlation between (A, B) and (A, C). It will not be ignored for
				the correlation between (B, C). This corresponds to the function
				<i>cor(&lt;data.frame&gt;, use="pairwise.complete.obs")</i>
				in the R statistics package.
				<br />
				The value of this measure ranges from -1 (strong negative 
				correlation) to 1 (strong positive correlation). A value of 0
				represents no linear correlation (the columns might still be
				highly dependent on each other, though).
				<br />
				<tt>nominal &lt;-&gt; nominal</tt>:
				<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pearson%27s_chi-square_test">
					Pearson's chi square test on the contingency table</a>. 
			    This value is then normalized to a range [0,1] using
				<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cram%C3%A9r%27s_V">
					Cramer's V</a>, whereby 0 represents no correlation and 1 
			    a strong correlation. Missing values in nominal columns are
			    treated such as they were a self-contained possible value. 
			    If one of the two columns contains more possible values than
			    specified in the dialog (default 50), the correlation will not
			    be computed.
                <br />
				Correlation measures for other pairs of columns are not
				available, they are represented by missing values in the output
				table and crosses in the accompanying view.
			</p>
		</intro>

		<option name="Column Filter">
			Select columns for which correlation values shall
			be computed.
		</option>
		<option name="Possible Values Count">
			Select an upper bound for the number of possible
			values for each
			of the nominal columns. If more values are encountered in a nominal
			column, the column will be ignored (no correlation values will
			be
			computed).
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Numeric input data">Numeric input data to evaluate</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Correlation measure">Correlation variables in a square
			matrix</outPort>
		<outPort name="Correlation Model" index="1">
			A model containing the
			correlation measures. This model is appropriate
			to be read by the Correlation Filter node.</outPort>
	</ports>
	<views>
		<view name="Correlation Matrix" index="0">Squared table view showing
			the
			pair-wise correlation values of all columns. The color range varies from
			dark red (strong negative correlation), over white (no correlation) to
			dark blue (strong positive correlation). If a correlation value for a
			pair
			of column is not available, the corresponding cell contains a missing
			value
			(shown as cross in the color view).</view>
	</views>

</knimeNode>