<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="equalsizesampling.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Equal Size Sampling</name>

    <shortDescription>Removes rows from the input data set such that the values
        in a categorical column are equally distributed.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>
	           Removes rows from the input data set such that the values in a
	           categorical column are equally distributed. This can be useful, for instance
	           if a learning algorithm is prone to unequal class distributions and you
	           want to downsize the data set so that the class attributes occur equally
	           often in the data set. 
	        </p>
	        <p>
	           The node will remove random rows belonging to the majority classes. The
	           rows returned by this node will contain all records from the minority
	           class(es) and a random sample from each of the majority classes, 
	           whereby each sample contains as many objects as the minority class
	           contains.
	        </p>
        </intro>
        <option name="Nominal Column">
            Select the class column here. The node will run over the data set once
            to count the occurrences in this selected column and then do the filtering
            in a second pass. Note that missing values in this column are treated as
            a separate category (can also build the minority class).
        </option>
        <option name="Use exact sampling">
            If selected, the final output will be determined up-front. Each class will have
            the same number of instances in the output table. This sampling is 
            slightly more memory expensive as each class will need to be represented
            by a bit set containing instances of the corresponding rows. In most cases 
            it is save to select this option unless you have very large data with many
            different class labels.
        </option>
        <option name="Use approximate sampling">
            If selected, the final output will be determined on the fly. The number 
            of occurrences of each class may slightly differ as the final number can't
            be determined beforehand.            
        </option>
        <option name="Enable static seed">
            If selected, the removal of rows is driven by a static seed 
            (result is reproducable). 
        </option>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input">Arbitrary input data.</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Downsampled input">
            The input data with fewer rows.
        </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
