<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./db_query.png" type="Source" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    <name>Parameterized Database Query</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        This node runs SQL queries in the connected database restricted by the 
	    possible values given by the input table.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
		<intro>
		This node runs SQL queries in the connected database restricted by the 
		possible values given by the input table. It establishes and opens a 
		database access connection from which to read data and restricts 
		each SQL query so that only rows that match the possible values from
		the input table are retrieved.
		</intro>
        
        <option name="Database Column List">
        The list contains the columns that are available in the connected database 
        table. Double clicking any of the entries will insert the respective 
        identifier at the current cursor position (replacing the selection, if any).
        </option>

		<option name="Column List">
		The list contains the columns that are available in the input table. 
		Double clicking any of the entries will insert the respective 
        identifier at the current cursor position (replacing the selection, if any).
		</option>
        
        <option name="Flow Variable List">
        The list contains the flow variables that are currently available at the 
        node input. Double clicking any of the entries will insert the respective 
        identifier at the current cursor position (replacing the selection, if any).
        </option>
        
        <option name="SQL Statement">
        Enter the SQL-like query here, for example SELECT * FROM table. If the table
        place holder isn't changed, then it will be replaced with the query from the
        database connection. Constant values and any identifier from the 
        database column list, column list, flow variable list can be used in
        WHERE statement.
        </option>
        
        <option name="Fail on error">
        If checked, then the node will fail if there is any error. Otherwise, the
        node will continue executing and all errors will be collected in the second
        output table.
        </option>
        
        <option name="Append input columns">
       	If checked, then the columns from the input table will be appended to the 
       	output table. Only columns that are used in the looping SQL statement will
       	be appended.
        </option>
        
        <option name="Retain all columns">
        If checked, then all columns including columns that are not used in the 
        looping SQL statement will be appended to the output table.
        </option>
        
        <option name="Include empty results">
        If checked, then all empty results will be appended to the output table
        and represented as Missing Cell. All input rows will be retained.
        </option>
              
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Data with possible values">
        Data column with possible values used to constrain the database SQL query
		</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Database query connection">
         A database query connection that will be used to connect to the database
        </inPort>
        <!-- possibly more input ports here-->
        <outPort index="0" name="Result Table">
        Table with data read from the database and optionally the data from the input table
        </outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Error Table">
        Table with error message if any, otherwise empty table
        </outPort>        
    </ports>        
</knimeNode>
