<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 1.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd" >
<knimeNode icon="./colappender.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Column Appender</name>
    <shortDescription>Appends column from one table to another based on a common key</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This node adds the columns from the second table to the first table. The rows are mapped bases on the values
            of cells in two columns that the user can choose. The first table may contain the same value in several rows
            of the join column, whereas the second table must not. As a side effect the output table is sorted on the
            join column.
        </intro>
        <option name="Column from left table">
            The column from the left table which should be used for joining rows
        </option>
        <option name="Column from right table">
            The column from the right table which should be used for joining rows
        </option>
        <option name="Duplicate handling">
            Determines the handling of column with the same name (except the join column) in both columns
            <br />
            <ul>
                <li>Don't execute: If both tables contain columns with the same name the node is not executed</li>
                <li>Filter columns: The columns with duplicate names from the right (second) table are filtered out</li>
                <li>Append suffix: Append a suffix to the duplicate columns of the right table</li>
            </ul>
        </option>
        <option name="Row name suffix">The suffix appended to duplicate columns from the right table</option>
        <option name="Sort tables in memory">
            If activated, the two tables are sorted completely in memory. This is faster but may need too much memory.
            Use with caution!
        </option>
        <option name="Remove rows with missing values">
            If no matching row is found in the right table then the row is removed from the output. The default is to
            fill the columns from the right table with missing values.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <dataIn index="0" name="Base table">Base table</dataIn>
        <dataIn index="1" name="Additional table">Table with additional columns</dataIn>
        <dataOut index="0" name="Appended table">Base table with appended columns</dataOut>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
