<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.10" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10" type="Source">
    <name>Database Table Selector</name>
    <shortDescription>Selects a table from a database using the input database JDBC connection.</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This node takes a database connection as input and allows selecting a table based on the incoming database 
            JDBC connection. The node outputs the incoming connection together with the query which can later on be used
            in subsequent database manipulation nodes.
        </intro>
        
        <option name="SQL Statement">
            Enter SQL statement being executed here, for example SELECT * FROM mytable.
            <br/>
            Additional SQL commands (create, drop, set parameter, etc.) can be added before the actual SELECT statement 
            and are executed together line-by-line during configure and execute. Note, those additional SQL commands 
            need to be separated by semicolon.
        </option>
        <option name="Database Browser">
            Click <i>Fetch Metadata</i> to connect to the database using the entered settings and to fetch all tables 
            and display them grouped by type in the Database Browser.
            <br/>
            Click on any table to retrieve all contained columns. Double-click on a table or column to insert its name 
            into the SQL query at the current cursor position.
        </option>
        <option name="Flow Variable List">
            The list contains the flow variables that are currently available at the node input. Double clicking any of 
            the entries will insert the respective identifier at the current cursor position (replacing the
            selection, if any).
        </option>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Database JDBC Connection">A database connection to select a table from</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Database Connection">A database connection with an initial table</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
