<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./xjoiner.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Cross Joiner</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Performs a cross join of two tables.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        	<p>
        		Performs a cross join of two tables. Each row of the top table is joined with
		        each row of the bottom table. Note, this is an extremely expensive operation as the number of rows in the
        		output is the product of both input table row counts, by increasing the chunk size there will be a speed up.
        	</p>
        	<p>
        		<i>Note:</i> If executed in streaming mode only the top input will be processed in a streamable fashion.
	        </p>
        </intro>
        <option name="Bottom table's column suffix">
        The suffix attached to a column's name if the bottom table contains a column with the same name.
        The column names of the first inport are always retained. If there are duplicates found in the second table
        the suffix is added once or multiple times to ensure uniqueness.
        </option>
        <option name="Separator for new RowIds"> This string will separate the rowids in the new data table. E.g. RowID1 + sep + RowID2</option>
        <option name="Chunk size: ">Number of rows read at once, increasing this
              value yields faster execution time but also increases memory consumption.</option>
        <option name="Append top data tables RowIds"> If selected a new column will be attached to the output, containing the rowids of the top data table. </option>
        <option name="Column name(top): ">The name of the newly generated rowkey column.</option>
        <option name="Append bottom data tables RowIds ">If selected a new column will be attached to the output, containing the rowids of the bottom data table.</option>
        <option name="Column name(bottom): ">The name of the newly generated rowkey column.</option>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Top Table">The top table to be joined (streamable)</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Bottom Table">The bottom table to be joined (non-streamable)</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Joined Table">Cross join</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>