<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./scattermatrix.png" type="Visualizer">
	<name>Scatter Matrix</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
	    Plots a scatter matrix where each column is compared to all others.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>		
			<p>
				In a scatter matrix each matrix element Eij is a scatterplot of the columns
				i and j, where the values of the i-th column are displayed at the x axis 
				and the values of the j-th column at the y axis while the coordinates
				are displayed alternating on all sides of the plot.
			</p>
		
            <p><b>Only columns with a valid domain are available in this view.
            Make sure that the predecessor node is executed or set the domain 
            with the DomainCalculator node!</b></p> 		
		
			<h3>HiLiting:</h3>
			<p> 
				The data points may be selected by either dragging
				a rectangle with the mouse over the points or clicking directly on them.
				Hold control pressed for multiple selections. 
				The selected datapoints may be 
				hilited by either right-click to get the context menu or via the hilite
				menu in the menu bar.
				The data points are displayed as selected or hilited in all matrix elements.
			</p>
		
			<h3>Tooltip</h3>
			<p>
				Move the mouse over the data points to get information about the 
				row ID and the value.
			</p>
		
			<h3>Properties: </h3>
			<p>
				Default Settings:
				<ul>
					<li>
						Mouse Mode: choose "Selection" to select the datapoints or
						"Zooming" to zoom in. If you have zoomed in you may choose "Moving" 
						to navigate in the zoomed display. If you want to rearrange the order of the columns
						choose "Transformation". The matrix columns can then be selected and dragged
						to another position.
					</li>
					<li>
						"Fit to screen" fits the display again to the available space.
					</li>
					<li>
						"Background color" lets you choose the background color of the display. 
					</li>
					<li>"Anti-aliasing": Check if the view should enable anti-aliasing
                    (make a smoother drawing). This will slow down performance as well.</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
			<p>
				Column Selection:
				Choose the columns you want to have displayed in the scatter matrix.
				Initially only the first three are selected.
			</p>
			<p>
				Appearance:
				<ul>
					<li>
						"Dot Size" lets you define the size of the dots.
					</li>
					<li>
						"Jitter": if a nominal column is selected, you may adjust how much
						the values are jittered (scattered around there origin).
					</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
		
		</intro>
		<option name="Nr. of rows to display">Enter the maximum number of rows
		the plotter should display. Setting a higher value than the default value 
		might dramatically decrease performance.</option>
		<option name="Ignore columns with more nominal values than:">
            Enter the maximum number of distinct nominal values that the
            view should consider. Columns with more values than the
            specified number will be ignored and can't be selected in
            the view. Please also note that nominal values must be
            present in the table specification of the input table (check
            it by inspecting the table spec tab of the predecessor's
            outport view). If no nominal values are present in the
            table, execute the predecessor or consider to use the 
            "Domain Calculator" node and to enforce the determination of 
            the nominal values.
        </option>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Display data">Data to display</inPort>
	</ports>	
	<views>
		<view index="0" name="Scatter Matrix">
			A scatter matrix displays scatter plots for each combination of columns.
		</view>
	</views>
</knimeNode>