<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="treeensemble_predictor.png" type="Predictor">
    <name>Random Forest Predictor</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Predicts patterns according to an aggregation of the predictions of the individual trees in a random forest model.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            Predicts patterns according to an aggregation of the predictions of the individual trees in a random forest model.
        </intro>
        <option name="Change prediction column name">
           Select if you want to change the name of the column containing the prediction.
        </option>
        <option name="Prediction column name">The name of the column that will contain the prediction of the tree ensemble model</option>
        <option name="Append overall prediction confidence">
           The confidence of the predicted class. It is the maximum of all confidence values 
           (which can be appended separately).
        </option>
        <option name="Append individual class probabilities">
           For each class the prediction confidence. It's the number of trees predicting to
           the current class (as per column name) divided by the total number of trees.
        </option>
        <option name="Suffix for probability columns">Here a suffix for the names of the class probability columns can be entered.</option>
        <option name="Use soft voting">
        	Per default ("hard voting") the class that receives the most votes is predicted. In case of "soft voting" the class probabilities of all
        	trees are aggregated and the class with the highest aggregated probability is predicted. In order for this to work properly, the random forest model
        	needs to contain the class distributions. This can be specified in the learner node by selecting the option "Save target distribution in tree nodes".
            Setting this option on models that do not have the target distributions saved, will cause a warning message to be issued. 
        </option>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Random Forest Model">The output of the learner.</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Input data">Data to be predicted.</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Prediction output">Input data along with prediction columns.</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
