<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="db_pivot-icon.png" type="Manipulator">
	<name>Database Pivot</name>
	<shortDescription>
		The Database Pivot node allows to pivot and group the input table by the 
		selected columns for pivoting and grouping; enhanced by column aggregations.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
    	<intro>
    	   <p>
        	This node creates a SQL statement for pivoting to be executed on the
			input database using a selected number of 
			columns for grouping and pivoting. The group columns will result
        	into unique rows, whereby the pivot values turned into 
        	columns for each set of column combinations together with each 
        	aggregation method.
           </p>
           <p>
            To change the aggregation method of more than one column select all
            columns to change, open the context menu with a right mouse click
            and select the aggregation method to use.
           </p>
           <p>
            A detailed description of the available aggregation methods can be
            found on the 'Description' tab in the node dialog.
   		   </p>
    	</intro>
    	<tab name="Group settings">
          <option name="Group columns">
            Select one or more columns according to which the group rows 
            are created.
          </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Pivot settings">
          <option name="Pivot columns">
            Select one or more columns according to which the pivot columns 
            are created.
          </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Manual Aggregation">
          <option name="Aggregation methods">
            Select one or more columns for aggregation from the available 
            columns list. Change the aggregation method in the Aggregation 
            column of the table. You can add the same column multiple
            times. In order to change the aggregation method of more than one 
            column select all columns to change, open the context menu with a 
            right mouse click and select the aggregation method to use.
            The parameter column shows an "Edit" button for all 
            aggregation operators that require additional information. 
            Clicking on the "Edit" button opens the parameter dialog 
            which allows changing the operator specific settings.
          </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Advanced settings">
          <option name="Column naming">
            The name of the resulting aggregation column(s) depends on the 
            selected naming schema.
            <ul>
                <li>Keep original name(s):
                Keeps the original column names.
                Note that you can use all aggregation columns only once with 
                this column naming option to prevent duplicate column names.
                </li>
                <li>Aggregation method (column name): 
                Uses the aggregation method first and appends the column name
                in brackets
                </li>
                <li>Column name (aggregation method):
                Uses the column name first and appends the aggregation method
                in brackets
                </li>
            </ul>
          </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Database Connection">
			Table in database to apply pivoting
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Database Connection">
			Table in the database with pivoted rows
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>