<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./mds.png" type="Learner">
	<name>MDS Projection</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
		Multi dimensional scaling node, mapping data of a high dimensional 
		space onto a lower dimensional space by applying a modified Sammons 
		mapping with respect to a given set of fixed points.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
	<intro>
	   This node maps data of a high dimensional space onto a lower (usually
	   2 or 3) dimensional space with respect to a set of fixed data points.
	   Therefore modified Sammons mapping is applied, which iteratively 
	   decreases the difference of the distances of high and low dimensional 
	   data. When adjusting the position a low dimensional data point by default 
	   not its neighbors (or all other data points) are taken into account but a 
	   specified set of fixed data points which are not modified. Additionally 
	   the data points (and not only the fixed points) can be taken into account 
	   when adjusting its positions, therefore the setting "Project only"
	   has to be unchecked. If the setting is checked the data points will be
	   mapped only with respect to the fixed data, which we call a projection. 
	   The algorithm converges like a common mds algorithm due to a 
	   decreasing learning rate.
	</intro>
	
	<option name="Number of rows to use">
	   Specifies the number of rows to apply the MDS on.
	</option>
    <option name="Output dimension">
        Specifies the dimension of the mapped output data.
    </option>	
    <option name="Epochs">
        Specifies the number of epochs to train.
    </option>
    <option name="Learn rate">	   
        Specifies the learning rate to use. The learning rate
        is decreased automatically over the trained epochs.
	</option>
	<option name="Random seed">
	   Specifies the random seed to use, which allows to reproduce a mapping 
	   even if the initialization is done randomly.
	</option>
	<option name="Distance metric">
		The distance metric to use Euclidean or Manhattan. 
		The Euclidean distance metric is used by default.
	</option>
    <option name="Project only">
        If checked the input data is mapped only with respect to the specified 
        fixed data points (see tab 'Fixed data'). If unchecked, the other
        (not fixed) data points are taken into account too, when adjusting
        the position of each single data point.
    </option>	
	
	<option name="Input data">
	   Specifies the columns to use by the mapping.
	</option>
    <option name="Fixed data">
       Specifies the columns to use as fixed data. Be aware that the chosen
       columns represent the lower dimensional data which is used to project
       the input data at.
       The number of columns to choose has to be equal to the value set for
       output dimension. 
    </option>	
	</fullDescription>
		
	<ports>
		<inPort name="Any input table" index="0">
			Data table containing the fixed data points.
		</inPort>
        <inPort name="Any input table" index="1">
            Data table containing the data to map.
        </inPort>		
		<outPort name="The input data and the mapped data" index="0">
			The input data and the mapped data.
		</outPort>
	</ports>	
</knimeNode>

