<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE properties SYSTEM "http://java.sun.com/dtd/properties.dtd">
<properties>
	<entry key="shortdescription">
		Allows filtering of datarows by certain criteria, like row ID, 
		attribute value, and row number range.  
    </entry>
    <entry key="fulldescription">
 		The node allows for row filtering with certain criterias. It can include
 		or exclude certain ranges (by row number), include or exclude rows with
 		a certain row ID, and in- or exclude rows with a certain value in a
 		selectable column (attribute). Below are the steps to configure the node
 		in its configuration dialog:
 	</entry>
 	<entry key="1. The 'criteria' tab:">
		From the three selection boxes, choose which criteria should be used to 
		filter rows.
		The default setting is to include all rows from the table. After a list
		is set to include or exclude rows the corresponding tab will allow for 
		adjustments of this criteria.
     </entry>
 	<entry key="2. The 'by row number' tab:">
 		If, in the 'criteria' tab, row range filtering is enabled, specify here
 		the first and last row number to in- or exclude (or set a checkmark to
 		extend the range all the way to the end of the data table).
 	</entry>
 	<entry key="3. The 'by row ID' tab:">
 		If, in the 'criteria' tab, row ID matching is enabled, enter here a
 		regular expression all included or excluded rows must match. You can also
 		specify if the match should be case sensitive and if the id must fully
 		match or just start with the specified pattern. 
     </entry>
     <entry key="4. The 'column value' tab:">
 		If, in the 'criteria' tab, filtering by value in a column is enabled,
 		select the column here and specify the criteria how to match the value
 		in that column. The options are: matching the string representation
 		against a regular expression, or checking the value of the attribute
 		to be in a certain number range.  If the range checking is disabled,
 		you either selected a non-numerical column, or there is no information
 		available about the incoming data (then, execute the predecessor node
 		to make it available). 
     </entry>
</properties>
