<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 1.0//EN" "http://www.inf.uni-konstanz.de/bioml/research/knime/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./rowfilter.gif">
	<name>Row Filter</name>
	<type>Transformer</type>
	<shortDescription>
		Allows filtering of datarows by certain criteria, like row ID, 
		attribute value, and row number range.  
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>The node allows for row filtering with certain criterias. 
		It can include
 		or exclude certain ranges (by row number), include or exclude rows with
 		a certain row ID, and in- or exclude rows with a certain value in a
 		selectable column (attribute). Below are the steps to configure the node
 		in its configuration dialog.
		</intro>

		<option name="In- or exclude rows by criteria">First, on the left hand
			side, select which criteria should be used for filtering. Also choose
			whether to include or exclude rows by the selected criteria. 
			Depending on the choice the filter parameters in the panel on the 
			right hand side need to be adjusted
		</option>
		<option name="Column value matching">If filter by attribute value is 
			selected, select the column's name whose value should be matched. Then,
			either enter a regular expression for string matching, or a value range,
			for range filtering. When using a regular expression, a check mark can
			be set, if a case sensitive match is desired. If a range is specified,
			it is possible to specify only one boundary, the other is then set to
			(plus or minus) infinity.
		</option>
	    <option name="Row number range">If filter by range is selected, specify
		    the first row number to in/exclude. The end of the range can either 
		    be specified by row number, or set to the end of the table, causing 
		    all remaining rows to be in/excluded then.
		</option>
	    <option name="Row ID pattern">If filter by row key is selected, specify
	    	a regular expression, which is matched against the row ID of each row.
	    	A check mark can be set, if a case sensitive match should be performed
	    	and if the row ID must start with the specified pattern.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<dataIn index="0" name="To be filtered">Datatable to filter rows from.</dataIn>
		<dataOut index="0" name="Filtered">Datatable with rows meeting the specified criteria</dataOut>
	</ports>	
</knimeNode>