<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./line.png" type="Visualizer">
	<name>Line Plot</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
	    Plots the numeric columns as lines.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>		
	    <p>Plots the numeric columns of the input table as lines. All values are
	    mapped to a single y coordinate. This may distort the visualization if the
	    difference of the values in the columns is large.  
		</p>
		
		<h3>HiLiting:</h3>
		<p> The data points may be selected by either dragging
		a rectangle with the mouse over the points or 
		by clicking on points 
		(if the dots are not displayed you won't see the selection or hilite since
		only data points can be selected or hilited). 
		Hold control pressed for multiple selections. 
		The selected datapoints may be 
		hilited by either right-click to get the context menu or via the hilite
		menu in the menu bar.</p>
		
		<h3>Tooltip</h3>
		<p>
		Move the mouse over the data points to get detailed information about 
		the data point (Row ID, the x and y values).
		</p>
		
		<h3>Properties: </h3>
		<p>Default Settings:
			<ul>
			<li>Mouse Mode: choose "Selection" to select the datapoints or
			"Zooming" to zoom in. If you have zoomed in you may choose "Moving" 
			to navigate in the zoomed display.</li>
			<li>"Fit to screen" fits the display again to the available space.</li>
			<li>"Background color lets you choose the background color of the display. </li>
			<li>"Anti-aliasing": Check if the view should enable anti-aliasing
            (make a smoother drawing). This will slow down performance as well.</li>
			</ul>
		</p>
		<p>Column Selection:
		Choose the columns you want to have displayed as lines. 
		If the visualization is distorted due to great differences between the 
		columns the most distorting columns can be removed to scale the y axis correctly.
		</p>
		<p>Legend: 
		Since the colors of the lines do not depend on the colors of the rows
		(since not the rows, but the columns are displayed as lines) the colors are created
		automatically. Click "Change..." in the legend to change the color of the referring line.
		</p>
		<p>Missing Values:
			Per default missing values will interrupt the line. Check "Interpolate" to 
			linearly interpolate the missing values. Missing values at the beginning
			and at the end will not be interpolated.
		</p>
		<p>Appearance:
			<ul>
			<li>"Show/Hide dots": Check if the points should
			be displayed explicitely as dots, uncheck if you want to hide the dots.</li>
			<li>"Thickness" lets you define the thickness of the lines.</li>
			<li>"Dot Size" lets you define the size of the dots.</li>
			</ul>
		</p>

		</intro>
		<option name="Nr. of rows to display">Enter the maximum number of rows
		the plotter should display. Setting a higher value than the default value 
		might dramatically decrease performance.</option>
		      <option name="Ignore columns with more nominal values than:">
            Enter the maximum number of distinct nominal values that the
            view should consider. Columns with more values than the
            specified number will be ignored and can't be selected in
            the view. Please also note that nominal values must be
            present in the table specification of the input table (check
            it by inspecting the table spec tab of the predecessor's
            outport view). If no nominal values are present in the
            table, execute the predecessor or consider to use the 
            "Domain Calculator" node and to enforce the determination of 
            the nominal values.
        </option>		
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<dataIn index="0" name="Display data">Data to display</dataIn>
	</ports>	
	<views>
		<view index="0" name="Line Plot">
			The line plot displaying the data.
		</view>
	</views>
</knimeNode>