<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./splitter.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Splitter</name>
    <shortDescription>Splits the columns of the input table into two output tables.</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
			This node splits the columns of the input table into two output tables. Specify in the
		    dialog which columns should occur in the top table (left list), 
		    and the bottom table (right list). Use the buttons to move columns 
		    from one list to the other.
		</intro>
		
		      <tab name="Column Filter">      
		
		<option name="Top">
            A list of column names that make up the first output table (top 
            output port).
        </option>
        
        <option name="Enforce Exclusion (Top)">
            Select this option to enforce the current top list to stay
            the same even if the input table specification changes. If some
            of the included columns are not available anymore, a warning
            is displayed. (New columns will automatically be added to the
            bottom list.)
        </option>
        
        <option name="Select">
            Use these buttons to move columns between the Top and Bottom 
            list.
        </option>
        
        <option name="Search">
            Use one of these fields to search either within the Top
            or Bottom list for certain column names or name substrings.
            Repeated clicking of the search button marks the next column that 
            matches the search text. The check box 'Mark all search hits' causes
            all matching columns to be selected making them movable between
            the two lists.
        </option>
        
        <option name="Bottom">
            A list of column names that make up the second output table (bottom 
            output port).
        </option>

        <option name="Enforce Inclusion (Bottom)">
            Select this option to enforce the current exclusion list to stay
            the same even if the input table specification changes. If some
            of the bottom columns are not available anymore, a warning
            is displayed. (New columns will automatically be added to the
            Top list.)
        </option>
        </tab>
		
	</fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Table to split">Table to split.</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Splitted table, Top partition">Input table with the columns as defined in the dialog's left list.</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Splitted table, Bottom partition">Input table with the columns as defined in the dialog's right list.</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>