<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Manipulator" icon="correlation.png">
    <name>Cronbach Alpha</name>
    <shortDescription>
        Computes the Cronbach Alpha for all numerical columns based on their variance.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        Computes the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cronbach%27s_alpha">Cronbach Alpha</a> for all numerical columns based on their variance. Cronbach's Alpha compares the variance of the individual columns with the variance of the sum of all columns. It typically serves as an estimate of the reliability of a psychometric test. Cronbach Alpha is known as an internal consistency estimate of reliability of test scores since it will generally increase as the intercorrelations among test items increase. The theoretical value of alpha varies from zero to 1. However, depending on the estimation procedure used, estimates of alpha can take on any value less than or equal to 1. 
        If Missing Values are encountered the node will fail.
        </intro>
    <tab name="Column Filter">
    
        <option name="Include">
            This list contains the column names to be included in the Cronbach Value.
        </option>
        
        <option name="Enforce Inclusion">
            Select this option to enforce the current inclusion list to stay
            the same even if the input table specification changes. 
            New columns will automatically be added to the exclusion list.
        </option>
      
        <option name="Select">
            Use these buttons to move columns between the Include and Exclude 
            list.
        </option>
        
        <option name="Search">
            Use one of these fields to search either within the Include
            or Exclude list for certain column names or name substrings.
            Repeated clicking of the search button marks the next column that 
            matches the search text. The check box 'Mark all search hits' causes
            all matching columns to be selected making them movable between
            the two lists.
        </option>
        
        <option name="Exclude">
            This list contains the column names of the input table that are 
            left out of the calculation.
        </option>
        
        <option name="Enforce Exclusion">
            Select this option to enforce the current exclusion list to stay
            the same even if the input table specification changes. 
            New columns will automatically be added to the inclusion list.
        </option>
        
      </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Numeric input data">Numeric input data to evaluate</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Cronbach alpha">The Cronbach Alpha in a data table with one row/column</outPort>
    </ports>

</knimeNode>