<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 1.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Learner" icon="./rbf_small.ico">
	<name>PNN Learner</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
	    Trains a Probabilistic Neural Network (PNN) on labeled data.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>		
		 		Generates a Probabilistic Neural Network (PNN) on labeled data using
			<a href="http://www.inf.uni-konstanz.de/bioml2/publications/Papers1998/BeDi98_dda_neurocomp.pdf">
			Constructive Training of Probabilistic Neural Networks</a> as underlying
			algorithm.<br />
			All numeric columns are used as input columns for training. One 
		   	additional column is used as a classification target.
		   	The input port contains the training data, the data output port contains 
		   	the center vectors of the PNN rules.
		   	The algorithm uses high-dimensional Gaussian functions to cover 
		   	instances that are adjusted by two thresholds, theta minus and plus, 
		   	during the learning process. New prototypes are commited until all
		   	examples have been correctly covered.
		</intro>
		
		<option name="Target Column">
			Select column to be used as classification attribute.
		</option>
		<option name="Missing Values">
		    Select method to handle missing values.
		</option>
		<option name="Properties">
		    Check, if a shrink should be performed immediately after a new rule
		    has been introduced. Shrink means the new rule is reduced so that a
		    conflict with all other rules is avoided.
		</option>
		<option name="Theta Minus">
		    Default theta minus value is 0.2. This is the upper bound of
			activation for conflicting rules.
		</option>
		<option name="Theta Plus">
		    Default theta plus value is 0.4. This is the lower bound of
			activation for non-conflicting rules.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<ports>
		<dataIn index="0" name="Training Data">Data used for training. Should contain numeric data, 
		as well as one target attribute for classification.</dataIn>
		<dataOut index="0" name="PNN Rule Table">Table with generated center vectors and a classification attribute.</dataOut>
		<modelOut index="0" name="PNN Rule Model" type="PNNModel">Generated PNN model can be used for prediction.</modelOut>
	</ports>
	
	<views>
		<view index="0" name="PNN Rule Model View">
			Shows a summary of the generated PNN rule model.
		</view>
	</views>
	
</knimeNode>

