<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Learner" icon="./rbf_small.ico">
	<name>PNN Learner (DDA)</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
	    Trains a Probabilistic Neural Network (PNN) on labeled data.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>		
	 		Trains a Probabilistic Neural Network (PNN) based on the DDA 
	 		(Dynamic Decay Adjustment) method on labeled data using
			<a href="http://www.inf.uni-konstanz.de/bioml2/publications/Papers1998/BeDi98_dda_neurocomp.pdf">
			Constructive Training of Probabilistic Neural Networks</a> as the
			underlying algorithm.<br />
			This algorithm generates rules based on numeric data. Each rule is
			defined as high-dimensional Gaussian function that is adjusted by
		   	two thresholds, theta minus and theta plus, to avoid conflicts with
		   	rules of different classes. Each Gaussian function is defined by
		   	a center vector (from the first covered instance) and a standard
		   	deviation which is adjusted during training to cover only 
		   	non-conflicting instances. The selected numeric columns of the
			input data are used as input data for training and additional 
			columns are used as classification target, either one column holding
			the class information or a number of numeric columns with class 
			degrees between 0 and 1 can	be selected. The data output contains 
			the rules after execution along with a number of of rule 
			measurements. The model output port contains the PNN model, 
			which can be used for prediction in the PNN Predictor node.
		</intro>
	    <option name="Missing Values">
	    Select one method to handle missing values: "Incorp" may generate  
	    rules with missing values, if no replacement value has been 
	    found during the learning process. "Best Guess" computes the optimal
	    replacement value by projecting the rule (with missing value(s))
	    onto the missing dimension(s) of all other rules. "Mean", "Min", and "Max"
	    replaces the missing value with each column's statistical property. 
	    "Zero" and "One" perform a constant replacement by inserting either zero
	    or one.
		</option>
		<option name="Advanced">
	    <b>Shrink after commit</b> If selected, a shrink to reduce conflicting 
	    rules is executed immediately after a new rule is committed, i.e. the 
	    new rule is reduced so that conflicts with all other rules of different
	    classes are avoided.<br />
	    <b>Use class with max coverage</b> If selected, only the class with
	    maximum coverage degree of the target columns is used during training,
	    otherwise all class columns are considered for coverage. 
		</option>
	    <option name="Maximum no. Epochs">
    	If selected, the option defines the maximum number of epochs 
    	the algorithm has to process the entire data set, otherwise it repeats 
    	this process until this rule model is stable, i.e. no new rule has been 
    	committed and/or no shrink is executed.
		</option>
		<option name="Target Columns">
		Select the target(s) to be used for classification. If more
		than one column (only numeric) is selected, the columns must contain 
		class membership values between 0 and 1 for each class given by the 
		column name.
		</option>
		<option name="PNN">
		<b>Theta Minus</b> This defines the upper boundary of activation for 
		conflicting rules: default value is 0.2.<br />
		<b>Theta Plus</b> This defines the lower boundary of activation for 
		non-conflicting rules: default value is 0.4.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
	
    <ports>
		<dataIn index="0" name="Training Data">
			Numeric data as well as class information used for training.
		</dataIn>
		<dataOut index="0" name="PNN Rules">
			Rules as Gaussian functions, classification columns,
			and additional rule measures.
		</dataOut>
		<modelOut index="0" name="PNN Model">
			PNN model can be used for prediction.
		</modelOut>
	</ports>
	
	<views>
		<view index="0" name="Learner Statistics">
			Displays a summary of the learning process.
		</view>
	</views>
	
</knimeNode>

